<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>pydanny</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pydanny.com/feeds/.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pydanny.com/</id><updated>2013-02-27T10:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>Two Scoops Beta Released</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/two-scoops-beta-released.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-27T10:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2013-02-27:two-scoops-beta-released.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://django.2scoops.org/"&gt;&lt;img alt="https://s3.amazonaws.com/twoscoops/img/tsd-cover.png" class="align-center" id="two-scoops-of-django" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/twoscoops/img/tsd-cover.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After thirty three days of hard work, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey Roy&lt;/a&gt; and I are proud to announce that we've released the &lt;strong&gt;beta&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;Two Scoops of Django: Best Practices for Django 1.5&lt;/a&gt;. It's been a monumental effort, a labor of love, and we hope you find our efforts worthy. You can buy it right now in e-book (PDF) form on the website: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;http://django.2scoops.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-is-different-about-the-beta-release"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is different about the beta release?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added 50+ pages of new content while reducing the file size from 5.1 MB to 1.3 MB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added list of tables, list of figures, and index.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dramatically improved the chapters on security, testing, logging, admin, and many more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add so many more code examples we lost count.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaking of code examples, most of the code samples in the book are loaded directly out of fully tested projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incorporated the feedback of dozens of readers. Thank you so much for your contributions!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Addressing the complaint that we don't charge enough, we raised the price by two dollars, from US$12 to US14.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-does-buying-the-beta-get-me"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What does buying the beta get me?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access the PDF version of the book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access to the Kindle and ePub formats when we release the final.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access to final release of the book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="if-i-bought-the-alpha-do-i-have-to-buy-the-beta"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;If I bought the alpha do I have to buy the beta?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, as promised, you get full access the beta. In fact, you should have already received an email with a link to the latest version. If that hasn't arrived, please email us at &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com"&gt;2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="is-this-book-good-for-beginners"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is this book good for beginners?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe so and the response from new Django developers reading it has been unbelievably, overwhelmingly positive. This is the book we wanted to have when we learned Django, and we're honored by the response the book has received.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A small number of more experienced developers have raised concerns that the book isn't for beginners. However, when beginners find sections of the book above their head, they do what everyone does when reading a technical resource, which is skip over that section until they have enough grounding to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any beginners are confused by our explanations, or have difficulties, please email us at &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com"&gt;2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com&lt;/a&gt;. Your issues provide invaluable insight into what we need to improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="is-this-book-good-for-experienced-developers"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is this book good for experienced developers?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've done our best to provide worthwhile material for developers of all levels. In fact, a lot of intermediate to advanced developers have said they've found good things to use in our book, or that by using our book as a manual, it helps them work with their team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="is-this-book-going-to-get-updated"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is this book going to get updated?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the &lt;strong&gt;alpha&lt;/strong&gt; we updated the book multiple times before knuckling down on the &lt;strong&gt;beta&lt;/strong&gt; rewrite. Even after the final version comes out, we'll continue to update the book. One of the advantages of self-published e-books is we have total control of content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="when-can-i-get-a-print-version"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When can I get a print version?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a lot of consideration, we've decided to hold off on the print version of the book until what we call the &lt;strong&gt;final&lt;/strong&gt; edition, which won't be released until after &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/"&gt;PyCon US&lt;/a&gt;. We're very finicky and don't want buyers of the print version to have an unfinished book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, at PyCon, we will be selling a limited set of the printed &lt;strong&gt;beta&lt;/strong&gt;. They'll be sold as first-come, first-serve, and students of our PyCon &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/11/"&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; have first right of sale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="tutorial-pycon-are-you-going"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tutorial? PyCon? Are you going?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes! We're going to be at PyCon next month!  We're giving the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/11/"&gt;Wiring Up Django Packages&lt;/a&gt; tutorial, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://brack3t.com/"&gt;Kenneth Love&lt;/a&gt; (of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gettingstartedwithdjango.com/"&gt;Getting Started with Django&lt;/a&gt; fame) is part of our team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While tickets to PyCon itself are sold out, you can still &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/registration/register/"&gt;register for the tutorials&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="when-are-is-the-book-s-final-release"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When are is the book's final release?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some time after PyCon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="can-i-buy-the-book-via-paypal"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Can I buy the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; via PayPal?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No. I'll answer why in a blog post next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're considering other non-credit card options to handle payment, but chances are they won't be implemented until after PyCon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="where-should-i-send-errata"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where should I send errata?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send errata to &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com"&gt;2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com&lt;/a&gt;. The first person who reports an issue or makes a suggestion that we adopt will receive credit in the book. If not in the changelog, then in the dialogue of the book itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="twoscoops"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="audrey"></category><category term=""></category></entry></feed>