<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>pydanny</title><link href="http://pydanny.github.com" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pydanny.github.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pydanny.github.com</id><updated>2012-02-24T12:45:00Z</updated><entry><title>PyCon Australia 2011 Review</title><link href="http://pydanny.github.com/pycon-australia-2011-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-24T12:45:00Z</updated><author><name>Daniel Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.github.com,2012-02-24:/pycon-australia-2011-review.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In June of 2011 I had the good fortune of having my then girlfriend, Audrey Roy, now fiancee, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.blogspot.com/2011/06/im-going-to-pycon-australia.html"&gt;invited to present a keynote speech at PyCon Australia 2011&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was terribly excited for her to get that invitation, and that excitement was compounded when they allowed me to present on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/pydanny/confessions-of-a-joe-developer`:"&gt;Confessions of Joe Developer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travel is a passion of mine, and it's only been since 2007 that I've gotten a chance to do much seeing of the world. Australia was always this distant goal of mine, but I never thought I would get the chance to go. Fortunately, my assumption was wrong and we landed on August 18th in Sydney, Australia!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audrey &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreyr.posterous.com/thank-you-pycon-au"&gt;wrote her own statement about the event&lt;/a&gt; right after we were done. She's good that way. Okay then, off to my own review. This is belated, but better late then never, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conference-rooms"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conference Rooms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sydney Masonic Center was the venue and it was a really curious building. They built it a while ago, then apparently grafted an office building onto the top of the temple. &lt;strong&gt;You have to see it to believe it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main temple room was room, interesting, and fun. The acoustics, to my limited ear, seemed quite good. The alternative rooms for some of the tracks were small presentation rooms, which did quite nicely except when the organizers chose popular talks for small rooms and things overflowed. Everyone was good natured about that and we all just worked it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result: Great&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="speakers"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Speakers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm partial but I think the opening keynote by Audrey Roy about diversity was wonderful. Mary Gardinar also talk about open source projects trying to change the world that need our support. Raymond Hettiger seriously delivered the goods with another version of his amazing talk about what makes Python great. Whatever you do, go and see it as many times as possible because he changes it each and every time.  Richard Jones' presentation on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny-event-notes.readthedocs.org/en/latest/PyconAU2011/zen_of_python.html"&gt;Zen of Python&lt;/a&gt; was very solid too, and I'll use this as an opportunity to promote my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pypi.python.org/pypi/that"&gt;Anti-Zen of Python&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it came time for me to present on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/pydanny/confessions-of-a-joe-developer`:"&gt;Confessions of Joe Developer&lt;/a&gt;, I finished way too early; plus me and Audrey felt the talk was not technical enough. Even though the reception for my talk was very positive, based on that experience and observation we ramped up the technical content for DjangoCon US and I delivered a much stronger talk. I want to thank the Australian Python community for being a wonderful audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny-event-notes.readthedocs.org/en/latest/PyconAU2011/index.html"&gt;rest of the talks I saw were all quite good&lt;/a&gt;, in fact the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny-event-notes.readthedocs.org/en/latest/PyconAU2011/decorators.html"&gt;one on decorators&lt;/a&gt; was incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result: Super&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conference-meals"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conference Meals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The night before the conference, Frends/mentors Russell Keith-Magee and Malcolm Tredennick took me to a sushi-train place and we gobbled down some very nice raw seafood. Call me silly, but sushi on moving plates just tastes better! Thanks guys!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In between talks they served nice little sandwiches. The coffee bar had lovely Flat Whites and considering the quality of dairy in Australia I was very happy with the break food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first night of the conference they served an amazing, amazing meal. The lamb was like nothing I've tasted before - my best way of describing it was &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;so this is how lamb is supposed to taste&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot;. We also got served Pavlova, which Audrey really enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last evening of the conference we went out to a famous Sydney gastropub/brewery and got kangaroo and crocodile pizza. The kangaroo was outstanding, but the alligator wasn't my thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the conference we went with Graham Dumpleton to a wonderful Dim Sum place and I stuffed myself silly while Audrey quizzed Graham on WSGI. I was sleepy for the rest of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pounds gained? Many.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result: Superb&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="parties"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Parties&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were some lovely dinners and hang-outs. It was incredible putting faces to names and personalities. Everyone looked as I imagined, which meant they looked smashing. Events tended to be lower key, which can make for some wonderfully nice, cozy conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result: Good&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="accomodations"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Accomodations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was no official conference hotel so we stayed at World Hotel - in easy walking distance of the conference center. It wasn't cheap, but I've learned from painful experience that when you travel to a conference, you want to spend your time at the conference, not going to-and-from a cheap hotel five miles away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The staff of the hotel were very nice and helpful. Unfortunately they were working around the limitations of their building. The rooms were really tiny and rather stuffy. Normally that isn't an issue since we spend a lot of our time outside the room, but in this case Audrey was polishing her talk and needed a quiet room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result: Average but not the fault of the conference&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sprints"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sprints&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked with Richard Jones and he implemented OpenID on PyPI so things like &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opencomparison.org"&gt;http://opencomparison.org&lt;/a&gt; could support it. Personally, I would prefer OAUTH but I'll take whatever I can get. One goal at PyCon 2012 is to get that working as another authentication system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise I closed bugs and worked lintification of the project. Audrey and a couple Australian PyLadies, Elena Williams and Jenny Nguyen, worked some core Django documentation tickets. We didn't get as much done as we hoped thanks to an outside distraction, but the organization of the sprints was top-notch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the sprint, those crazy Australians taught us how to do a &lt;strong&gt;Tim Tam Slam&lt;/strong&gt;. It's rather scary and not for the faint of heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result: Great&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="overall-result"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overall Result&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conference was run professionally. The leadership was on the ball. The few issues that cropped up were taken care of, certainly better then what I would have done. Thank you everyone who put it together or just gave us a great time: Tim Ansell, Richard Jones, Nick Coghlan, Russell Keith McGee, Graham Dumpleton, Malcolm Tredennick and many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Australia was amazing. The people were wonderful. I wish we had more time to go sightseeing and relax, but we were off all too quickly. I could write a book about the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Combined Result: Great&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="audrey"></category><category term="australia"></category><category term="review"></category></entry><entry><title>My PyCon 2012 Schedule</title><link href="http://pydanny.github.com/my-pycon-2012-schedule.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-22T09:00:00Z</updated><author><name>Daniel Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.github.com,2012-02-22:/my-pycon-2012-schedule.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here I was thinking that this year's PyCon wasn't going to be so busy because I didn't submit a talk or tutorial. Ha! What the heck was I thinking?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what I've already got in the works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="wednesday-march-7th"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wednesday, March 7th&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me and Audrey are driving up from Los Angeles. I've wanted to do this drive for a while, so this is very exciting. We'll arrive in the evening and hopefully tag up with friends old and new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="thursday-march-8th"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thursday, March 8th&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm moderating the Code Reuse panel of the Python Web Summit. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.google.com/moderator/#15/e=1c9a94&amp;amp;t=1c9a94.43"&gt;Have you submitted a question yet&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening we'll be helping assemble bags for the conference. That's always a blast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="friday-march-9th"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Friday, March 9th&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon really begins! I'll be at the keynotes, and then the talks begin. These are some of the talks I'm really leaning towards watching:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/64/"&gt;Introduction to Metaclasses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/399/"&gt;The Art of Subclassing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/249/"&gt;Data, Design, Meaning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/246/"&gt;Code Generation in Python: Dismantling Jinja&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem, of course, is that all the talks look awesome. Missing some of these talks is going to hurt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening we're going to the New Relic/Loggly/Skull Candy party and hang out at the (in)famous TIP BOF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="saturday-march-10th"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Saturday, March 10th&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be at the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://consumernotebook.com"&gt;Consumer Notebook&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pycon.blogspot.com/2012/02/startup-row-winners-for-pycon-2012.html"&gt;Startup Row&lt;/a&gt; booth all day! Come and hang out with us and all the other bright, new companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening I'm hosting the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/community/openspaces/capoeira/"&gt;PyCon Capoeira Open Space&lt;/a&gt;. We've got a seriously large room assigned for the event, and over twenty five people currently signed up to participate (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bit.ly/pycon-capoeira"&gt;there's still room for signups&lt;/a&gt;). Even if you don't want to play a musical instrument or learn/play at Capoeira, come anyway to watch. Some of the players there have some seriously amazing skills - I can assure you've seen them in the movies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sunday-march-11th"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sunday, March 11th&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More talks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/482/"&gt;Transifex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/301/"&gt;Sketching a better product&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/66/"&gt;Building A Python-Based Search Engine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/168/"&gt;Diversity in practice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="monday-march-12-thursday-march-15"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Monday March 12 - Thursday, March 15&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sprints! Nothing set in stone yet, but some ideas I've had include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launch python.opencomparison.org for all of Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenComparison integration of PyPI OpenID, SourceForge OAUTH, and BitBucket OAUTH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved OpenComparison integration of the Launchpad API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement Gitorious API for OpenComparison.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement Text Based search for OpenComparison.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hack on Mongo related technologies such as django-mongonaut and some other planned projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/"&gt;&lt;img border="0" height="102" width="277" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-fa4jnLXs1so/TniyemLkoiI/AAAAAAAAAqo/LjZqklTFBXk/s400/pycon2012.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="consumernotebook"></category><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>Selected for PyCon StartUp Row</title><link href="http://pydanny.github.com/selected-for-pycon-startup-row.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-21T01:00:00Z</updated><author><name>Daniel Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.github.com,2012-02-21:/selected-for-pycon-startup-row.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Me and Audrey have been working hard on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://consumernotebook.com"&gt;Consumer Notebook&lt;/a&gt;, a Python/Django based project. We submitted it to PyCon StartUp row and found out this morning we've been accepted. &lt;strong&gt;Hooray!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pycon.blogspot.com/2012/02/startup-row-winners-for-pycon-2012.html"&gt;PyCon StartUp Row winner's post&lt;/a&gt;, here is a little bit of what we're about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="highlights"&gt;
Have you tried researching products online recently? Search engines are gamed by scammy marketers. Product review sites overwhelm you with ads, have unreliable reviews, or dryly compare raw product specs. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://consumernotebook.com"&gt;Consumer Notebook&lt;/a&gt; is working to solve this problem. It is like Yelp for products, with product comparison grids inspired by the founders' open-source work on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://djangopackages.com"&gt;Django Packages&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opencomparison.org"&gt;Open Comparison&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just so you know, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://us.pycon.org"&gt;PyCon&lt;/a&gt; in North America is the biggest gathering for the international Python community. The conference this year is in Santa Clara, California, and is sold-out at 1500+ attendees, but could have easily sold out several times that number. The talks, tutorials, and events are going to be incredible, and I'm delighted to be part of the PyCon experience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to sharing the StartUp Row with friends like Transifex, Python Packages, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.weddinglovely.com/"&gt;Wedding Lovely&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please check out &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://consumernotebook.com"&gt;Consumer Notebook&lt;/a&gt; right now and also visit our PyCon booth on Saturday, March 10th and we'll show you what we're doing.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="audrey"></category><category term="consumernotebook"></category><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>Parsing MongoDB URI</title><link href="http://pydanny.github.com/parsing-mongodb-uri.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-20T09:20:00Z</updated><author><name>Daniel Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.github.com,2012-02-20:/parsing-mongodb-uri.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Rather than hard-code the configuration into a Python based settings file, when using a PaaS such as Heroku you want to pick up the MongoDB URI from the system settings. Here's what I do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="c"&gt;# get the dynamic elements from the MongoURI&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;os&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;re&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;r&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;r&amp;#39;^mongodb\:\/\/(?P&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;[_\w]+):(?P&amp;lt;password&amp;gt;[\w]+)@(?P&amp;lt;host&amp;gt;[\.\w]+):(?P&amp;lt;port&amp;gt;\d+)/(?P&amp;lt;database&amp;gt;[_\w]+)$&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;regex&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;re&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;compile&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;r&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;mongolab_url&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;os&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;environ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;MONGOLAB_URI&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;match&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;regex&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;search&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;mongolab_url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;data&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;match&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;groupdict&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="c"&gt;# Save the data to settings&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;MONGO_HOST&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;host&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;MONGO_PORT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;int&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;port&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;])&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;MONGO_NAME&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;username&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;MONGO_DATABASE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;database&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;MONGO_PASSWORD&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;password&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="c"&gt;# Connect to MongoEngine&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kn"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;mongoengine&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;connect&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;me_connect&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;me_connect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;database&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;],&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;host&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;host&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;],&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;port&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;int&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;port&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]),&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;username&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;username&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;],&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;password&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;password&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;])&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="mongodb"></category><category term="howto"></category></entry><entry><title>django-uni-form end of life</title><link href="http://pydanny.github.com/django-uni-form-end-of-life.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-18T01:00:00Z</updated><author><name>Daniel Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.github.com,2012-02-18:/django-uni-form-end-of-life.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I started on django-uni-form in January 2009. In order to use &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pinaxproject.com"&gt;Pinax&lt;/a&gt; on an internal social network for &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nasa.gov"&gt;NASA&lt;/a&gt; HQ, we had to render all content, including forms, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django-uni-form.readthedocs.org/en/latest/concepts.html#section-508"&gt;Section 508&lt;/a&gt; compliant. Rather than rewrite the html for all 50+ forms that existed in the  Pinax 0.5.x framework at that time, I decided to minimize my work and automate things. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jtauber.com"&gt;James Tauber&lt;/a&gt; gave guidance and insight, my co-workers were supportive, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://enn.io"&gt;Jannis Leidel&lt;/a&gt; suggested the Uni-form library. The name &lt;strong&gt;Django Uni-Form&lt;/strong&gt; was obvious, and lo the project was named.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the old, extremely deprecated &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code.google.com/p/django-uni-form/"&gt;Google Code site for django-uni-form&lt;/a&gt;, I see that the first commit happened on January 7th, 2009. That was for version 0.1, with some core code that was literally a merger between the Django form example on how to integrate divs into forms and the simplest template tag I could figure out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The python code in uni_form/templatetags/uni_form.py:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;django.template&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Context&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Template&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kn"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;django.template.loader&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;get_template&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kn"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;django&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;template&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;span class="n"&gt;register&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;template&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nd"&gt;@register.filter&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;as_uni_form&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;form&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;template&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;get_template&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;templates/uni_form.html&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;c&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Context&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;({&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;form&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;form&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;})&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;template&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;render&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The template tag code was nearly exactly copy/pasted from the starter &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/1.0/topics/forms/#looping-over-the-form-s-fields"&gt;Django docs on forms&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;{%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;field&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;form&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;    &amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;ctrlHolder &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;{%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;field.errors&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;{%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;endif&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;{%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;error&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;field.errors&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;            &amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;errorField&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;                &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;error&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;            &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;{%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;endfor&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;field.label_tag&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;field&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;{%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;field.help_text&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;        &amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;formHint&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;field.help_text&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;{%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;endif&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="x"&gt;    &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="cp"&gt;{%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;endfor&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using it was trivial, you just wrote out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;{%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;load&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;uni_form&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="x"&gt;&amp;lt;form&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;form&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;as_uni_form&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;&amp;lt;/form&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="days-of-django-uni-form"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Days of django-uni-form&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading up to &lt;cite&gt;PyCon&lt;/cite&gt; 2009 James Tauber suggested some things that lead to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django-uni-form.readthedocs.org/en/latest/concepts.html#form-helpers"&gt;FormHelpers&lt;/a&gt;, and we hammered out the API on IRC. We knew it crossed the rigid lines between Model-View-Template, but sometimes it's advantageous to break a few rules and abstractions in order to get better things down the road&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At PyCon 2009 with the mentoring of Jannis, James, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://twitter.com/brosner"&gt;Brian Rosner&lt;/a&gt;, I moved the project from google code to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/pydanny/django-uni-form"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. Jannis released it on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pypi.python.org/pypi/"&gt;PyPI&lt;/a&gt; and I followed the pattern he showed me for two years. Yeah, I learned tons under those duys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After PyCon 2009 a pull request with the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django-uni-form.readthedocs.org/en/latest/helpers.html#layouts"&gt;Layout&lt;/a&gt; helper was provided. It took some work to make it pass all the tests and use cases, but the end result was definition of form layout in the Python. This broke the rigid battle lines of Model-View-Template and left purists screaming in agony, but it certainly made working with forms in Django trivially easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lots of people started to use the project across projects like Pinax and organizations like NASA, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pbs.org"&gt;PBS&lt;/a&gt;, Discovery Channel, various newspapers and many others. Lots of pull requests came in and the features grew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2010, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://twitter.com/arowla"&gt;Alice Rowland&lt;/a&gt; submitted the first &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://sphinx.pocoo.org/"&gt;Sphinx&lt;/a&gt; docs, and it was her work that really helped get me started on doing lots of Sphinx work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, all the way into 2011, pull requests for Django Form Sets started to come rolling in, and almost none were of acceptable quality. They never came with documentation, tests, and almost always broke existing tests really hard. Since I'm not a huge fan of Django FormSets, I didn't want to put in a ton of effort making them work. I believe one of them was pretty good, but life was crazy busy at the time and I let it slide. Apologies to whoever it was gave me a working FormSet pull request with documentation, tests, and working code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long periods were going by without new versions. I admit I often slow about accepting pull requests. Life was busy and reviewing the incoming code took a lot of time. Browser cross-checking, running tests, and more was really time consuming. I tried to get others to become co-leads on the project, but invariably they didn't have time to do it. Note: If someone asks you to co-lead something, respond in 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="enter-miguel-araujo"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enter Miguel Araujo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After PyCon 2011, when there was some unpleasant stress in my life, I woke up cranky one morning and mouthed off on twitter to this guy who asked me to accept a pull request on django-uni-form. This guy tweeted back to me saying I ought to be nicer since I had a library people liked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I apologized to the guy (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://twitter.com/maraujop"&gt;Miguel Araujo&lt;/a&gt;) and remembered my manners. Over the next couple of months we chatted via Twitter and Github's messaging system. He was smart, trustworthy, and passionate about everything he did. I knew I had found my co-lead. He responded promptly and I gave him commit rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working together (with him doing the vast majority of the work), we moved the project into new releases. The architecture and design changed, driven by discussions we had together. The code was cleaned up, gnarly bits in there to support old versions of Python and Django kicked out, and the documentation revised. The project had new life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only blip I saw with Miguel is my own fault of sometimes being too nice as a project leader when it comes to accepting pull requests. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django-uni-form.readthedocs.org/en/latest/contributing.html#how-to-get-your-pull-request-accepted"&gt;I believe pull requests should be really atomic&lt;/a&gt; - for one thing and one thing only with support tests and documentation. Otherwise it becomes nigh impossible to incorporate them and these days I reject multi-purpose pull requests.  One pull request in particular took a huge amount of debate and discussion to work in. I think after that Miguel is much better at being upfront at the beginning about rejecting pull requests with giant scopes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During all this I asked Miguel to take over the project, he accepted, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.blogspot.com/2011/06/announcing-django-uni-form-080-beta.html"&gt;I even blogged my announcement his role as project leader&lt;/a&gt;. Miguel is indeed very nice and after that fact he asked me to remain on board as co-lead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finally met in September of 2011 and co-presented on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/pydanny/advanced-django-forms-usage"&gt;Advanced Django Form Usage at DjangoCon 2011&lt;/a&gt;. The deepest technical material we presented was authored by Miguel. During our research he uncovered at least one bug in Django and got an ancient bug closed. It was a great experience and I hope he'll co-present with me in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="django-uni-form-is-dead-long-live-django-crispy-forms"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;django-uni-form is dead, long live django-crispy-forms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The upside of django-uni-form is that it grew in features organically thanks to my own needs and general community effort. The downside of django-uni-form is that it grew in features organically thanks to my own needs and general community effort. In any long running project there is cruft and weird patterns that start to hurt after a while. django-uni-form was no different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I'm making this absolutely official as of now. &lt;strong&gt;django-uni-form is at it's end of life&lt;/strong&gt;. It's done and kaput. No more pull requests will be accepted and the issue tracker will be turned off shortly. Just so no one is mistaken:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;django-uni-form is deprecated. Use django-crispy-forms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miguel asked if he could start the project anew, under a different name. We both had been uncomfortable with the name &lt;em&gt;django-uni-form&lt;/em&gt; for some time, especially since it had almost nothing to do with Uni-form anymore. In fact, I often using template overrides to avoid the Uni-form HTML layout - the most common alternative being &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://twitter.github.com/bootstrap/"&gt;Twitter Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tossed around names for the project, but all of them were stupid, especially mine. We are both huge fans and users of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/brutasse/django-floppyforms"&gt;django-floppyforms&lt;/a&gt; (HTML5 form widget app), so my fiancee, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey Roy&lt;/a&gt;, suggested django-crispy-forms. And lo, the project was named.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/maraujop/django-crispy-forms"&gt;django-crispy-forms&lt;/a&gt; has an improved API, better performance, and supports both Twitter bootstrap forms 2.0 and UniForm. Adding new form layouts will be easier, and feature controls will be better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you should be using now is &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/maraujop/django-crispy-forms"&gt;django-crispy-forms&lt;/a&gt;. Don't worry about changing over as there are &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django-crispy-forms.readthedocs.org/en/d-0/migration.html"&gt;migration instructions&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django-crispy-forms.readthedocs.org/"&gt;excellent documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try it. You'll like it. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="django"></category><category term="python"></category></entry><entry><title>Two years ago today</title><link href="http://pydanny.github.com/two-years-ago-today.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-17T09:20:00Z</updated><author><name>Daniel Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.github.com,2012-02-17:/two-years-ago-today.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://us.pycon.org"&gt;PyCon&lt;/a&gt; tutorial on Django in Depth was ending. I had been sitting next to my friend &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://djangrrl.com/"&gt;Barbara&lt;/a&gt; and we got up to go when I heard a feminine voice ask: &amp;quot;Are you &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/bshaurette"&gt;bshaurette&lt;/a&gt;?&amp;quot; I turned and it was like I got punched in the gut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the first time I met &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey&lt;/a&gt;. I remember every detail of how she looked at that moment. The clothes she was wearing, the part in her hair, that her eyes met mine, and that they didn't turn away. I was immediately captivating, but fortunately remembered to act like a gentleman. I tossed in a casual invitation to her to join us for lunch, which I pulled off even though my heart was pounding. Thankfully she accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life has been pretty much awesome ever since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the day I met the love of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pycon"></category><category term="audrey"></category></entry><entry><title>My new blog</title><link href="http://pydanny.github.com/my-new-blog.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-17T00:30:00Z</updated><author><name>Daniel Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.github.com,2012-02-17:/my-new-blog.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What I did to get it running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
pip install pelican
git clone git://github.com/pydanny/pydanny.github.com.git
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My settings.py file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
AUTHOR = 'Daniel Greenfeld'
DISQUS_SITENAME = 'pydanny'
GITHUB_URL = 'https://github.com/pydanny'
GOOGLE_ANALYTICS='UA-18066389-2'
SITEURL = 'http://pydanny.github.com'
SITENAME = 'pydanny'
SOCIAL = (('twitter', 'http://twitter.com/pydanny'),
          ('github', 'https://github.com/pydanny'),
          ('facebook', 'http://www.facebook.com/daniel.greenfeld'),)
TAG_FEED = 'feeds/%s.atom.xml'
THEME='notmyidea'
TWITTER_USERNAME = 'pydanny'
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How I push up entries and pages and themes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
pelican . -o . -s settings.py
git commit -am &amp;quot;blogging here&amp;quot;
git push
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="results"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Results!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.github.com"&gt;http://pydanny.github.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="blog"></category></entry><entry><title>Tried out Jekyll</title><link href="http://pydanny.github.com/tried-out-jekyll.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-09T10:20:00Z</updated><author><name>Daniel Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.github.com,2012-02-09:/tried-out-jekyll.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="why-jekyll"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why Jekyll?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've had issues with Blogger for some time.  After my fiancee, Audrey Roy, moved her blog to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll"&gt;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, I was impressed enough to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did it impress me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="code-highlighting-made-easy"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Code highlighting made easy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't have to hand-craft HTML code to get google prettify in a post. I just stick in a simple macro of 'highlight python' called like a Django templatetag and I get:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;Daniel Greenfeld&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;letter&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;split&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;():&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;letter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This issue alone sums up why I don't do more blog posts with code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-don-t-want-to-maintain-my-own-blog-site"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I don't want to maintain my own blog site&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple times I rolled out a blog on a site I stood up, but didn't really feel like maintaining a site. I want someone else to do it. When I write, I want someone else to worry about the details. I want to focus on writing and nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-want-to-be-able-to-write-without-connection"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I want to be able to write without connection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need an internet connection to get my blogger posts to format right. With Jekyll, I can just type away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ability-to-publish-via-git"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ability to publish via git&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny-event-notes.rtfd.org"&gt;http://pydanny-event-notes.rtfd.org&lt;/a&gt; has really exploded in my own usage and continued because it uses the same patterns I use in software development. I'm used to the pattern of using Git to push up content, so why use naked HTML? Sure, there are RST-to-HTML processors that I could use to generate that HTML, but they always require an some amount of manual correction. Jekyll, and it's alternatives,let me just write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="why-not-jekyll"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why not Jekyll?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is written in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ruby-lang.org"&gt;ruby&lt;/a&gt;. Nothing against ruby, but I can't trivially work in that language the way I can in Python. It's good to eat your own dogfood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I started looking at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hyde.github.com/"&gt;hyde&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blogofile.com/"&gt;blogofile&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pelican.readthedocs.org/"&gt;pelican&lt;/a&gt; as alternatives. More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="ruby"></category><category term="blog"></category></entry></feed>