<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>pydanny</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pydanny.com/feeds/audrey.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pydanny.com/</id><updated>2013-02-28T15:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>Two Scoops of Django 1.5 Beta Released</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/two-scoops-beta-released.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-28T15:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2013-02-28:two-scoops-beta-released.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After thirty four days of hard work, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey Roy&lt;/a&gt; and I are proud to announce that we've released the &lt;strong&gt;beta&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;Two Scoops of Django: Best Practices for Django 1.5&lt;/a&gt;. It's been a monumental effort, a labor of love, and we hope you find our efforts worthy. You can buy it right now in e-book (PDF) form on the website: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;http://django.2scoops.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two Scoops of Django: Best Practices for Django 1.5 is a compilation of best practices for the Django framework. Like any framework, Django has tips, tricks, and pitfalls that aren't documented in one place. Experienced developers know this stuff, but gleaning it off the Internet takes a lot of time. We decided to take everything we know and write it down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stand of the shoulders of giants: We received advice from Django experts including a BDFL, Django core developers, and subject matter experts from around the world. Reader contributions from advanced and beginning developers have also shaped the book, and we can't thank enough those who gave us their insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://django.2scoops.org/"&gt;&lt;img alt="https://s3.amazonaws.com/twoscoops/img/tsd-cover-beta.png" class="align-center" id="two-scoops-of-django" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/twoscoops/img/tsd-cover-beta.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a name="features"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class="section" id="what-is-different-about-the-beta-release"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is different about the beta release?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added 50+ pages of content while reducing the file size from 5.1 MB to 1.5 MB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added list of tables, list of figures, and an index.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dramatically improved the chapters on security, testing, logging, admin, and many more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added so many more code samples that even with the new example numbering system we lost count.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaking of code examples, most of the code samples in the book are loaded directly out of fully tested projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incorporated the feedback of dozens of readers. Thank you so much for your contributions!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;a name="what-do-i-get"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-does-buying-the-beta-get-me"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What does buying the beta get me?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access the PDF version of the book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access to the Kindle and ePub formats when we release the final.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access to final release of the book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;a name="alpha-buyers"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="if-i-bought-the-alpha-do-i-have-to-buy-the-beta"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;If I bought the alpha do I have to buy the beta?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alpha buyers get full access the beta. In fact, you should have already received an email with a link to the latest version. If that hasn't arrived, please email us at &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com"&gt;2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name="beginners"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="is-this-book-good-for-beginners"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is this book good for beginners?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The response from beginning Django developers reading it has been &lt;strong&gt;unbelievably, overwhelmingly positive&lt;/strong&gt;. This is the book we wanted to have when we learned Django, and we're honored by the response the book has received.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the book isn't a tutorial, we ask that before beginners purchase it, they &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://learnpythonthehardway.org/"&gt;learn the fundamentals of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Learn-Python-Hard-Way-Introduction/dp/0321884914/?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=cn-001-20"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; and take the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/1.5/intro/tutorial01/"&gt;official Django tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When beginners find sections of the book above their head, they do what everyone does when reading a technical reference: skip over challenging sections until they have enough grounding to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any beginners are confused by our explanations, or have difficulties, please email us at &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com"&gt;2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com&lt;/a&gt;. We'll do our best to answer your questions. Your issues provide invaluable insight into what we need to improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name="experienced"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="is-this-book-good-for-experienced-developers"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is this book good for experienced developers?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've done our best to provide worthwhile material for developers of all levels. In fact, a lot of intermediate to advanced developers have said they've found good things to use in our book. Many have also found that by using our book as a supplementary manual, it helps them their team work better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name="updates"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="is-this-book-going-to-get-updated"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is this book going to get updated?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the &lt;strong&gt;alpha&lt;/strong&gt; we updated the book multiple times before knuckling down on the &lt;strong&gt;beta&lt;/strong&gt; rewrite. Even after the final version comes out, we'll continue to update the book. One of the advantages of self-published e-books is we have total control of content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name="print"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="when-can-i-get-a-print-version"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When can I get a print version?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a lot of consideration, we've decided to hold off on the print version of the book until what we call the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.com/two-scoops-beta-released.html#final"&gt;final&lt;/a&gt; release, which won't be released until after &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/"&gt;PyCon US&lt;/a&gt;. We're very finicky and don't want buyers of the print version to have an unfinished book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name="tutorial"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a name="pycon"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a name="wiring-up-django-packages"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="tutorial-pycon-are-you-going"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tutorial? PyCon? Are you going?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes! We're going to be at PyCon next month!  We're giving the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/11/"&gt;Wiring Up Django Packages&lt;/a&gt; tutorial, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://brack3t.com/"&gt;Kenneth Love&lt;/a&gt; (of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gettingstartedwithdjango.com/"&gt;Getting Started with Django&lt;/a&gt; fame) is part of our team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While tickets to PyCon itself are sold out, you can still &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/registration/register/"&gt;register for the tutorials&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name="final"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="when-is-the-book-s-final-release"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When is the book's final release?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final release won't occur until after PyCon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our plan for the final release of Two Scoops of Django: Best Practices for Django 1.5 is to focus on errata, alternative electronic formats, and the print version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name="bulk"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="can-we-purchase-the-book-in-bulk"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Can we purchase the book in bulk?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're working on a program to provide organizations the capability to purchase many e-copies and keep the recipients of the book updated constantly. We hope to have this ready in a few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name="paypal"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="can-i-buy-the-book-via-paypal"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Can I buy the book via PayPal?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No. I'll answer why in a blog post next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're considering other non-credit card options to handle payment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name="known-issue-warnings"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="known-issue-warnings"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Known Issue Warnings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="copy-paste"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Copy/Paste&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are problems with copy/pasting of code from the PDF. The new build process is turning the code examples into some sort of image type of object, which explains the strange characters. We're working on it, but aren't sure how long the fix will take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="android"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Android&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Android, if you try to open the PDF directly from the Gumroad download, you might get a &amp;quot;Cannot open file&amp;quot; error; however, if you navigate to the download location on your phone/tablet with a file browser (e.g. Samsung's &amp;quot;My Files&amp;quot;), you should be able to open the file from there. Gumroad is currently investigating the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name="errata"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="where-should-i-send-errata-or-suggestions"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where should I send errata or suggestions?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send errata to &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com"&gt;2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com&lt;/a&gt;. We try to respond personally to every request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="twoscoops"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="audrey"></category><category term="pycon"></category></entry><entry><title>Beginner's Guide to PyCon 2013 Part II</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/beginners-guide-pycon-2013-part-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-23T16:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2013-01-23:beginners-guide-pycon-2013-part-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is Part II in a series of blog posts about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/"&gt;PyCon US 2013&lt;/a&gt;. The goal is to provide a handy reference guide for first time attendees of the world's largest &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://python.org"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; conference. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.com/beginners-guide-pycon-2013-part-1.html"&gt;Part I&lt;/a&gt; was mostly about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/tutorials/"&gt;tutorials&lt;/a&gt;, this post will be about registration and the first day of talks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="registration"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Registration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven't done so yet, please &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/registration/register/"&gt;register&lt;/a&gt; now. Last year PyCon sold out way in advance, and hundreds missed the event. Which is a shame, because the conference is awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that the money you spend on registration will go towards a very good thing. You see, after the costs for running PyCon are subtracted, the rest will go to the non-profit Python Software Foundation (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://python.org/psf/"&gt;PSF&lt;/a&gt;). In addition to supporting the Python language itself, the PSF provides financial aid and grants for aspiring developers around the world. Which means the money you spend registering for PyCon will literally change people's lives. This isn't an idle exaggeration, this outreach has made a difference for you, me, and arguably the world. I would love to say more, but that's an article for another day...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, on to the talks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="talk-attendance-guidelines"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Talk Attendance Guidelines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At PyCon, talks are either 30 or 45 long. They represent the best and brightest in both old hands in the community and rising stars. Some quick guidelines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask Questions!&lt;/strong&gt; If the speaker leaves time for questions at the end, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://cecinestpasun.com/entries/i-can-haz-question-or-five/"&gt;go and ask&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shut the Laptop and Turn Off the Device.&lt;/strong&gt; It's disconcerting to give a speech to hundreds of people staring at their portable electronics and not responding to your banter. Unless you are using electronics to actively take notes on the talk, consider turning them off to look at the speaker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't Heckle.&lt;/strong&gt; It's nerve wracking going up in front of hundreds of people live and tens of thousands on streaming video. Heckling is &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; funny and it's a good way to lose friends and make enemies. Unless the speaker asks for commentary during the talk, wait until the end and then ask your questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, that out of the way, let's take a look at what Friday, March 15th, has to offer in terms of beginner friendly talks...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="friday-morning"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Friday Morning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The registration desk opens at 7:00 AM. Breakfast begins at 8:00 AM. From 9:00 AM to 10:20 AM is the welcome and initial keynote speeches. PyCon keynotes aren't boring - &lt;strong&gt;they are crazy awesome!&lt;/strong&gt; Say hi if you see me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In selecting these talks, I've tried to focus on the more technical ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="am-talks"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;10:50 AM talks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/35/"&gt;How to Except When You're Excepting&lt;/a&gt; (Esther Nam) - One of the rising stars of the community, Esther works for a group that demands 100% test coverage. She's going to cover the fundamentals of writing tests and why tests are a good thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/50/"&gt;How the Internet works&lt;/a&gt; (Jessica McKellar) - Want to know how the internet actually works? Jessica McKellar (also giving two tutorials and a keynote speech) will use Python to help you understand what's really going on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/116/"&gt;Gittip: Inspiring Generosity&lt;/a&gt; (Chad Whitacre) - Gittip is an open source Python platform for sustaining open source development via small, anonymous donations. This is a technical case-study about the story of community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id1"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;11:30 AM talks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/135/"&gt;Scrapy: it GETs the web&lt;/a&gt; (Asheesh Laroia) - In 2009 I took a web scraping tutorial by the author. He impressed me with his energy and knowledge. While technically this is an &lt;strong&gt;intermediate&lt;/strong&gt; talk, I know everyone will get something out of this talk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id2"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;12:10 AM talks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/39/"&gt;API Design for Library Authors&lt;/a&gt; (Chris McDonough) - Well designed APIs are critical for how other developers interact with your code. Chris is one of the talents in the community when it comes to creating easy-to-use but extremely powerful tools. I'm delighted he's made this an introductory talk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="friday-lunch"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Friday Lunch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't forget to keep your PyCon meal tickets you got when you registered in the morning or they won't let you into the lunch room!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sit down to people you don't know and introduce yourself. Every time I do this I don't just get to meet interesting people, I get to meet &lt;strong&gt;amazing&lt;/strong&gt; people. PyCon is full of brilliant minds and you'll never get to know any of them unless you try.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="friday-afternoon"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Friday Afternoon&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got lunch? Time for more talks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pm-talks"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1:40 PM talks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/58/"&gt;Using Python To Generate Art And Sound&lt;/a&gt; (Audrey Roy) - This is an &lt;strong&gt;intermediate&lt;/strong&gt; talk, but myself and those who have seen it can assure you it's a very good talk. Audrey demonstrates how to use Python tools like NumPy, SciPy, and PIL to make lovely things. You probably already know that Audrey and I wrote a Django book together, but you probably don't know that she wrote a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Very-Magical-Caterpillar-Tale-Butterfly/dp/1453714081/?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=cn-001-20"&gt;book about  caterpillars&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/54/"&gt;You can be a speaker at PyCon!&lt;/a&gt; (Anna Ravenscroft, Lynn Root) - PyCon loves new blood. Get some pointers on how to get your talks ready for submission next year!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/117/"&gt;Python 3.3: Trust Me, It's Better than 2.7&lt;/a&gt; (Brett Cannon) - The world of Python is heading towards Python 3. Want to know why? Attend this talk!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pm-talk"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1:55 PM talk&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/40/"&gt;Twisted Logic&lt;/a&gt; (Ashwini Oruganti) - Twisted is a mature, stable asynchronous framework written in Python that's been around for over a decade. New to the framework, the presenter explains why you shouldn't be scared of Twisted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id3"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2:35 PM talks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This slot is going to be hard because all three beginner talks are things you don't want to miss!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/76/"&gt;Loop like a native: while, for, iterators, generators&lt;/a&gt; (Ned Batchelder) - One of the really awesome features of Python is that you can write custom looping classes. Factor in generators and you'll be amazed by one of Python's most powerful features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/112/"&gt;Visualizing Github, Part I: Data to Information&lt;/a&gt; (Dana Bauer, Idan Gazit) - How can you go wrong with visualizing GitHub data using Python?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/145/"&gt;Encapsulation with descriptors&lt;/a&gt; (Luciano Ramalho) - Python has no private fields, but the property decorator lets you replace public attributes with getters and setters without breaking client code. It's amazing what Python can do when you delve into it's subtleties!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id4"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3:15 PM talk&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/136/"&gt;Music Theory and Performance Analysis with Sebastian and Czerny&lt;/a&gt; (James Tauber) - An amazing speaker talking about one of his favorite subjects, this will be a great beginner talk. James mentored me in my early days of Django and JQuery, and I only have good things to say about him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id5"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4:15 PM talks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/126/"&gt;Transforming Code into Beautiful, Idiomatic Python&lt;/a&gt; (Raymond Hettinger) - This is the talk that's going to bring down the house, because Raymond covers the basics in such a way that even the most advanced developers pick up new tricks. This talk will be standing room only, filled with beginners to the most senior developers on the planet. Get to this one early or you'll miss it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/118/"&gt;Deploy your Python app in 5 min with a PaaS&lt;/a&gt; (Nate Aune) - Long time presenter Nate Aune doesn't just explain and demonstrate various Platforms as a Service, he also gives tips on evaluating which one is best for your needs. For someone getting into the Python web this talk is an invaluable service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="talk"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4:30 talk&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/124/"&gt;If You Code, You Should Write&lt;/a&gt; (Brian Jones) - Python has an amazing culture of documentation. We believe it's our civic duty to document our work on private and public projects. Brian explains why this is so and how to get across the concepts of your work in the best way possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="talks"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5:10 talks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/65/"&gt;SimpleCV - Computer Vision using Python&lt;/a&gt; (Katherine Scott) - This is a crash course on computer vision using the amazing ipython notebook along with NumPy and SciPy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/96/"&gt;Planning and Tending the Garden: The Future of Early Childhood Python Education&lt;/a&gt; (Kurt Grandis) - After his PyCon talk last year about using Python to fend off squirrels, Kurt suddenly found himself in the world of kid's education. This talk goes over the current state of the art for kids learning programming in Python and other tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/113/"&gt;Write the Docs&lt;/a&gt; (James Bennett) - Have you heard of a certain well-documented web framework called 'Django'? James Bennett is one of the people responsible for it's amazingly high documentation standard. In this talk he's going to coach on how to write prose that inspires and invigorates people to use your tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="evening-activities"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Evening Activities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On friday night the social scene will kick into high gear. There will be dinners, parties, Starcraft II contests, and hopefully the second year of PyCon Capoeira. As these become more definite I'll adding them to this post!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="part-iii"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Part III&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for Part III of this series where I cover the second day of talks best suited for new Python developers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="audrey"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon-2013-guide"></category></entry><entry><title>Beginner's Guide to PyCon 2013 Part I</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/beginners-guide-pycon-2013-part-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-22T16:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2013-01-22:beginners-guide-pycon-2013-part-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;New to Python and thinking about going to the upcoming &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/"&gt;PyCon US&lt;/a&gt; for the first time? You know, that big &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://python.org"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; conference taking place near San Francisco in March?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps you signed up already and are getting worried about being overwhelmed by hundreds of tutorials, talks, and activities?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No worries! This multi-part guide will aid you in getting the most out of attending one of the best technical conferences on the planet. I'm going to share how to get through the whole event in good shape and cover some incredible beginner friendly events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-basics"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Basics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/registration/register/"&gt;register&lt;/a&gt; already! PyCon US sold out last year around this time. Don't be left out in the cold. Buy your ticket now before it's too late!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you've got that done, keep in mind that Python has two days of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/tutorials/"&gt;tutorials&lt;/a&gt;, three days of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/talks/"&gt;talks&lt;/a&gt;, and four days of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/community/sprints/"&gt;sprints&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Nine days of Python!&lt;/strong&gt; The trick is to not get exhausted or sick. Therefore, do the following every day of the conference:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take at least one shower. Please.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eat at least two good meals. Make a point of sitting with different people at each meal and introducing yourself. Make new friends!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get at least three hours of sleep. More if possible because your brain is going to go into learning overdrive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, PyCon US also has a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/about/code-of-conduct/"&gt;code of conduct&lt;/a&gt;. I like to sum it up as, &amp;quot;Act professionally.&amp;quot; Whether or not you agree with codes of conduct for conferences, PyCon US has one and it will be enforced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, enough basics, let's get onto tutorials!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="tutorials"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tutorials&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tutorials take place on March 13th and 14th. They each cost $150 but are well worth the price. The following are the talks I believe are best suited for beginners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="wednesday-morning"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Wednesday Morning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For novice programmers start with Jessica McKellar's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/1/"&gt;A hands-on introduction to Python for beginning programmers&lt;/a&gt;. I can vouch that the instructor is amazing, and will jumpstart you on the road to being a Python developer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are you an experienced developer new to Python? I suggest &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/8/"&gt;Going from web pages to web apps with Python&lt;/a&gt; by Asheesh Loroia and Karen Rustad. In 2009 I took a class by Asheesh and was impressed by his energy, enthusiasm, and depth of knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to learn Python web that isn't Django? Try out Paul Everitt's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/12/"&gt;Pyramid for Humans&lt;/a&gt; class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="wednesday-afternoon"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Wednesday Afternoon&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You simply can't go wrong with David Beazley's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/2/"&gt;Learn Python Through Public Data Hacking&lt;/a&gt;. He's the author of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Python-Essential-Reference-4th-Edition/dp/0672329786/?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=cn-001-20"&gt;Python Essential Reference&lt;/a&gt;, an amazing instructor, and delivered a PyCon keynote last year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you're interested in the web, check out Nathan Yergler's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/9/"&gt;Effective Django&lt;/a&gt;. I can assure you that he knows his Django material and is going to deliver a great experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="thursday-morning"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Thursday Morning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you're new to Python, you need to learn the Python environment. This means version control, PyPI, test automation, and more. Matt Harrison covers this in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/3/"&gt;Scripting: from Hard-drive to Github to PyPI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting back to the web, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/10/"&gt;Fully Test-Driven Web Development with Django and Selenium&lt;/a&gt; is another run through the Django tutorial, but done from the test driven perspective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fascinating tutorial offered at this time is &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/30/"&gt;A Gentle Introduction to Computer Vision&lt;/a&gt;. It's a great way to learn how Python is used in many creative and unexpected ways.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="thursday-afternoon"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Thursday Afternoon&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jessica McKellar returns to instruct on how to give back to the community with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/4/"&gt;Contribute with me! Getting started with open source development&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to learn how to program games? Look no further than Richard Jones' &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/19/"&gt;Introduction to PyGame&lt;/a&gt;. He's taught this class for years, and I can't say enough good things about him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shameless Plug:&lt;/strong&gt; My talk is not meant for beginning Django developers, but I'm listing it anyway. It's my blog, right? In any case, along with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey Roy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gettingstartedwithdjango.com/"&gt;Kenneth Love&lt;/a&gt;, we're presenting &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/11/"&gt;Wiring Up Django Packages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="part-ii"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Part II&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.com/beginners-guide-pycon-2013-part-2.html"&gt;Beginner's Guide to PyCon 2013 Part II&lt;/a&gt; where I cover the first day of talks best suited for new Python developers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="audrey"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon-2013-guide"></category></entry><entry><title>Two Scoops of Django FAQ</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/two-scoops-django-faq-20130121.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-21T16:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2013-01-21:two-scoops-django-faq-20130121.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://django.2scoops.org/"&gt;&lt;img alt="https://s3.amazonaws.com/pydanny/frontispiece.png" class="align-center" id="two-scoops-of-django" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/pydanny/frontispiece.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;Two Scoops of Django: Best Practices for Django 1.5&lt;/a&gt; book has gone pretty well. The response has been almost entirely positive and sales have been pretty brisk. We've gotten a ton of great, constructive editorial feedback, which we're sorting through as we race towards the BETA release. Here are answers to the commonly asked questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="when-can-i-buy-the-book-via-paypal"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When can I buy the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; via PayPal?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will support PayPal in either the BETA or FINAL release of the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to handle PayPal we need to find a reputable e-publisher that supports it that gives us similar rates, customer service, and product control (updates at any time, uploads of PDF, no surprise charges, etc) as &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gumroad.com"&gt;Gumroad&lt;/a&gt;. If you know of an e-publisher who is willing to provide that same level of service, please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the record, we aren't leaving &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gumroad.com"&gt;Gumroad&lt;/a&gt;. We just want to support developers and students who don't have credit cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;note:&lt;/strong&gt; While we could certainly write our own publishing platform, that would delay work on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt;. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="when-can-i-get-a-kindle-mobi-or-epub-version"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When can I get a Kindle (mobi) or ePub version?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our plan is to support those formats in either the BETA or FINAL releases. In fact, I really love my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B007HCCNJU/?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=cn-001-20"&gt;Kindle&lt;/a&gt;. I can't wait to proof my own &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; on my favorite reading device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="when-can-i-get-a-print-version"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When can I get a print version?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope to have a print version in about 30 days. We need to ensure that the cover and layout actually looks nice, and that involves ordering copies from the Lulu, CreateSpace, whatever and reviewing them and making corrections. Then ordering again to make sure the corrections look okay. That simply takes a lot of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are hoping for a mid-February release. Also, keep in mind we aren't sure yet if we'll do a print version of anything but a FINAL release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="when-are-the-beta-and-final-releases"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When are the BETA and FINAL releases?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can't make promises, but at the latest, the FINAL &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be done by the start of March so people have them in hand at PyCon US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="is-this-book-going-to-get-updated"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is this book going to get updated?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, we've already sent out three minor updates for grammar and spelling issues, and some bug fixes.  Even after the FINAL version comes out, we'll continue to update the book. One of the advantages of self-published books is we have control of content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-much-work-went-into-the-book"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How much work went into the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey&lt;/a&gt; and I put in hundreds of hours writing and testing the content. We worked 12-16 hour days for weeks. It was madness, but a glorious madness. We became like hermits and toiled on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; while ignoring distractions like sleep, food and consistent exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our amazing technical reviewers also worked very hard to provide us with critical commentary, advice and corrections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="where-should-i-send-errata"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where should I send errata?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send errata to &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com"&gt;2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com&lt;/a&gt;. The first person who reports an issue or makes a suggestion that we adopt will receive credit in the book. If not in the changelog, then in the dialogue of the book itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="are-you-going-to-pycon-us"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Are you going to PyCon US?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely! Wouldn't miss &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/"&gt;PyCon US&lt;/a&gt; for the world! &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey&lt;/a&gt; and I met and fell in love at PyCon US 2010! We'll be there for at least the second day of  tutorials, all the talks, and all the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/community/sprints/"&gt;sprints&lt;/a&gt;. I've even got a blog post coming that should serve as a guide for beginning Python and Django developers attending the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shameless Plug:&lt;/em&gt; We're both speaking and giving a tutorial. Sign up for the tutorial or attend our talks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="wiring-up-django-packages-tutorial"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/11/"&gt;Wiring Up Django Packages&lt;/a&gt; (Tutorial)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You just finished the Django tutorial. What do you do now? You wire in Django Packages! Django is part of an ecosphere of over 20,000 packages, which can be leveraged to great effect. This tutorial will teach the evaluation, use, and extension of third party Python and Django applications in your projects. This tutorial will be a lecture with a lot of detailed and annotated code examples. Instructors are &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey Roy&lt;/a&gt;, Daniel Greenfeld, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://brack3t.com/"&gt;Kenneth Love&lt;/a&gt; (of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gettingstartedwithdjango.com/"&gt;Getting Started with Django&lt;/a&gt; fame).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="advanced-django-forms-usage-talk"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/101/"&gt;Advanced Django Forms Usage&lt;/a&gt;  (Talk)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django forms are really powerful but there are edge cases, especially with class based views), that can cause a bit of anguish. This talk will go over how to handle many common solutions not currently described in the core documentation. It will also cover useful third-party libraries. Speaker is Daniel Greenfeld.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="using-python-to-generate-art-and-sound-talk"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/58/"&gt;Using Python To Generate Art And Sound&lt;/a&gt; (Talk)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trick to navigating the overwhelming Python audio/imaging landscape is understanding how the fundamentals work, using common data processing/visualization libraries, in-depth code samples, and simple math operations. I use the stdlib, NumPy, SciPy, Matplotlib, PIL, and PyCairo to create building blocks, which I then combine to demonstrate advanced sound and image generation techniques. Speaker is &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey Roy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="are-you-going-to-django-circus"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Are you going to Django Circus?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope so. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://2013.djangocon.eu/"&gt;Django Circus&lt;/a&gt;, a.k.a. DjangoCon Europe, is one of the important industry events for us and we're trying to figure out logistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our problem is that 2012 was a very hard year - the majority of our clients have not paid for the work that we did. Collecting is turning out to be extremely difficult, time consuming, and unpleasant. This is impacting everything we want to do in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-does-the-alpha-work"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How does the ALPHA work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ALPHA is a preview version that we are selling at an introductory price of $12. When you purchase the ALPHA, you get access to the BETA and FINAL versions when they are released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you're wondering, we are planning to increase the price of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; when we release the BETA and FINAL versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="twoscoops"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="audrey"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="djangocon"></category></entry><entry><title>Our Django Book Has Launched</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/our-django-book-is-launched.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-17T10:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2013-01-17:our-django-book-is-launched.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://django.2scoops.org/"&gt;&lt;img alt="https://s3.amazonaws.com/twoscoops/img/tsd-cover.png" class="align-center" id="two-scoops-of-django-best-practices-for-django-1-5" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/twoscoops/img/tsd-cover.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey Roy&lt;/a&gt; and I) wrote a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; on Django! It's called &lt;strong&gt;Two Scoops of Django: Best Practices for Django 1.5&lt;/strong&gt;, and you can buy it right now in e-book (PDF) form on the website: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;http://django.2scoops.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django, like any framework, has tips, tricks, and pitfalls that aren't documented in one place. Experienced developers know this stuff, but gleaning it off the Internet takes a lot of time. We decided to take everything we know and write it down. This &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; reflects a portion of what we documented, and if it does well we plan to follow it up with other references.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've followed this blog or watched our talks you've know we've explained tons of Django and Python related examples. We enjoy using Django and Python to build stable, fast web applications quickly and efficiently. This is the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; we would have wanted while learning the intricacies of our tools, and then kept it handy for reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; we cover everything from customizing the Django 1.5 User model, forms,  views, templates, security, bottleneck analysis and so much more. We tie in third-party packages from the Django and Python community. We discuss the positive patterns that allow for rapid development, and point out the anti-patterns that cause problems.
The result isn't a walk-through or tutorial, but a reference guide for anyone with at least a basic understanding of Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tried to make the code copy/pastable, but we are constrained by the limits of PDF. While the code examples display nicely, &lt;em&gt;when pasting from Adobe Reader the leading white spaces vanish&lt;/em&gt;. We apologize and ask if anyone knows how to address this issue to let us know at &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com"&gt;2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even with an amazing cadre of technical reviewers, there is always the possibility of errors. We are going to be actively maintaining the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt;, so if you find a mistake, let us know and we'll update it and send out an updated copy of the PDF to all buyers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you'd like to buy the book (or learn more about it), you can do so here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;http://django.2scoops.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="twoscoops"></category><category term="resolutions"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="audrey"></category><category term="class-based-views"></category><category term="heroku"></category><category term="dotcloud"></category><category term="gondor"></category></entry><entry><title>PyCon Australia 2011 Review</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/pycon-australia-2011-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-24T12:45:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2012-02-24:pycon-australia-2011-review.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In June of 2011 I had the good fortune of having my then girlfriend, Audrey Roy, now fiancee, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.blogspot.com/2011/06/im-going-to-pycon-australia.html"&gt;invited to present a keynote speech at PyCon Australia 2011&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was terribly excited for her to get that invitation, and that excitement was compounded when they allowed me to present on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/pydanny/confessions-of-a-joe-developer`:"&gt;Confessions of Joe Developer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travel is a passion of mine, and it's only been since 2007 that I've gotten a chance to do much seeing of the world. Australia was always this distant goal of mine, but I never thought I would get the chance to go. Fortunately, my assumption was wrong and we landed on August 18th in Sydney, Australia!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audrey &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreyr.posterous.com/thank-you-pycon-au"&gt;wrote her own statement about the event&lt;/a&gt; right after we were done. She's good that way. Okay then, off to my own review. This is belated, but better late then never, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conference-rooms"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conference Rooms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sydney Masonic Center was the venue and it was a really curious building. They built it a while ago, then apparently grafted an office building onto the top of the temple. &lt;strong&gt;You have to see it to believe it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main temple room was room, interesting, and fun. The acoustics, to my limited ear, seemed quite good. The alternative rooms for some of the tracks were small presentation rooms, which did quite nicely except when the organizers chose popular talks for small rooms and things overflowed. Everyone was good natured about that and we all just worked it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result: Great&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="speakers"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Speakers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm partial but I think the opening keynote by Audrey Roy about diversity was wonderful. Mary Gardinar also talk about open source projects trying to change the world that need our support. Raymond Hettiger seriously delivered the goods with another version of his amazing talk about what makes Python great. Whatever you do, go and see it as many times as possible because he changes it each and every time.  Richard Jones' presentation on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny-event-notes.readthedocs.org/en/latest/PyconAU2011/zen_of_python.html"&gt;Zen of Python&lt;/a&gt; was very solid too, and I'll use this as an opportunity to promote my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pypi.python.org/pypi/that"&gt;Anti-Zen of Python&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it came time for me to present on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/pydanny/confessions-of-a-joe-developer`:"&gt;Confessions of Joe Developer&lt;/a&gt;, I finished way too early; plus me and Audrey felt the talk was not technical enough. Even though the reception for my talk was very positive, based on that experience and observation we ramped up the technical content for DjangoCon US and I delivered a much stronger talk. I want to thank the Australian Python community for being a wonderful audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny-event-notes.readthedocs.org/en/latest/PyconAU2011/index.html"&gt;rest of the talks I saw were all quite good&lt;/a&gt;, in fact the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny-event-notes.readthedocs.org/en/latest/PyconAU2011/decorators.html"&gt;one on decorators&lt;/a&gt; was incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result: Super&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conference-meals"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conference Meals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The night before the conference, Frends/mentors Russell Keith-Magee and Malcolm Tredennick took me to a sushi-train place and we gobbled down some very nice raw seafood. Call me silly, but sushi on moving plates just tastes better! Thanks guys!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In between talks they served nice little sandwiches. The coffee bar had lovely Flat Whites and considering the quality of dairy in Australia I was very happy with the break food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first night of the conference they served an amazing, amazing meal. The lamb was like nothing I've tasted before - my best way of describing it was &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;so this is how lamb is supposed to taste&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot;. We also got served Pavlova, which Audrey really enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last evening of the conference we went out to a famous Sydney gastropub/brewery and got kangaroo and crocodile pizza. The kangaroo was outstanding, but the alligator wasn't my thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the conference we went with Graham Dumpleton to a wonderful Dim Sum place and I stuffed myself silly while Audrey quizzed Graham on WSGI. I was sleepy for the rest of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pounds gained? Many.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result: Superb&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="parties"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Parties&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were some lovely dinners and hang-outs. It was incredible putting faces to names and personalities. Everyone looked as I imagined, which meant they looked smashing. Events tended to be lower key, which can make for some wonderfully nice, cozy conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result: Good&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="accommodations"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Accommodations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was no official conference hotel so we stayed at World Hotel - in easy walking distance of the conference center. It wasn't cheap, but I've learned from painful experience that when you travel to a conference, you want to spend your time at the conference, not going to-and-from a cheap hotel five miles away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The staff of the hotel were very nice and helpful. Unfortunately they were working around the limitations of their building. The rooms were really tiny and rather stuffy. Normally that isn't an issue since we spend a lot of our time outside the room, but in this case Audrey was polishing her talk and needed a quiet room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result: Average but not the fault of the conference&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sprints"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sprints&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked with Richard Jones about PyPI authentication issues, and he decided to go with OpenID. Personally, I would prefer OAUTH but I'll take whatever I can get. On the behalf of the community Mark Rees implemented OpenID on PyPI at the sprint so things like &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opencomparison.org"&gt;http://opencomparison.org&lt;/a&gt; can support the community better. One goal at PyCon 2012 is to get that working as another authentication system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise I closed bugs and worked lintification of the project. Audrey and a couple Australian PyLadies, Elena Williams and Jenny Nguyen, worked some core Django documentation tickets. We didn't get as much done as we hoped thanks to an outside distraction, but the organization of the sprints was top-notch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the sprint, those crazy Australians taught us how to do a &lt;strong&gt;Tim Tam Slam&lt;/strong&gt;. It's rather scary and not for the faint of heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result: Great&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="overall-result"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overall Result&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conference was run professionally. The leadership was on the ball. The few issues that cropped up were taken care of, certainly better then what I would have done. Thank you everyone who put it together or just gave us a great time: Tim Ansell, Richard Jones, Nick Coghlan, Russell Keith McGee, Graham Dumpleton, Malcolm Tredennick and many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Australia was amazing. The people were wonderful. I wish we had more time to go sightseeing and relax, but we were off all too quickly. I could write a book about the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Combined Result: Great&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="audrey"></category><category term="australia"></category><category term="review"></category></entry><entry><title>Selected for PyCon StartUp Row</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/selected-for-pycon-startup-row.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-21T01:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2012-02-21:selected-for-pycon-startup-row.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Me and Audrey have been working hard on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://consumernotebook.com"&gt;Consumer Notebook&lt;/a&gt;, a Python/Django based project. We submitted it to PyCon StartUp row and found out this morning we've been accepted. &lt;strong&gt;Hooray!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pycon.blogspot.com/2012/02/startup-row-winners-for-pycon-2012.html"&gt;PyCon StartUp Row winner's post&lt;/a&gt;, here is a little bit of what we're about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="highlights"&gt;
Have you tried researching products online recently? Search engines are gamed by scammy marketers. Product review sites overwhelm you with ads, have unreliable reviews, or dryly compare raw product specs. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://consumernotebook.com"&gt;Consumer Notebook&lt;/a&gt; is working to solve this problem. It is like Yelp for products, with product comparison grids inspired by the founders' open-source work on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://djangopackages.com"&gt;Django Packages&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opencomparison.org"&gt;Open Comparison&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just so you know, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://us.pycon.org"&gt;PyCon&lt;/a&gt; in North America is the biggest gathering for the international Python community. The conference this year is in Santa Clara, California, and is sold-out at 1500+ attendees, but could have easily sold out several times that number. The talks, tutorials, and events are going to be incredible, and I'm delighted to be part of the PyCon experience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to sharing the StartUp Row with friends like Transifex, Python Packages, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.weddinglovely.com/"&gt;Wedding Lovely&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please check out &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://consumernotebook.com"&gt;Consumer Notebook&lt;/a&gt; right now and also visit our PyCon booth on Saturday, March 10th and we'll show you what we're doing.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="audrey"></category><category term="consumernotebook"></category><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>Two years ago today</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/two-years-ago-today.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-17T09:20:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2012-02-17:two-years-ago-today.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://us.pycon.org"&gt;PyCon&lt;/a&gt; tutorial on Django in Depth was ending. I had been sitting next to my friend &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://djangrrl.com/"&gt;Barbara&lt;/a&gt; and we got up to go when I heard a feminine voice ask: &amp;quot;Are you &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/bshaurette"&gt;bshaurette&lt;/a&gt;?&amp;quot; I turned and it was like I got punched in the gut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the first time I met &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey&lt;/a&gt;. I remember every detail of how she looked at that moment. The clothes she was wearing, the part in her hair, that her eyes met mine, and that they didn't turn away. I was immediately captivating, but fortunately remembered to act like a gentleman. I tossed in a casual invitation to her to join us for lunch, which I pulled off even though my heart was pounding. Thankfully she accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life has been pretty much awesome ever since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the day I met the love of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pycon"></category><category term="audrey"></category></entry></feed>