<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>pydanny</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pydanny.com/feeds/blog.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pydanny.com/</id><updated>2014-04-02T05:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Surgery in Two Days</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/surgery-in-two-days.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-04-02T05:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2014-04-02:surgery-in-two-days.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In two days, Friday, April 4th, I'm going into &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laparoscopic_surgery"&gt;laparoscopic surgery&lt;/a&gt; in order to correct a double inguinal hernia. If you want to know what that is, you can read the &lt;cite&gt;Not Safe For Work (NSFW) Wikipedia article&lt;/cite&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I said it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a hernia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's one thing to admit you are sick or have an injury, but it's another thing to admit you have a lower abdominal injury caused by lifting too much. Even if 27% of men get it in their lifetime, it's still hard to admit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-did-i-get-a-hernia"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How Did I Get A Hernia?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genetic predisposition, not to mention moving a refrigerator. And a sofa. And much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year in early April my wife and were given the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.com/off-to-europe.html"&gt;chance to work in Europe&lt;/a&gt; for a while. We moved out of our place and put all our stuff into storage. We don't have that much stuff, so we decided to do all the packing and moving ourselves. While I hadn't worked out consistently in a couple of months, I &lt;em&gt;knew&lt;/em&gt; I was up for any heavy lifting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, for all my adult life every once in a while I either moved or helped friends move their stuff. I'm in pretty good shape, have endurance, and know how to lift. I'm really flexible too, able to get low and push up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For several days Audrey and I packed and moved stuff into the storage facility. It was hard, sweaty work and we were racing to meet a deadline. I didn't mind the work or pace at all. For me it's fun to do hard labor for short periods and this was a blast. I also love pushing myself physically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had to move lots of stuff in a few days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stuff was not gym-style weights, but awkward boxes and furniture. Some of it heavy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Love to push myself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got it done just in time! Hooray! I was achey and sore, but really proud of what we did. Something didn't feel quite right &lt;em&gt;down there&lt;/em&gt;. I shrugged it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="something-is-wrong"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Something is Wrong&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the way to Europe I realized something was wrong. I thought it would go away, especially with good food and exercise. During the journey and once we arrived, I tried working out, but afterwards I would be in more discomfort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter. We worked long, hard hours and spent the weekends sightseeing. It was awesome. We met lots of our online friends. We attended amazing conferences and events. It was incredible, and I pray I get to do it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except that all that walking and standing ached. Over a few hours that ache would turn to pain. I thought it would go away, but it didn't. Over time it hurt more and more. Often, out with friends, I pleaded exhaustion. We kept going home early. Actually, I was just in a lot of pain that I didn't understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My pride meant I didn't want to admit I was hurt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="admitting-the-problem-and-diagnosis"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Admitting the Problem and Diagnosis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one of our last days in Zagreb, Croatia we took a very long walk. Far from our lodging the discomfort got so bad that I sat on the ground. Getting home was a nightmare. That was when we realized something was really wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to keep walking to a minimum after that. We readied for our next stop, the beachside city of Split in Croatia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we arrived in Split we did a little research and discovered that I probably had a hernia. We went to a physician, and he confirmed it. He had me see a surgeon, who confirmed it as well. While he suggested surgery, he also let us know that just then wasn't a good time - there was a threat of a nurses' strike in Croatia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to wait until we got back to the USA and the Affordable Care Act went into effect. I could wait that long if I was careful abut exercise and wore a brace. It sucked, because I would have to wait or pay completely out of pocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ugh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waiting was necessary because I didn't want to spend all my earnings for a time feeding the heartless American insurance bureaucracy industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as it was available we signed up for proper American medical coverage through the Affordable Care Act. I now have medical coverage! I went through the necessary appointments and was recommended the surgery that's going to happen in two days. The operation should take 90 minutes and I'm going home the same day. Two weeks after surgery I'll be feeling completely normal, and a month after surgery I can carefully restart my exercise regimen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="living-with-a-hernia"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Living With a Hernia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's doable but I don't recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I walk or exercise, then I have to wear a brace. That brace gets uncomfortable the longer I wear it, but it's better than the alternative. It's risky for me to max out my weights unless I'm on a machine. I can't do any direct abdominal exercises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without the brace I'm not supposed to lift anything heavier than 15 pounds. Ugh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-part-i-really-don-t-like"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Part I Really Don't Like&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm scared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logically I know it's a low risk operation done millions of times a year around the world. That my surgeon is rated extremely well. Still, it's me going under general anesthesia so a really nice lady can cut holes in me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I'm scared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try not to think about it, the same way I ignored the injury during most of my time in Europe. So far it's been working pretty well, except when I'm driving or trying to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pycon-in-montreal"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PyCon in Montreal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're not going. We weren't going because of finances, work, etc., but the scheduled surgery cemented it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="wish-me-luck"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wish Me Luck!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't wait for this to be done and finished. I want to be able to do things again. To walk and run for hours with no more discomfort than aching feet. To be able to pick things up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's going to be delightful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more thing: next time I'm hiring movers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="blog"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="surgery"></category></entry><entry><title>Two Scoops of Goblins</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/two-scoops-of-goblins.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-04-01T05:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2014-04-01:two-scoops-of-goblins.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;While &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreyr.com/"&gt;Audrey Roy Greenfeld&lt;/a&gt; and I were contemplating our next Two Scoops Press book topic, it came down to a decision between Pyramid, Flask, and mythical creatures. Inspired by Django's magical flying pony, Pyramid's scary alien dude, and even the idea of a magical Flask pouring out wonderful projects, we've decided to go with mythical creatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, we're writing about goblins, hence the title of this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What that means is that the next book we publish will be fantasy. Going forward all the books we write will be fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we ever write a new &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://twoscoopspress.com/products/two-scoops-of-django-1-6"&gt;Two Scoops of Django&lt;/a&gt; book, it will be a fantasy about a magical flying pony who eats ice cream. That way we'll confuse the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/s/ref=nb_sb_noss_2?url=search-alias%3Daps&amp;amp;field-keywords=django&amp;amp;tag=mlinar-20"&gt;already muddled Amazon.com search requests for 'Django'&lt;/a&gt; even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this is a technical blog, I'll be moving my fiction writing based articles to my author blog at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.danielroygreenfeld.com"&gt;danielroygreenfeld.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://www.danielroygreenfeld.com"&gt;&lt;img alt="https://s3.amazonaws.com/pydanny/two-scoops-of-goblins.png" class="align-center" id="two-scoops-of-goblins-cover" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/pydanny/two-scoops-of-goblins.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="blog"></category><category term="book"></category><category term="twoscoops"></category></entry><entry><title>Developer Time</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/developer-time.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-04T12:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2012-12-04:developer-time.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This blog post got started with a tweet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That tweet got retweeted a lot by developers. And system administrators. And database administrators. And any creative type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of December 7th, 2012, it had been retweeted over 500 times, a personal best. Obviously I struck a chord that resonated with a lot of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developers should have 4-6 hours of uninterrupted activity each day. Each 3-5 minute interruption costs more than you can imagine.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Daniel Greenfeld (@pydanny) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/pydanny/status/275680738773463040" data-datetime="2012-12-03T19:19:44+00:00"&gt;December 3, 2012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script src="http://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;div class="section" id="why-did-this-tweet-resonate-with-so-many-people"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why did this tweet resonate with so many people?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I said in that tweet was not new - dozens if not hundreds of others have tweeted similar thoughts before and gotten many retweets. Heck, it's been written about in blogs and articles for years, either as a huge rant or often as an effort to politely educate others on how to set up a developer/operations/creative shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this is because developers/engineers/creatives (and good managers) know that even a tiny distraction to someone &amp;quot;in the zone&amp;quot; takes more than just the 3-5 minutes it takes for you to finish a question and get an answer. Plus, because you are trying to remember the pieces in your head, you won't be able to give this issue your full attention. Which causes a whole other set of issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know this. Good managers know this. Good companies live off of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet this remains a huge problem for many of us because the distractions keep happening. Maybe it's because your manager doesn't understand this issue, or you have a team mate who can switch in-and-out of the zone with impunity. Or because you foolishly leave the chat/IRC/phone on and you get pinged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-do-we-fix-it"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How do we fix it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We can't.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this sounds depressing, but I'm being realistic. Here's some reasons that apply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unless you are fortunate enough to be working on a solo effort, you are working with other developers/engineers/creatives. And if they can't ask you questions or inform you about critical stuff then you or they can waste hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meetings, short or long, online or in person, are a necessary part of any operation. If not with your boss or underlings, then with clients or users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your boss/co-workers/underlings/kids/pets/parents don't get it that you can't be interrupted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a freelancer, you can't be inaccessible to existing or potential clients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="no-really-how-do-we-fix-it"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;No really, how do we fix it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doesn't matter how frequently you ask the the question (or rant about it), I don't believe this problem can be really solved. However, here are some possible mitigations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Maker's Day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://craigkerstiens.com/2011/11/07/how-heroku-works-maker-day/"&gt;Craig Kerstiens&lt;/a&gt; describes how &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://heroku.com"&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt; gives engineers a full day each week (Thursday) to focus on getting stuff done. No meetings, no standup, just 100% uninterrupted quiet time to focus on making stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suggest this at your company and see how it goes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Blocks of Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of 2010, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://eldarion.com"&gt;Eldarion&lt;/a&gt; broke up their work day into at least two sizable chunks of uninterrupted activity. Between the chunks you communicated with co-workers. The advantage of this approach is if you went down the wrong path or someone had a critical question, the period between chunks addressed this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In theory this is how a lot of places work (lunch being the break). The reality is that the distractions often still pile in. For Eldarion it worked because everyone was remote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. New Desk Location&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If working at an office, asked to be moved to a place with less foot traffic. The downside to this is you can end up in noisy, cold, dark places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. New Job&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Switch to a new job that promises less distractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="maybe-i-m-wrong"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Maybe I'm wrong&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm more than happy to be proven wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe there is a way to get 4-6 hours a day of uninterrupted maker's time every work day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've got any ideas, let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="rant"></category><category term="blog"></category></entry><entry><title>Thoughts on ranting</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/thoughts-on-ranting.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-11-26T16:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2012-11-26:thoughts-on-ranting.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'll admit it, I love a good rant. I respect those who can give rants well. I would list the ones I really like, but I'm not sure I want to deal with the arguments that would follow. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, as much as I like to read or listen to them, I also like to give them. As of 11/26/2012 there are 2 on this &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.com/tag/rant.html"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; and 26 on my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.blogspot.com/search/label/rant"&gt;old blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I have a problem in giving rants. It ties with this unfortunate trait I possess where if I let myself get angry I say things that destroy relationships. No, I'm not giving examples, but there you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when I do rant, I try to never do so in anger. Especially when it's the written word. Instead, I try to do so under one of the following conditions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I need to be a whimsical mood.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OR I need to be willing to submit a solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OR I need to be willing to accept a solution, even if it means work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OR I need to be willing to create a solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OR the object of the rant must be an easy target to flame.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="blog"></category><category term="rant"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="friends"></category></entry><entry><title>Choosing a new python based blog engine</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/choosing-a-new-python-based-blog-engine.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-04-05T12:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2012-04-05:choosing-a-new-python-based-blog-engine.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="why-a-new-blog-engine"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why a new blog engine?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.blogspot.com/"&gt;old blog&lt;/a&gt;, I had been having issues with Blogger for some time.  The WYSIWYG text editor was annoying in that it produced wonky HTML, so I had to hand craft the posts. Which meant I often wrote the HTML formatted copy in a text editor and then copy/pasted it into the browser. A few times this blew up and I really wished I had version controlled back ups. Adding code examples was problematic, even with a stylesheet helpfully provided by Google. Finally, some of the changes to the blog engine itself were beginning to worry me, so I started looking for alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my fiancee, Audrey Roy, converted her blog to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll"&gt;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&lt;/a&gt; at it's new location of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;audreymroy.com&lt;/a&gt;, the static file hosting seemed so awesome I was impressed enough to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.com/tried-out-jekyll.html"&gt;give Jekyll a try&lt;/a&gt;. Why did Jekyll and static file hosting interest me so much?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-don-t-want-to-maintain-my-own-server"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;I don't want to maintain my own server&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple times I rolled out a blog on a site I stood up, but didn't really feel like maintaining a site. I want someone else to do it. When I write, I want someone else to worry about the details. I want to focus on writing and nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well... almost nothing else. You'll understand shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-want-to-be-able-to-write-without-connection"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;I want to be able to write without connection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With blogger, I needed an internet connection to get my blog posts to format correctly. With Jekyll and other static file systems, I can just type away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-want-to-publish-via-git"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;I want to publish via git&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny-event-notes.rtfd.org"&gt;http://pydanny-event-notes.rtfd.org&lt;/a&gt; has really exploded in my own usage and continued because it uses the same patterns I use in software development. I'm used to the pattern of using Git to push up content, so why use naked HTML? Sure, there are RST-to-HTML processors that I could use to generate that HTML, but they always require some amount of manual correction. Jekyll, and it's alternatives, let me just write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="jekyll-wasn-t-for-me"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Jekyll wasn't for me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found Jekyll to be good and much more fun than Blogger, but not good enough. To sum up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I prefer RestructuredText over Markdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don't know enough Ruby to easily customize things. I don't feel like diving into Ruby just to learn how to make modifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The template engine was like Smarty/Django/Jinja2, but not as much fun. Debugging errors was very problematic. Which was a problem when I started to play with modifying the theme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the second and third bullets, you might wonder why I would care about the underlying engine if all I wanted to do was write. Well, I'm well aware of the fact that I change opinions now and then.  :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was after trying out Jekyll that I started looking for &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://python.org"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; based static file blog systems. The choices that seemed appropriate were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="blogofile"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.blogofile.com/"&gt;blogofile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably the most mature, most common Python static file generator around. It looks really awesome, and everyone who uses it swears by it. Alas, it's powered by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.makotemplates.org/"&gt;Mako&lt;/a&gt; templates, which is... um... &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.blogspot.com/2010/12/stupid-template-languages.html"&gt;not my friend&lt;/a&gt; (apologies to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://techspot.zzzeek.org/2010/12/04/in-response-to-stupid-template-languages/"&gt;Mike Bayer&lt;/a&gt;). What I really wanted was something with templates powered by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pocoo.org/projects/jinja2/"&gt;Jinja2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="hyde"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hyde.github.com/"&gt;hyde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyde claims to have started as Jekyll's evil Python twin. On the surface it looks awesome. Where it fails is documentation. There are lots of wonderful features that appear to exist, but follow the links to those features and you find yourself on placeholder pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In theory, I could have just looked at the hyde code and figured out stuff myself. Maybe even document out the holes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In practice, all I want to do is write blog posts. It's one thing to customize things to suit your needs, it's another thing to make things work. Or document a tool. Color me lazy if you will, but when it comes to blogging, that's just how I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think in the near future, once fully documented, Hyde is going to be AWESOME. For now? Well, I wanted another option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pelican"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pelican.readthedocs.org/"&gt;pelican&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was immediately hooked. Python powered engine with Jinja2 templates with &lt;strong&gt;complete documentation&lt;/strong&gt;. In fact, every time I asked the author for help, he resignedly pointed me at the documentation. How cool is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point I'll use the &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;CSS&lt;/tt&gt; setting to change the color of &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;pygments&lt;/tt&gt; to something with white background and black text. For now I'm happy as things are now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/77704901&amp;#64;N05/6831339872/"&gt;&lt;img alt="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7043/6831339872_10d0c40171.jpg" class="align-center" id="pycon-cartwheel-with-glass" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7043/6831339872_10d0c40171.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=3804553"&gt;Discuss this post on Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="blog"></category></entry><entry><title>My new blog</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/my-new-blog.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-17T00:30:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2012-02-17:my-new-blog.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What I did to get it running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
pip install pelican
git clone git://github.com/pydanny/pydanny.github.com.git
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My settings.py file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
AUTHOR = 'Daniel Greenfeld'
DISQUS_SITENAME = 'pydanny'
GITHUB_URL = 'https://github.com/pydanny'
GOOGLE_ANALYTICS='UA-18066389-2'
SITEURL = 'http://pydanny.github.com'
SITENAME = 'pydanny'
SOCIAL = (('twitter', 'http://twitter.com/pydanny'),
          ('github', 'https://github.com/pydanny'),
          ('facebook', 'http://www.facebook.com/daniel.greenfeld'),)
TAG_FEED = 'feeds/%s.atom.xml'
THEME='notmyidea'
TWITTER_USERNAME = 'pydanny'
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How I push up entries and pages and themes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
pelican . -o . -s settings.py
git commit -am &amp;quot;blogging here&amp;quot;
git push
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="results"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Results!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.github.com"&gt;http://pydanny.github.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="blog"></category></entry><entry><title>Tried out Jekyll</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/tried-out-jekyll.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-09T10:20:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2012-02-09:tried-out-jekyll.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="why-jekyll"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why Jekyll?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've had issues with Blogger for some time.  After my fiancee, Audrey Roy, moved her blog to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll"&gt;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, I was impressed enough to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did it impress me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="code-highlighting-made-easy"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Code highlighting made easy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't have to hand-craft HTML code to get google prettify in a post. I just stick in a simple macro of 'highlight python' called like a Django templatetag and I get:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;Daniel Greenfeld&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;letter&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;split&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;():&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;letter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This issue alone sums up why I don't do more blog posts with code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-don-t-want-to-maintain-my-own-blog-site"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I don't want to maintain my own blog site&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple times I rolled out a blog on a site I stood up, but didn't really feel like maintaining a site. I want someone else to do it. When I write, I want someone else to worry about the details. I want to focus on writing and nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-want-to-be-able-to-write-without-connection"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I want to be able to write without connection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need an internet connection to get my blogger posts to format right. With Jekyll, I can just type away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ability-to-publish-via-git"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ability to publish via git&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny-event-notes.rtfd.org"&gt;http://pydanny-event-notes.rtfd.org&lt;/a&gt; has really exploded in my own usage and continued because it uses the same patterns I use in software development. I'm used to the pattern of using Git to push up content, so why use naked HTML? Sure, there are RST-to-HTML processors that I could use to generate that HTML, but they always require an some amount of manual correction. Jekyll, and it's alternatives,let me just write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="why-not-jekyll"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why not Jekyll?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is written in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ruby-lang.org"&gt;ruby&lt;/a&gt;. Nothing against ruby, but I can't trivially work in that language the way I can in Python. It's good to eat your own dogfood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I started looking at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hyde.github.com/"&gt;hyde&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blogofile.com/"&gt;blogofile&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pelican.readthedocs.org/"&gt;pelican&lt;/a&gt; as alternatives. More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="ruby"></category><category term="blog"></category></entry></feed>