<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>pydanny - blog</title><link href="https://pydanny.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pydanny.com/feeds/blog.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pydanny.com/</id><updated>2014-12-20T12:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>I did an Aú Batido in 2014, now what?</title><link href="https://pydanny.com/new-years-resolutions-2015.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-12-20T12:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2014-12-20T12:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2014-12-20:/new-years-resolutions-2015.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my summary of my &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.pydanny.com/tag/resolutions.html"&gt;resolutions&lt;/a&gt; for 2014 and an early pass at my resolutions for 2015. I'm doing this right now instead of at the end of the year because as of the afternoon of December 21, I'm &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://danielroygreenfeld.com/2014/12/21/going-off-the-grid/"&gt;going off the grid&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="resolutions-accomplished-in-2014"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resolutions Accomplished in 2014&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Release the …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my summary of my &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.pydanny.com/tag/resolutions.html"&gt;resolutions&lt;/a&gt; for 2014 and an early pass at my resolutions for 2015. I'm doing this right now instead of at the end of the year because as of the afternoon of December 21, I'm &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://danielroygreenfeld.com/2014/12/21/going-off-the-grid/"&gt;going off the grid&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="resolutions-accomplished-in-2014"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resolutions Accomplished in 2014&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Release the second edition of Two Scoops of Django.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visited South America.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visited two new nations, Argentina and Brazil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Went back to the East Coast to visit Philadelphia and places in New Jersey.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Went back to the Philippines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Took some awesome road trips around the USA. My favorite was driving up the Pacific Coast Highway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Took a fun class with Audrey. We did woodshop!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learned how to do &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/L-kick"&gt;Aú Batido&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="https://pydanny.com/static/aubatido.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="align-center" id="au-batido" src="https://pydanny.com/static/aubatido.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="general-accomplishments"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;General Accomplishments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Published Two Scoops of Django 1.6 with my awesome wife, Audrey Roy Greenfeld.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experienced my first major surgery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started working at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.eventbrite.com"&gt;Eventbrite&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Found a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.meetup.com/Riverside-Capoeira-Meetup/"&gt;Inland Empire Capoeira group&lt;/a&gt; but still remained friends with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/valleycapoeirabatuque"&gt;Capoeira Batuque&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gave talks at:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wharton School of Business Web Conference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PyDay Mendoza&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python Brazil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PyCon Argentina&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experienced the unbelievably tasty asado (steak) of Argentina.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participated in organizing the first Django Bar Camp.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Played in 2 Capoeira Rodas in Brazil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participated in the successful effort to reboot &lt;a class="reference external" href="www.meetup.com/ladjango"&gt;LA Django&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ate dinner below the waterline inside &lt;a class="reference external" href="www.forbesisland.com"&gt;fake island in the San Francisco Bay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="resolutions-for-2015"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resolutions for 2015&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bring a new child into the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write and publish at least 1 fiction book. This is a childhood dream that I would like to make reality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn Swift or some other interesting programming language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find sponsors for my open source projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit the two continents I've yet to see. That means Africa and Antarctica.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See the Grand Canyon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit more family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do 1000 push-ups or similar exercises in a single day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pull off an Aú sem Mão (no-handed cartwheel).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take another fun class with Audrey.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how to surf or snowboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See all my friends. All of them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enjoy life with Audrey more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="holidays"></category><category term="resolutions"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="friends"></category><category term="capoeira"></category><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>Building, Maintaining and Scaling Projects</title><link href="https://pydanny.com/building-maintaining-scaling-projects.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-15T14:30:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-07-15T14:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2014-07-15:/building-maintaining-scaling-projects.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;These are the slides from the talk I gave today at the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.sas.upenn.edu/wwc/"&gt;Wharton Web Conference&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/37009740" width="427" height="356" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" style="border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px 1px 0; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;" allowfullscreen&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;div style="margin-bottom:5px"&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.slideshare.net/pydanny/building-maintainableprojectswharton" title="From NASA to Startups to Big Commerce" target="_blank"&gt;From NASA to Startups to Big Commerce&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.slideshare.net/pydanny" target="_blank"&gt;Daniel Greenfeld&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;These are the slides from the talk I gave today at the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.sas.upenn.edu/wwc/"&gt;Wharton Web Conference&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/37009740" width="427" height="356" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" style="border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px 1px 0; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;" allowfullscreen&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;div style="margin-bottom:5px"&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.slideshare.net/pydanny/building-maintainableprojectswharton" title="From NASA to Startups to Big Commerce" target="_blank"&gt;From NASA to Startups to Big Commerce&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.slideshare.net/pydanny" target="_blank"&gt;Daniel Greenfeld&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="nasa"></category><category term="WhartonWC"></category></entry><entry><title>Surgery in Two Days</title><link href="https://pydanny.com/surgery-in-two-days.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-04-02T05:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-04-02T05:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2014-04-02:/surgery-in-two-days.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In two days, Friday, April 4th, I'm going into &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laparoscopic_surgery"&gt;laparoscopic surgery&lt;/a&gt; in order to correct a double inguinal hernia. If you want to know what that is, you can read the &lt;cite&gt;Not Safe For Work (NSFW) Wikipedia article&lt;/cite&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I said it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a hernia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's one …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In two days, Friday, April 4th, I'm going into &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laparoscopic_surgery"&gt;laparoscopic surgery&lt;/a&gt; in order to correct a double inguinal hernia. If you want to know what that is, you can read the &lt;cite&gt;Not Safe For Work (NSFW) Wikipedia article&lt;/cite&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I said it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a hernia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's one thing to admit you are sick or have an injury, but it's another thing to admit you have a lower abdominal injury caused by lifting too much. Even if 27% of men get it in their lifetime, it's still hard to admit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-did-i-get-a-hernia"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How Did I Get A Hernia?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genetic predisposition, not to mention moving a refrigerator. And a sofa. And much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year in early April my wife and were given the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pydanny.com/off-to-europe.html"&gt;chance to work in Europe&lt;/a&gt; for a while. We moved out of our place and put all our stuff into storage. We don't have that much stuff, so we decided to do all the packing and moving ourselves. While I hadn't worked out consistently in a couple of months, I &lt;em&gt;knew&lt;/em&gt; I was up for any heavy lifting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, for all my adult life every once in a while I either moved or helped friends move their stuff. I'm in pretty good shape, have endurance, and know how to lift. I'm really flexible too, able to get low and push up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For several days Audrey and I packed and moved stuff into the storage facility. It was hard, sweaty work and we were racing to meet a deadline. I didn't mind the work or pace at all. For me it's fun to do hard labor for short periods and this was a blast. I also love pushing myself physically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had to move lots of stuff in a few days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stuff was not gym-style weights, but awkward boxes and furniture. Some of it heavy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Love to push myself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got it done just in time! Hooray! I was achey and sore, but really proud of what we did. Something didn't feel quite right &lt;em&gt;down there&lt;/em&gt;. I shrugged it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="something-is-wrong"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Something is Wrong&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the way to Europe I realized something was wrong. I thought it would go away, especially with good food and exercise. During the journey and once we arrived, I tried working out, but afterwards I would be in more discomfort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter. We worked long, hard hours and spent the weekends sightseeing. It was awesome. We met lots of our online friends. We attended amazing conferences and events. It was incredible, and I pray I get to do it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except that all that walking and standing ached. Over a few hours that ache would turn to pain. I thought it would go away, but it didn't. Over time it hurt more and more. Often, out with friends, I pleaded exhaustion. We kept going home early. Actually, I was just in a lot of pain that I didn't understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My pride meant I didn't want to admit I was hurt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="admitting-the-problem-and-diagnosis"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Admitting the Problem and Diagnosis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one of our last days in Zagreb, Croatia we took a very long walk. Far from our lodging the discomfort got so bad that I sat on the ground. Getting home was a nightmare. That was when we realized something was really wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to keep walking to a minimum after that. We readied for our next stop, the beachside city of Split in Croatia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we arrived in Split we did a little research and discovered that I probably had a hernia. We went to a physician, and he confirmed it. He had me see a surgeon, who confirmed it as well. While he suggested surgery, he also let us know that just then wasn't a good time - there was a threat of a nurses' strike in Croatia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to wait until we got back to the USA and the Affordable Care Act went into effect. I could wait that long if I was careful abut exercise and wore a brace. It sucked, because I would have to wait or pay completely out of pocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ugh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waiting was necessary because I didn't want to spend all my earnings for a time feeding the heartless American insurance bureaucracy industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as it was available we signed up for proper American medical coverage through the Affordable Care Act. I now have medical coverage! I went through the necessary appointments and was recommended the surgery that's going to happen in two days. The operation should take 90 minutes and I'm going home the same day. Two weeks after surgery I'll be feeling completely normal, and a month after surgery I can carefully restart my exercise regimen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="living-with-a-hernia"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Living With a Hernia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's doable but I don't recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I walk or exercise, then I have to wear a brace. That brace gets uncomfortable the longer I wear it, but it's better than the alternative. It's risky for me to max out my weights unless I'm on a machine. I can't do any direct abdominal exercises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without the brace I'm not supposed to lift anything heavier than 15 pounds. Ugh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-part-i-really-don-t-like"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Part I Really Don't Like&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm scared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logically I know it's a low risk operation done millions of times a year around the world. That my surgeon is rated extremely well. Still, it's me going under general anesthesia so a really nice lady can cut holes in me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I'm scared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try not to think about it, the same way I ignored the injury during most of my time in Europe. So far it's been working pretty well, except when I'm driving or trying to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pycon-in-montreal"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PyCon in Montreal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're not going. We weren't going because of finances, work, etc., but the scheduled surgery cemented it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="wish-me-luck"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wish Me Luck!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't wait for this to be done and finished. I want to be able to do things again. To walk and run for hours with no more discomfort than aching feet. To be able to pick things up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's going to be delightful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more thing: next time I'm hiring movers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="blog"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="surgery"></category></entry><entry><title>Memories of Malcolm</title><link href="https://pydanny.com/memories-of-malcolm.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-03-17T12:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-03-17T12:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2014-03-17:/memories-of-malcolm.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A year ago today &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://about.me/malcolmt"&gt;Malcolm Tredinnick&lt;/a&gt;, core contributor to Django suddenly passed away. He was a mentor, and more importantly, a good friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of my memories of Malcolm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="djangocon-us-september-2010"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;DjangoCon US: September 2010&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where Audrey and I first met Malcolm. We ended up spending a good …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A year ago today &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://about.me/malcolmt"&gt;Malcolm Tredinnick&lt;/a&gt;, core contributor to Django suddenly passed away. He was a mentor, and more importantly, a good friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of my memories of Malcolm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="djangocon-us-september-2010"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;DjangoCon US: September 2010&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where Audrey and I first met Malcolm. We ended up spending a good amount of the conference with him just hanging out and having a good time. I remember being honored that such a luminary wanted to spend time with us, yet was more delighted in discovering a good friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the conference, he peered into the nascent code base of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.djangopackages.com"&gt;djangopackages.com&lt;/a&gt; and asked some pointed questions. We justified a few design decisions, and he agreed, and we saw him using similar techniques later. He gave us some great pointers on things we could do, and I believe we implemented all of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="summer-to-autumn-of-2010"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summer to Autumn of 2010&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Malcolm and I worked together on a project in 2010. During this time we had a number of email and chat discussions. Going over them now I'm impressed by his friendship and generosity of knowledge. I know he was terribly busy but yet he always had time for me in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After about 15 emails where I addressed him as 'Malcom', Malcolm finally got me to consistently spell his name correctly with a single sentence:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might be amazed at how cranky it makes me when people try to spell Malcolm with only one &amp;quot;l&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was Malcolm: Acerbic yet tempered with a smile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pycon-australia-august-2011"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PyCon Australia: August 2011&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had just arrived in Sydney. Our first overseas trip together! Audrey was giving the opening keynote at PyCon Australia. She wanted to practice her speech but I was restless. So she suggested that I go out for dinner, specifically sushi train with Malcolm Tredinnick and Russell Keith-Magee. I don't remember anything about the food, but I do remember having a great time with good friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the conference one evening Audrey and I spent a few hours with just Malcolm walking around Sydney. None of us wanted it to end. The time spent together outside of the insane pace of a conference was a poignant reminder that even with email, chat, and IRC, there was still thousands of miles between us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pycon-philippines-june-2012"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PyCon Philippines: June 2012&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On his own dollar, Malcolm had dropped everything to attend. He spoke, he taught, and he made many friends. I have to admit being jealous of the students in the Django tutorial he taught because they got to spend time with him. ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was our last time with Malcolm, and it was so brief, so limited. I was okay with that because I thought I would get a chance to see him again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="two-scoops-of-django-october-2012-january-2013"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Two Scoops of Django: October 2012-January 2013&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you read the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://twoscoopspress.com/pages/malcolm-tredinnick-memorial"&gt;memorial&lt;/a&gt; we wrote for Malcolm, you can see that his presence is an integral part of Two Scoops of Django. He coached us, guided us, forced us to dig deeper and deeper into source code. Of special note is the database chapter (excluding the 1.6 edition transactions), which he really focused on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="today-march-17th-2014"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Today: March 17th, 2014&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Matt Croydon says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Celebrate the life of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/malcolmt"&gt;@malcolmt&lt;/a&gt; today: be nice to someone, help someone learn something, and push some code. Tomorrow: repeat.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Matt Croydon (@mc) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mc/statuses/314013575406571520"&gt;March 19, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="djangocon"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="book"></category><category term="australia"></category><category term="twoscoops"></category></entry><entry><title>New Year's Resolutions for 2014</title><link href="https://pydanny.com/new-years-resolutions-for-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-01-01T12:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2014-01-01T12:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2014-01-01:/new-years-resolutions-for-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Making New Year's Resolutions is something I do every year. It's important to me. I like to set goals and see how well I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="resolutions"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resolutions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write and publish fiction. This is a childhood dream that I would like to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write and publish as least one new technical book …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Making New Year's Resolutions is something I do every year. It's important to me. I like to set goals and see how well I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="resolutions"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resolutions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write and publish fiction. This is a childhood dream that I would like to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write and publish as least one new technical book, preferably on Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn Haskell or some other interesting programming language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Figure out a way I can make money working in open source efforts. As a consultant, this explains why I don't do it more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit the two continents I've yet to see. That means Africa and Antarctica.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See the Grand Canyon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit more family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do 1000 push-ups or similar exercises in a single day. I'm at 300 now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pull off an Aú sem Mão (no-handed cartwheel).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blog once a week. That is at least 52 blog entries!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a fun class with Audrey.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload all my outstanding pictures to Flickr!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how to surf or snowboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See all my friends. All of them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work less and enjoy life with Audrey more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="accomplished"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Accomplished&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Release the second edition of Two Scoops of Django.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visited South Africa (Argentina and Brazil!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visited two new nations, Argentina and Brazil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Went back to the East Coast to visit Philadelphia and places in New Jersey.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Went back to the Philippines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Took some awesome road trips around the USA. My favorite was driving up the Pacific Coast highway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pulled of an Aú Batido&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Took a fun class with Audrey. We did woodshop!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="holidays"></category><category term="resolutions"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="friends"></category><category term="capoeira"></category><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>Dynów 2013 Part I</title><link href="https://pydanny.com/dynow-2013-part-i.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-09-09T12:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2013-09-09T12:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2013-09-09:/dynow-2013-part-i.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;note&lt;/strong&gt;: This is the first part in a series about a family research trip to Dynów, Poland in May 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was our second trip to Poland. Last year (2012) I went with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey&lt;/a&gt; in 2012 for a few days to present at a software conference called &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pl.pycon.org/"&gt;PyCon Poland&lt;/a&gt;. We …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;note&lt;/strong&gt;: This is the first part in a series about a family research trip to Dynów, Poland in May 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was our second trip to Poland. Last year (2012) I went with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey&lt;/a&gt; in 2012 for a few days to present at a software conference called &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pl.pycon.org/"&gt;PyCon Poland&lt;/a&gt;. We stayed for a few days afterwards in the eerily familiar Krakow, always conscious that my family heritage was perhaps just hours away. You see, my mother and father's family come from Jews who emigrated to the USA respectively about 110 and 90 years ago. Unfortunately, for many reasons boiling down to time, resources, and contacts I held off from exploring my family roots, promising myself I would return one day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I was back in Poland, with both the time, resources, and contacts to make it possible to explore at least a portion of my family roots. This year I would get to research and visit where my grand-father's roots in south-eastern Poland. We blocked out some time, made various reservations, talked to family members such as my mother and Aunt Bernice (who &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kehilalinks.jewishgen.org/krosno/Krosnodubtrip.htm"&gt;wrote about her trip in 2006&lt;/a&gt;), and leaned heavily on the graces of close friends Tomasz 'Tomek' Paczkowski and Alexandra 'Ola' Sendecka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We knew we were in for an uphill battle researching the family. You can't just go to a computer and search. In fact, as of the summer of 2013 there isn't really a central database of information for Jewish ancestry - what exists is still under construction and rather incomplete. That means you have to go and look at old documents yourself, which are incomplete and hard to find. You see, over the decades various documents have been destroyed by accident or war, meaning that the old property/census/tax documents are either incomplete or broken up into parts seperated by hours of travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting to Dynów was a matter of renting a car and having Tomasz drive us from Krakow. Most of it was on a pretty new highway and we zipped along at a rapid pace. Once we got to Rzeszow and the highway ended, we were on the winding country roads that make up most of Poland. While unbelievably scenic, the country roads make Poland feel much larger than it seems; explaining why we would not be able to accomodate the requests from various family members and friends in the USA to visit the villages of their ancestors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More about the trip is forthcoming later in the series. In the meantime, here are some things still being edited:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/pydanny/sets/72157635453007448/"&gt;Photos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/pydanny/dynow-trip-2013"&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content><category term="europe"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="travel tips for geeks"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="friends"></category><category term="audrey"></category></entry><entry><title>Travel Tips for Geeks: Traveling Cheaply</title><link href="https://pydanny.com/travel-tips-for-geeks-living-cheaply.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-08-05T14:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2013-08-05T14:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2013-08-05:/travel-tips-for-geeks-living-cheaply.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's a given that in order to travel you need to have money or make a lot of money, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's not really true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are ways to live well but cheaply. It takes a bit of discipline, forethought, and judgement, but the reward of living is amazing. This article …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's a given that in order to travel you need to have money or make a lot of money, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's not really true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are ways to live well but cheaply. It takes a bit of discipline, forethought, and judgement, but the reward of living is amazing. This article explains how &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey Roy&lt;/a&gt; and I do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pick-the-right-location"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pick the Right Location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of famous destination cities are expensive no matter what you do. San Francisco, New York, London, Paris, Berlin, Rome, and Tokyo might be wonderful, but they are also places where you have to pay more. More for everything. Rent, food, and accessory costs are likely to be at least double what you expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, certain entire countries are expensive. Switzerland, Slovenia, Australia, and New Zealand are lovely, but everything just costs more there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, if the transit system is good, consider staying a little further from the expensive downtown or waterfront. This can make even expensive cities affordable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affordable places we've discovered this year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Barcelona, Spain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bologna, Italy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Florence, Italy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Krakow, Poland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Islands near Split, Croatia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Warsaw, Poland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zagreb, Croatia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of our resource is &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Worlds-Cheapest-Destinations-Countries-ebook/dp/B00AYIBO1M/ref=tmm_kin_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;sr=&amp;amp;tag=mlinar-20"&gt;The World's Cheapest Destinations&lt;/a&gt;, which, if nothing else, is an interesting read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="use-a-service-to-find-a-place-and-stay-a-while"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Use a service to find a place and stay a while&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use a service like &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.airbnb.com"&gt;airbnb&lt;/a&gt; or the local equivalent to find a place. Some people like to just stay at hostels, we prefer apartments. Stay for a month so you get a lower rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try to research the nearby grocery shopping. While little stores are wonderful, they cost more than a large supermarket. The supermarket will allow you to stay cheaply in an area. However, make sure to check out the little markets at least once a week because the food there is often much, much better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our two constant requirements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WiFi (we work remotely)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Washing machine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="if-you-work-remotely"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;If you work remotely&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're fortunate in that our work lets us work remotely. Keep in mind the two cardinal rules:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be available in real-time:&lt;/strong&gt; Use Google Hangouts, Chat, IRC or whatever at regular times to demonstrate you are working.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get your work done on time:&lt;/strong&gt;  If you are working remotely while traveling, you have to demonstrate to the client/boss that the travel isn't a distraction. If you seem flakey, they'll seriously consider other options besides you. Honestly, who can blame them?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="try-to-cook-and-eat-at-home"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Try to Cook and Eat at Home&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our rule is we eat out once a week. Otherwise, it's all home cooking. Even when we do tourist things on our day off, we bring food from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the ingredients are always different. Fruits, vegetables, and meats are grown in different soils and climates and taste different. This means don't try and replicate what you eat at home, cook simple things they make where you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="finding-good-affordable-restaurants"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Finding Good, Affordable Restaurants&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding good, affordable restaurants is easy. Here are our steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find a place that looks busy.&lt;/strong&gt; A busy place means the food is palatable and because of volume, the food is fresh. If the place is empty, walk away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check the menu for prices.&lt;/strong&gt; If they make you flinch, walk away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen to what people are saying.&lt;/strong&gt; If it's in your version of your language, walk away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you stay, keep in mind local portion sizes. For example, in slavic countries like Poland and Croatia, the portions can be quite large. What we sometimes do is share a main course and use the savings to buy drinks or dessert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like beer, try to order local varieties of beer. They often sell for less and can be really tasty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like wine, the rule goes like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the USA, order the cheapest non-house wine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Europe, order the house wine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-else"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Else?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be updating this article in the days and months and hopefully years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="travel"></category><category term="travel tips for geeks"></category></entry><entry><title>Travel Tips for Geeks: Preventing Theft</title><link href="https://pydanny.com/travel-tips-for-geeks-preventing-theft.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-18T16:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2013-07-18T16:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2013-07-18:/travel-tips-for-geeks-preventing-theft.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the first in a set of blog posts based on my experiences traveling in various places around the world. This particular safety-related post is about theft, not scams, which I may cover in another article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this first article, I'm hoping this gets on various technical RSS feeds …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the first in a set of blog posts based on my experiences traveling in various places around the world. This particular safety-related post is about theft, not scams, which I may cover in another article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this first article, I'm hoping this gets on various technical RSS feeds. I'm doing this because many of the readers of such feeds attend conferences and are strangers in far and distant places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="about-thieves"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About Thieves&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thieves (or pick pockets) are everywhere. I've seen extremely suspicious activity in Portland, Los Angeles, Washington DC, Barcelona, Florence, Pisa, and Krakow. Years ago in Washington DC I had stuff stolen from me twice so I've been observant and careful ever since. Anywhere there are non-residents distracted by looking at new vistas while suffering from travel fatigue is where most thieves can be found. I've learned a lot by observation and doing research but I don't claim to be an expert. All I claim to be is someone who doesn't want to be ripped off far from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-basics-any-place-with-tourists-is-risky"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Basics: Any place with tourists is risky&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it can be said that thieves can be anywhere, the truth is that they focus on where the tourists go. We carry money and expensive things, are tired, distracted, and don't know our way around. For a thief, A moment of risk can yield hundreds or thousands of dollars of profit from a traveler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-ve-never-had-any-problems-there"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&amp;quot;I've never had any problems there&amp;quot;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've heard this several times from local residents or travelers, often about places with statistically high crime rates. You'll hear it too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that means is that they've either been lucky or unobservant. It's better to avoid a miserable trip by being a least a little careful with your identity, money, and electronics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="listen-to-warnings-before-you-go-places"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Listen to warnings before you go places&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Barcelona our host warned us about La Rambla, a tourist-heavy street that's notoriously thick with thieves. While we're always careful, we were especially observant there, and enjoyed the very lovely and friendly downtown Barcelona without incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversely, don't pay attention to warnings at locations. Public notices about thieves are a nasty trap. When you see them you check your most expensive things, giving away the location of money, jewelry, watches, and cell phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="watch-how-local-residents-protect-themselves"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Watch how local residents protect themselves&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In suspicious places you'll notice local men with their hands in their pockets. Why? It's because they are literally keeping their hands on the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the same places, local women will take a shirt, sweater, or even a newspaper and have it on top of their purse with their arm on top of that. Where &amp;quot;man-purses&amp;quot; are acceptable wear, men will do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="good-thieves-look-like-tourists-or-non-criminals"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Good thieves Look like tourists or non-criminals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people or articles warn you about this or that ethnicity or how people dress. That's not just racist and shallow, it's stupid and inaccurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thieves simply don't want to be noticed, and if noticed they want escape to be as easy as possible. Which means the more active and successful ones dress and act like everyone around you. Which means, for example, in Europe the better thieves are of Caucasian descent and dress like American visitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do note that criminals from a non-majority ethnicity do exist, but they aren't likely to be thieves. This is because being an ethnic minority makes them easier to spot and track down. Also, the all-too-human justice system is harsher on them. Instead, they are often the ones preying on tourists by selling cheap, overpriced trinkets on the sidewalks to tourists who often don't realize they are breaking local laws by purchasing from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="underage-thieves-are-fearless"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Underage thieves are fearless&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Underage thieves have the benefit of that they don't have to worry about the justice system. In many places the police can't arrest children under a certain age and have to let them go. Also, if they are caught, if they are in a gang, an older family member&amp;quot; will come up, rebuke them publicly, and most people will let it go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="an-ounce-of-preperation"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;An ounce of preperation...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a good idea to spend a little time and money getting a few things before you travel. Why? Cause here are the easiest targets in rough order of ease for thieves (1 is super-easy, 7 is merely easy):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backbacks without locks worn on the back. &lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt;: Don't put passports in your backback!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fanny pack or wallet in the back pocket.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grocery or store-purchase bag&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any outside-pocket cellphone holder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suitcases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wallet in the front pocket.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="don-t-be-stupid"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Don't be stupid&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least one travel writer advocates putting your stuff in a local grocery or store bag. That way you &amp;quot;fit in&amp;quot;, thieves ignore you, and you can confidently enjoy your visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;em&gt;mind-bogglingly stupid&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confidence means you allow yourself to be distracted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unless you live somewhere, you stand out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grocery or store bags are not designed to carry things for hours on end. They break.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grocery or store bags are one of the easiest target for thieves. They either don't close adequately or are the perfect target for razor armed thieves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="your-wallet"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Your wallet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take your ID out and only keep a very small amount of money in your wallet, which should be in your front pocket. Take the credit cards out and put them in secret stashes. If you really want a credit card in your wallet, get one linked to a bank account with just enough money for the day in it. Add more money to it as you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="shorten-the-straps"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Shorten the Straps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep the straps of your stuff short and in your hands. When walking next to a street, keep bags on the far side from the road. Moped thieves will will snatch and pull you until the straps break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="use-secret-stashes-on-your-person"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Use secret stashes on your person&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most sporting good stores sell money belts and underclothes pouches. Use the money belt to store cash. Use an underclothes pouch to store your passport and at least one credit card. For underclothes pouches I recommend you open packages and feel the material against your skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="consider-buying-anti-theft-backpacks-laptop-bags"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Consider buying anti-theft backpacks / laptop bags&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We prefer &lt;strong&gt;PacSafe&lt;/strong&gt; brand gear because the clasps are hidden and require a trick to open. Their stuff also has steel wire woven into their straps and fabric, meaning they can't get cut by a razor. PacSafe stuff isn't cheap but the peace of mind has been definitely worth the price. We've relied on the PacSafe &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Pacsafe-Metrosafe-Anti-Theft-Tablet-Laptop/dp/B00AVXDELI/?tag=ihpydanny-20"&gt;laptop bag&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Pacsafe-Luggage-Slingsafe-Shoulder-Black/dp/B006QLMDH0/?tag=ihpydanny-20"&gt;shoulder bag&lt;/a&gt; for about 18 months now and they've been awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://www.amazon.com/Pacsafe-Metrosafe-Anti-Theft-Tablet-Laptop/dp/B00AVXDELI/?tag=ihpydanny-20"&gt;&lt;img alt="My laptop bag" class="align-center" src="http://ecx.images-amazon.com/images/I/41lh%2B2goeNL._SL500_SS80_.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My laptop bag&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://www.amazon.com/Pacsafe-Luggage-Slingsafe-Shoulder-Black/dp/B006QLMDH0/?tag=ihpydanny-20"&gt;&lt;img alt="Audrey's shoulder bag" class="align-center" src="http://ecx.images-amazon.com/images/I/31jF8RBoBEL._SL500_SS80_.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Audrey's shoulder bag&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="identifying-thief-tactics"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Identifying Thief Tactics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a successful thief requires the same skills as a magician. Observation, distraction, misdirection, staged audience members, and timing are how they do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some common techniques they use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-big-local-attraction"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Big Local Attraction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you are gazing at the masterpiece of architecture, hungrily peering at the door menu, or the incredible street performance, your focus is off your stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt;: Train yourself so when you start to feel distracted to put your arm or hand on your most expensive stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-magician"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Magician&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For reference, this is literally the same sort of sleight-of-hand that magicians use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pickpockets often have a newspaper, expensive jacket, or nice sweater in one hand to block what they are doing. While they engage you in friendly conversation they use the prop to block your like of sight from their other hand, which is busy. Especially good thieves don't even bother with the props and just rely on the width of their arm to block lines of observation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt;: If someone you don't know shows something up close to you, back off. In fact, just apologize and keep your distance. It's perfectly okay to not follow &amp;quot;local custom&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-spill"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Spill&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone throws anything at you, or if something is spilled on you, the thief helps you clean up, their accomplice is going through your stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt;: Back up and start screaming &amp;quot;Help, Thief&amp;quot; because it means you've been targeted and are under active scam. Cover your stuff with your arms and hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-fall"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Fall&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one is hard to deal with, especially for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a person falls or stumbles around you, don't help them, regardless of their age or apparent infirmity. While you help them their accomplice is taking from you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt;: Unless there is obvious injury, back off and let the locals take care of it, or find the police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-gift"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Gift&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year the new trick is for someone to ask you if you want them to take pictures of you using your camera or cell phone. You hand them your camera and they start running. &lt;em&gt;You've literally 'gifted' them your camera!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt;: Look for someone to take your picture, never the other way around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="your-room"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Your Room&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While staying at a hotel/hostel/BnB you go out for the day in a place without a safe. When you come back your valuables are gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt;: No safe? Carry your valuables!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="if-you-catch-a-thief"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;If you catch a thief&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You've caught them in the act. Maybe you've grabbed them or maybe they started running. Follow these steps to avoid injury and even death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="don-t-chase-thieves"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DON'T CHASE THIEVES&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever you do, don't chase thieves. Thieves of all ages are usually in gangs or have friends nearby. Their 'backup' carry weapons ranging from sticks to knives to guns. People die from chasing thieves every year in every country. Nothing you are carrying is worth your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="call-for-help"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Call for help&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how to yell &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;Help, Thief!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot; in the local language. Often the locals may deal with it as they hate thieves since crime damages their businesses and local reputation. In fact sometimes the response is overwhelmingly violent. There are stories of would-be victims in Africa, India, and Europe intervening to save the life of a would-be thief's life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-police"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Police&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's pretty universal police who deal with street crime wear uniforms. Work with them and if they ask you if you want to press charges, do so. Otherwise in many places they have to let the person go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="danger-the-undercover-police"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DANGER: The 'undercover' police&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone not wearing a uniform and claiming to be 'undercover' is an accomplice, scam artist, or worse. If they 'come to help':&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't give up any identification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demand that uniformed police be summoned by radio or phone to this location immediately. If the 'undercover' police refuse, then they are a scam or worse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't leave the spot!&lt;/strong&gt; If 'undercover' police try to get you to come with them, refuse loudly. If they try to force you away, start yelling as if your life is in danger, &lt;strong&gt;because it is&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="in-closing"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;In Closing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theft is real. Go to Youtube and spent 10 minutes searching on &amp;quot;thief&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;pickpocket&amp;quot; for proof. Most of the videos are surveillance videos, but when magicians talk about theft it's pretty fun to watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, it's easy to dramatically decrease your chances of being a victim of this kind of crime by being prepared and vigilant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="djangocon"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="travel tips for geeks"></category></entry><entry><title>Off to Europe!</title><link href="https://pydanny.com/off-to-europe.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-04-20T09:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2013-04-20T09:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2013-04-20:/off-to-europe.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I feel like I'm dreaming, but &lt;strong&gt;we're on our way to Europe!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey&lt;/a&gt; and I decided to move. While looking at possible rentals or even mortgages, we were idly (dreaming really... still paying off debts incurred from last year) looking at how much a room/apartment would …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I feel like I'm dreaming, but &lt;strong&gt;we're on our way to Europe!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey&lt;/a&gt; and I decided to move. While looking at possible rentals or even mortgages, we were idly (dreaming really... still paying off debts incurred from last year) looking at how much a room/apartment would cost to rent in Europe. To our surprise, we found a lot of good options that cost less then it would to pay monthly rent/mortgage in Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;o_O&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we discovered an amazing travel deal. It combined a very cheap red-eye flight from Los Angeles to Fort Lauderdale, and a slow trans-atlantic ship from Port Miami to Barcelona, about as much as a cheap hotel but with free food! If we avoid alcohol and any extra fees, it's actually extremely inexpensive. Being mostly disconnected from the internet would mean we could really focus on a couple of critical projects. If only we had a business justification for going to Europe...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It just so happens that we have business in Europe.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our plan is to spend a few months in Europe before returning back to the USA. We'll work hard on the ship, work hard when we arrive, and just get stuff done. It's not a vacation, but it is Europe, and there is such a thing as weekends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll be spending a few days in early May in Barcelona, then making our way to Poland for several weeks. Yes, we're attending &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://djangocircus.com"&gt;Django Circus&lt;/a&gt;, plus I want to investigate some family roots. After Poland, we're thinking either France, Italy, Hungary, England, Belgium, Scotland, Ireland, and other options. We'll see where the winds and affordable AirBNB places take us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When do we go back? Well, we plan to stay for at least two months. Even if we go back to the USA, we would have at least been in Europe for May and June. How cool is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We could have talked ourselves out of going. We nearly did. However, even with our workload this is the chance of a lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, for the next two weeks I'll only be able to access the internet for a few minutes per day. Please expect my responses to emails and tweets to be slower than normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; In the middle of all of this, I was invited to keynote Django Circus: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.djangocircus.com/post/48439600279/meet-daniel-greenfeld"&gt;http://blog.djangocircus.com/post/48439600279/meet-daniel-greenfeld&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="europe"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="djangocon"></category></entry><entry><title>New Year's Resolutions for 2013</title><link href="https://pydanny.com/new-years-resolutions-for-2013.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-12-31T10:45:00-08:00</published><updated>2012-12-31T10:45:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2012-12-31:/new-years-resolutions-for-2013.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm one of those people who not only likes to make New Year's Resolutions, I like to blog about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="resolutions"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resolutions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to at least one technical conference in South America, Asia,  Africa, and Australia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit at least one new nation. It's hard to come up with preferences since the …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm one of those people who not only likes to make New Year's Resolutions, I like to blog about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="resolutions"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resolutions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to at least one technical conference in South America, Asia,  Africa, and Australia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit at least one new nation. It's hard to come up with preferences since the whole world is so exciting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a road trip across the USA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See the Grand Canyon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep to a 32 waist for the whole year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blog once a week. That is at least 52 blog entries!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a fun class with Audrey.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build something real using Twisted as a critical component.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a high level Python class from the likes of Raymond Hettinger or David Beazley.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit to core Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload all my outstanding pictures to Flickr!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pull off an Aú sem Mão (no-handed cartwheel).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attend my first Capoeira Batizado (formal gathering).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work out at least three times a week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how to surf or snowboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a beer with Thomas, Andy, Andy, Tony, Garrick, Bernd, and the rest of Ye Aulde Gange.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See my old DC area friends such as Eric, Chris, Steve, Beth, Sarah, Daye, Renee, Kenneth, Leslie, Whitney, Dave, and many others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="accomplished"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Accomplished&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teach some Python or Django.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go back to at least one of the nations I've visited before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit at least one new nation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to at least one technical conference in North America and Europe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publish as least one book. See &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org/"&gt;Two Scoops of Django&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update my blog to Pelican 3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement a custom theme design so my blog looks more unique. ;-)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit a beach for more than one day. (Split, Croatia)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get married&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit friends and family back east.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="holidays"></category><category term="resolutions"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="capoeira"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="friends"></category><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>2012 resolution summary</title><link href="https://pydanny.com/2012-resolution-summary.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-12-30T10:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2012-12-30T10:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2012-12-30:/2012-resolution-summary.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="resolutions-completed"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resolutions completed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Go to a Python related conference in North America, Europe, and Asia. Conferences I attended:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PyCon US&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DjangoCon Europe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PyCon Philippines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PyCon Poland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;See a place in the USA I've never been. A couple places I saw:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/San_Luis_Obispo"&gt;San Luis Obispo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sonoma_County,_California"&gt;Sonoma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Drop to a 32 waist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Visit friends …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="resolutions-completed"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resolutions completed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Go to a Python related conference in North America, Europe, and Asia. Conferences I attended:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PyCon US&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DjangoCon Europe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PyCon Philippines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PyCon Poland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;See a place in the USA I've never been. A couple places I saw:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/San_Luis_Obispo"&gt;San Luis Obispo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sonoma_County,_California"&gt;Sonoma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Drop to a 32 waist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Visit friends and family back east. Been over a year since I've seen my sister!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Blog once a week. That is at least 52 blog entries! Details:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;48 entries on this blog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12 entries on my &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pydanny.blogspot.com/search?updated-min=2012-01-01T00:00:00-08:00&amp;amp;updated-max=2013-01-01T00:00:00-08:00&amp;amp;max-results=12"&gt;old blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60 entries total!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Visit a Theme park. The parks I got to visit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disneyland"&gt;Disneyland&lt;/a&gt; (Thanks Paul and Marty!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disney_California_Adventure"&gt;Disney California Adventure&lt;/a&gt; (More thanks to Paul and Marty!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Implement something in node.js, backbone.js, and handlebars.js&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Teach some Python or Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="resolution-failure"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resolution Failure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to a Python related conference in South America, Africa, Australia, and New Zealand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attend at least one JavaScript related conference or event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload all my outstanding pictures to Flickr!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make Consumer Notebook profitable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pull off an Aú sem Mão during a Capoeira Roda.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attend my first Capoeira Batizado.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work out at least three times a week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how to surf or snowboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a high level Python class from the likes of Raymond Hettiger or David Beazly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a beer with Thomas, Andy, Andy, Tony, Garrick, Bernd, and the rest of Ye Aulde Gange.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See my old DC area friends such as Eric, Chris, Steve, Beth, Sarah, Daye, Renee, Kenneth, Leslie, Whitney, Dave, and many others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="holidays"></category><category term="resolutions"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="capoeira"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="friends"></category></entry><entry><title>Result of our LA Migration Hackathon submission</title><link href="https://pydanny.com/result-of-our-la-migration-hackathon-submission.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-12-09T15:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2012-12-09T15:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2012-12-09:/result-of-our-la-migration-hackathon-submission.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="possible-causes-of-for-internal-migration-of-undocumented-people"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Possible Causes of for Internal Migration of Undocumented People&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our concept was to measure the effect of changing immigrant laws per state compared to income differences between regions. We present the following, which will be on it's own hosted site shortly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="median-income-over-5-years-between-states"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Median Income over 5 years between States&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; We …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="possible-causes-of-for-internal-migration-of-undocumented-people"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Possible Causes of for Internal Migration of Undocumented People&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our concept was to measure the effect of changing immigrant laws per state compared to income differences between regions. We present the following, which will be on it's own hosted site shortly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="median-income-over-5-years-between-states"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Median Income over 5 years between States&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; We will convert this chart to percentages this week. For now it is in (median income / 500).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="760" height="760" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://www.google.com/fusiontables/embedviz?viz=MAP&amp;amp;q=select+col0%3E%3E1+from+1Bl8lPwB3pVDbXlaS902K8yl_QNarQ2ogwXUaShA&amp;amp;h=false&amp;amp;lat=39.39259824852082&amp;amp;lng=-93.5076772155&amp;amp;z=4&amp;amp;t=1&amp;amp;l=col0%3E%3E1&amp;amp;y=2&amp;amp;tmplt=2"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;textarea cols="100" rows="3"&gt;&lt;iframe width="500" height="500" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://www.google.com/fusiontables/embedviz?viz=MAP&amp;amp;q=select+col0%3E%3E1+from+1Bl8lPwB3pVDbXlaS902K8yl_QNarQ2ogwXUaShA&amp;amp;h=false&amp;amp;lat=39.39259824852082&amp;amp;lng=-93.5076772155&amp;amp;z=4&amp;amp;t=1&amp;amp;l=col0%3E%3E1&amp;amp;y=2&amp;amp;tmplt=2"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="undocumented-immigrants-by-state-per-year"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Undocumented immigrants by state per year&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe width="760" height="760" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://www.google.com/fusiontables/embedviz?viz=MAP&amp;amp;q=select+col0%3E%3E1+from+1b96_5ZHL9DT0JcKVTBY5vbBbB_yMQ2B7Z8Cclog&amp;amp;h=false&amp;amp;lat=38.94970122997403&amp;amp;lng=-97.59459127800005&amp;amp;z=4&amp;amp;t=1&amp;amp;l=col0%3E%3E1&amp;amp;y=2&amp;amp;tmplt=2"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;textarea cols="100" rows="3"&gt;&lt;iframe width="500" height="500" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://www.google.com/fusiontables/embedviz?viz=MAP&amp;amp;q=select+col0%3E%3E1+from+1b96_5ZHL9DT0JcKVTBY5vbBbB_yMQ2B7Z8Cclog&amp;amp;h=false&amp;amp;lat=38.94970122997403&amp;amp;lng=-97.59459127800005&amp;amp;z=4&amp;amp;t=1&amp;amp;l=col0%3E%3E1&amp;amp;y=2&amp;amp;tmplt=2"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="deportation-numbers-per-state"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Deportation Numbers per State&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe width="760" height="760" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://www.google.com/fusiontables/embedviz?viz=MAP&amp;q=select+col0%3E%3E1+from+1jAhJfABP602AwQ4UcxWBf4E4NFP7Pvr3XzYhiTM&amp;h=false&amp;lat=39.39259824852082&amp;amp;lng=-93.5076772155&amp;z=4&amp;t=1&amp;l=col0%3E%3E1&amp;y=2&amp;tmplt=2"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;textarea cols="100" rows="3"&gt;&lt;iframe width="500" height="500" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://www.google.com/fusiontables/embedviz?viz=MAP&amp;q=select+col0%3E%3E1+from+1jAhJfABP602AwQ4UcxWBf4E4NFP7Pvr3XzYhiTM&amp;h=false&amp;lat=39.39259824852082&amp;amp;lng=-93.5076772155&amp;z=4&amp;t=1&amp;l=col0%3E%3E1&amp;y=2&amp;tmplt=2"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="credits"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://sblatino.com"&gt;Carlos Hernandez&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/restabro"&gt;Rachel Estabrook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/connectacopia"&gt;Scott Smith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://latinocalifornia.com"&gt;Agustin Duran&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pydanny.com"&gt;Daniel Greenfeld&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hackathon2012.wikidot.com/"&gt;LA Hackathon on Immigration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="hackathon"></category><category term="lahackthons"></category><category term="Los Angeles"></category></entry><entry><title>Thoughts on ranting</title><link href="https://pydanny.com/thoughts-on-ranting.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-11-26T16:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2012-11-26T16:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2012-11-26:/thoughts-on-ranting.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'll admit it, I love a good rant. I respect those who can give rants well. I would list the ones I really like, but I'm not sure I want to deal with the arguments that would follow. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, as much as I like to read or listen to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'll admit it, I love a good rant. I respect those who can give rants well. I would list the ones I really like, but I'm not sure I want to deal with the arguments that would follow. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, as much as I like to read or listen to them, I also like to give them. As of 11/26/2012 there are 2 on this &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pydanny.com/tag/rant.html"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; and 26 on my &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pydanny.blogspot.com/search/label/rant"&gt;old blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I have a problem in giving rants. It ties with this unfortunate trait I possess where if I let myself get angry I say things that destroy relationships. No, I'm not giving examples, but there you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when I do rant, I try to never do so in anger. Especially when it's the written word. Instead, I try to do so under one of the following conditions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I need to be a whimsical mood.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OR I need to be willing to submit a solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OR I need to be willing to accept a solution, even if it means work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OR I need to be willing to create a solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OR the object of the rant must be an easy target to flame.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content><category term="blog"></category><category term="rant"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="friends"></category></entry><entry><title>Curiosity has landed!</title><link href="https://pydanny.com/curiosity-has-landed.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-08-06T08:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2012-08-06T08:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2012-08-06:/curiosity-has-landed.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm terribly proud of what was accomplished last night: A car-sized robot weighing a whopping 8,580 pounds (3,893 kg) was landed on Mars. It is packed with scientific packages that will expand our knowledge of Mars, and has the power to use them for at least 14 years …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm terribly proud of what was accomplished last night: A car-sized robot weighing a whopping 8,580 pounds (3,893 kg) was landed on Mars. It is packed with scientific packages that will expand our knowledge of Mars, and has the power to use them for at least 14 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, this is an incredible step forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Mars_Science_Laboratory_Curiosity_rover.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="align-center" id="artist-impression-of-curiosity-on-mars" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/a9/Mars_Science_Laboratory_Curiosity_rover.jpg/800px-Mars_Science_Laboratory_Curiosity_rover.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an American, I'm proud that our nation is capable of putting together such amazing feats of engineering and science. People from a diverse arrangement of backgrounds and origins came together to make something incredible happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a human being, I'm proud that we have yet again proven that we are still capable of working together to make amazing things happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone who grew up in the 1970s, and someone who is proud to have worked at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nasa.gov"&gt;NASA&lt;/a&gt; for over 5 years, this is my American dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="going-forward"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Going Forward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curiosity is about to do amazing things and will tell a story to us that we'll never forget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alas, NASA is a terribly easy target for politicians. It's budget has shrank to a small fraction of the it's early 1970s high, and it remains a target to this day. While the politicians congratulate the JPL team on one hand, they are also cutting the JPL budget in a short-sighted attempt to make themselves look good. History will not be kind to such politicians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answers to our questions and our problems will be found in the heavens. Let's increase NASA funding and populate the world with miracles of science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="nasa"></category><category term="science"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>Choosing a new python based blog engine</title><link href="https://pydanny.com/choosing-a-new-python-based-blog-engine.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-04-05T12:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2012-04-05T12:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2012-04-05:/choosing-a-new-python-based-blog-engine.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="why-a-new-blog-engine"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why a new blog engine?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pydanny.blogspot.com/"&gt;old blog&lt;/a&gt;, I had been having issues with Blogger for some time.  The WYSIWYG text editor was annoying in that it produced wonky HTML, so I had to hand craft the posts. Which meant I often wrote the HTML formatted copy in a …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="why-a-new-blog-engine"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why a new blog engine?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pydanny.blogspot.com/"&gt;old blog&lt;/a&gt;, I had been having issues with Blogger for some time.  The WYSIWYG text editor was annoying in that it produced wonky HTML, so I had to hand craft the posts. Which meant I often wrote the HTML formatted copy in a text editor and then copy/pasted it into the browser. A few times this blew up and I really wished I had version controlled back ups. Adding code examples was problematic, even with a stylesheet helpfully provided by Google. Finally, some of the changes to the blog engine itself were beginning to worry me, so I started looking for alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my fiancee, Audrey Roy, converted her blog to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll"&gt;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&lt;/a&gt; at it's new location of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;audreymroy.com&lt;/a&gt;, the static file hosting seemed so awesome I was impressed enough to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pydanny.com/tried-out-jekyll.html"&gt;give Jekyll a try&lt;/a&gt;. Why did Jekyll and static file hosting interest me so much?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-don-t-want-to-maintain-my-own-server"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;I don't want to maintain my own server&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple times I rolled out a blog on a site I stood up, but didn't really feel like maintaining a site. I want someone else to do it. When I write, I want someone else to worry about the details. I want to focus on writing and nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well... almost nothing else. You'll understand shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-want-to-be-able-to-write-without-connection"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;I want to be able to write without connection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With blogger, I needed an internet connection to get my blog posts to format correctly. With Jekyll and other static file systems, I can just type away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-want-to-publish-via-git"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;I want to publish via git&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pydanny-event-notes.rtfd.org"&gt;https://pydanny-event-notes.rtfd.org&lt;/a&gt; has really exploded in my own usage and continued because it uses the same patterns I use in software development. I'm used to the pattern of using Git to push up content, so why use naked HTML? Sure, there are RST-to-HTML processors that I could use to generate that HTML, but they always require some amount of manual correction. Jekyll, and it's alternatives, let me just write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="jekyll-wasn-t-for-me"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Jekyll wasn't for me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found Jekyll to be good and much more fun than Blogger, but not good enough. To sum up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I prefer RestructuredText over Markdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don't know enough Ruby to easily customize things. I don't feel like diving into Ruby just to learn how to make modifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The template engine was like Smarty/Django/Jinja2, but not as much fun. Debugging errors was very problematic. Which was a problem when I started to play with modifying the theme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the second and third bullets, you might wonder why I would care about the underlying engine if all I wanted to do was write. Well, I'm well aware of the fact that I change opinions now and then.  :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was after trying out Jekyll that I started looking for &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://python.org"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; based static file blog systems. The choices that seemed appropriate were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="blogofile"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.blogofile.com/"&gt;blogofile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably the most mature, most common Python static file generator around. It looks really awesome, and everyone who uses it swears by it. Alas, it's powered by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.makotemplates.org/"&gt;Mako&lt;/a&gt; templates, which is... um... &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pydanny.blogspot.com/2010/12/stupid-template-languages.html"&gt;not my friend&lt;/a&gt; (apologies to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://techspot.zzzeek.org/2010/12/04/in-response-to-stupid-template-languages/"&gt;Mike Bayer&lt;/a&gt;). What I really wanted was something with templates powered by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pocoo.org/projects/jinja2/"&gt;Jinja2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="hyde"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hyde.github.com/"&gt;hyde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyde claims to have started as Jekyll's evil Python twin. On the surface it looks awesome. Where it fails is documentation. There are lots of wonderful features that appear to exist, but follow the links to those features and you find yourself on placeholder pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In theory, I could have just looked at the hyde code and figured out stuff myself. Maybe even document out the holes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In practice, all I want to do is write blog posts. It's one thing to customize things to suit your needs, it's another thing to make things work. Or document a tool. Color me lazy if you will, but when it comes to blogging, that's just how I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think in the near future, once fully documented, Hyde is going to be AWESOME. For now? Well, I wanted another option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pelican"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pelican.readthedocs.org/"&gt;pelican&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was immediately hooked. Python powered engine with Jinja2 templates with &lt;strong&gt;complete documentation&lt;/strong&gt;. In fact, every time I asked the author for help, he resignedly pointed me at the documentation. How cool is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point I'll use the &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;CSS&lt;/tt&gt; setting to change the color of &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;pygments&lt;/tt&gt; to something with white background and black text. For now I'm happy as things are now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/77704901&amp;#64;N05/6831339872/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="align-center" id="pycon-cartwheel-with-glass" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7043/6831339872_10d0c40171.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=3804553"&gt;Discuss this post on Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="python"></category><category term="blog"></category></entry><entry><title>My new blog</title><link href="https://pydanny.com/my-new-blog.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-02-17T00:30:00-08:00</published><updated>2012-02-17T00:30:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2012-02-17:/my-new-blog.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What I did to get it running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
pip install pelican
git clone git://github.com/pydanny/pydanny.github.com.git
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My settings.py file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
AUTHOR = 'Daniel Greenfeld'
DISQUS_SITENAME = 'pydanny'
GITHUB_URL = 'https://github.com/pydanny'
GOOGLE_ANALYTICS='UA-18066389-2'
SITEURL = 'https://pydanny.github.com'
SITENAME = 'pydanny'
SOCIAL = (('twitter', 'http://twitter.com/pydanny'),
          ('github' …&lt;/pre&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What I did to get it running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
pip install pelican
git clone git://github.com/pydanny/pydanny.github.com.git
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My settings.py file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
AUTHOR = 'Daniel Greenfeld'
DISQUS_SITENAME = 'pydanny'
GITHUB_URL = 'https://github.com/pydanny'
GOOGLE_ANALYTICS='UA-18066389-2'
SITEURL = 'https://pydanny.github.com'
SITENAME = 'pydanny'
SOCIAL = (('twitter', 'http://twitter.com/pydanny'),
          ('github', 'https://github.com/pydanny'),
          ('facebook', 'http://www.facebook.com/daniel.greenfeld'),)
TAG_FEED = 'feeds/%s.atom.xml'
THEME='notmyidea'
TWITTER_USERNAME = 'pydanny'
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How I push up entries and pages and themes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
pelican . -o . -s settings.py
git commit -am &amp;quot;blogging here&amp;quot;
git push
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="results"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Results!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pydanny.github.com"&gt;https://pydanny.github.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="python"></category><category term="blog"></category></entry><entry><title>Tried out Jekyll</title><link href="https://pydanny.com/tried-out-jekyll.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-02-09T10:20:00-08:00</published><updated>2012-02-09T10:20:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2012-02-09:/tried-out-jekyll.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="why-jekyll"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why Jekyll?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've had issues with Blogger for some time.  After my fiancee, Audrey Roy, moved her blog to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll"&gt;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, I was impressed enough to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did it impress me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="code-highlighting-made-easy"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Code highlighting made easy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't have to hand-craft HTML code to …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="why-jekyll"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why Jekyll?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've had issues with Blogger for some time.  After my fiancee, Audrey Roy, moved her blog to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll"&gt;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, I was impressed enough to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did it impress me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="code-highlighting-made-easy"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Code highlighting made easy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't have to hand-craft HTML code to get google prettify in a post. I just stick in a simple macro of 'highlight python' called like a Django templatetag and I get:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;Daniel Greenfeld&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;letter&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;split&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;():&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;letter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This issue alone sums up why I don't do more blog posts with code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-don-t-want-to-maintain-my-own-blog-site"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I don't want to maintain my own blog site&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple times I rolled out a blog on a site I stood up, but didn't really feel like maintaining a site. I want someone else to do it. When I write, I want someone else to worry about the details. I want to focus on writing and nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-want-to-be-able-to-write-without-connection"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I want to be able to write without connection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need an internet connection to get my blogger posts to format right. With Jekyll, I can just type away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ability-to-publish-via-git"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ability to publish via git&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pydanny-event-notes.rtfd.org"&gt;https://pydanny-event-notes.rtfd.org&lt;/a&gt; has really exploded in my own usage and continued because it uses the same patterns I use in software development. I'm used to the pattern of using Git to push up content, so why use naked HTML? Sure, there are RST-to-HTML processors that I could use to generate that HTML, but they always require an some amount of manual correction. Jekyll, and it's alternatives,let me just write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="why-not-jekyll"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why not Jekyll?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is written in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ruby-lang.org"&gt;ruby&lt;/a&gt;. Nothing against ruby, but I can't trivially work in that language the way I can in Python. It's good to eat your own dogfood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I started looking at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hyde.github.com/"&gt;hyde&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blogofile.com/"&gt;blogofile&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pelican.readthedocs.org/"&gt;pelican&lt;/a&gt; as alternatives. More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="ruby"></category><category term="blog"></category></entry></feed>