<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>pydanny</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pydanny.com/feeds/book.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pydanny.com/</id><updated>2013-03-02T09:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>We are not using PayPal</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/we-are-not-using-paypal.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-02T09:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2013-03-02:we-are-not-using-paypal.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In January &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey Roy&lt;/a&gt; and I launched a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; about Django called &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;Two Scoops of Django: Best Practices for Django 1.5&lt;/a&gt;. We decided to not use PayPal. Here's why:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="open-source-events-get-burned-by-paypal"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Open Source Events Get Burned By PayPal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PayPal has a long, sordid history of freezing the accounts of Python related conferences and events around the world. In fact, this article was born out of the fact &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.djangocircus.com/post/43806402173/back-on-track"&gt;DjangoCon Europe 2013 had its PayPal account frozen&lt;/a&gt;. In the past, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://2012.djangocon.eu/"&gt;DjangoCon Europe 2012&lt;/a&gt;, Plone Conferences 2008, 2011, and at least one PyCon Australia dealt with the same PayPal problem (DjangoCon 2013 was forewarned and took measures to protect itself). We also have unconfirmed reports of other Python and Django events also running into problems with PayPal freezing accounts. Going with just confirmed conferences having issues with PayPal, this is a combined total of assets in excess of over US$100,000 dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not just a Python issue either, it's an issue that &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://conferencesburnedbypaypal.tumblr.com/"&gt;strikes other open source languages and tools&lt;/a&gt;. It's at the point now where &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://aralbalkan.com/3898/"&gt;conference organizers don't trust PayPal&lt;/a&gt; and make a point telling each other to use alternative payment gateways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="fear-shame-and-paypal"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fear, Shame, and PayPal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The terrifying thing to consider is that I suspect that the number of technical conferences affected by PayPal freezes is much, much larger. My reasoning is that &lt;strong&gt;most conferences keep quiet about it&lt;/strong&gt; because &lt;strong&gt;they're afraid that raising a fuss will annoy PayPal's anti-fraud division&lt;/strong&gt;. Let's also face the fact that &lt;strong&gt;most people feel ashamed when bank accounts they are responsible for get frozen&lt;/strong&gt;, so probably don't publicize the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The usual way conferences deal with these lockouts is conference organizers beg and borrow from friends, family, take second mortgages, local banking institutions, and pray that PayPal will eventually free their account. When you deal with a hostile, inaccessible payment gateway who won't let you provide for the hundreds or even thousands of people who paid you their hard earned money, it's the only way to get by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-needs-of-paypal-s-anti-fraud-division"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The 'Needs' of PayPal's Anti-Fraud Division&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I could respect the needs of PayPal's anti-fraud division when dealing with non-fungible products like ticket sales, it's &lt;strong&gt;simply unacceptable&lt;/strong&gt; that prominent conferences for open source projects are treated this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The software represented by these conferences drives the modern e-commerce world, including the myriad of systems that use PayPal to process sales. Yet PayPal continues to burn open source conferences year after year, and we've never heard of any conference outreach by their so-called 'developer evangelists' when a conference's account is frozen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="legal-recourse-against-paypal-is-folly"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Legal recourse against PayPal is folly&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask any lawyer and they'll basically say against PayPal you have no options. PayPal has an army of lawyers and in most places isn't a bank, meaning your course of action is constrained from the beginning by your agreeing to PayPal's Terms of Service (TOS). Also, in the United States, their TOS prevents you from joining a class action lawsuit against them. Whether or not that TOS clause is enforceable in court, the fact that it is in their TOS greatly reduces any faith I might have had in them because it paints a picture of a company hostile to my needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In talking to authors and entrepreneurs, we've just heard (and read) too many horror stories. For merchants of non-fungible goods such as digital goods like the e-book I co-authored, PayPal seems even less trustworthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which means using PayPal places us at an unacceptable risk. We simply don't have the deep pockets to deal with PayPal freezing our funds for sales lost from a more reliable distribution system such as &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://stripe.com"&gt;Stripe&lt;/a&gt; that powers our sales through &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gumroad.com"&gt;Gumroad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="it-is-wrong-to-use-paypal"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It is Wrong to Use PayPal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering PayPal's unacceptable behavior in regards to the open source community I love and merchants who try to work in their system, I feel it is wrong to support PayPal. Audrey agrees, and so our policy of not using PayPal to sell the book is set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="paypal-is-at-risk"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PayPal is at Risk&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a day when Microsoft had what seemed to be an unassailable lock on the commercial software world. On many levels, Microsoft is a shadow of its former self, and I contend it wasn't just Apple's competition. Instead, Microsoft's contempt for their own customers and the developer community hurt them just as much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PayPal is on the same path of self-destruction. The've gone from the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/The-PayPal-Wars-Battles-Planet/dp/0977898431/?tag=cn-001-20"&gt;scrappy company&lt;/a&gt; helping people grow their business to the monolithic overlord that kills businesses and well-meaning events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PayPal's demise won't happen this year, or the next, but every time they damage their customer base and the developer community it's another nail in the coffin. I submit that unless PayPal changes its ways, within 5 years PayPal will be a shadow of its former self as the army of growing competitors such as &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://stripe.com"&gt;Stripe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.balancedpayments.com/"&gt;Balanced Payments&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.wepay.com/"&gt;wepay&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.payoneer.com/"&gt;Payoneer&lt;/a&gt; expands their availability and options around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-paypal-can-do-for-conferences"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What PayPal Can Do for Conferences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PayPal does have to worry about ticket sales for bogus events, since that  separates people from their money, but identifying real conferences is easy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PayPal developer evangelists and community managers need to track every valid developer event in the world. It's the job of people in these roles to have the connections and subject matter expertise to identify real events from fake ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PayPal needs to sponsor these events. Why? See point #3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PayPal's anti-fraud division needs to be informed that any PayPal sponsored event is off-limits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-paypal-can-do-for-small-business"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What PayPal Can Do for Small Business&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PayPal has its developer evangelists, community managers, and marketing departments working hard. However, at the end of the day, if you treat your customers with disrespect and a lack of trust, none of that matters. Bad press and market forces will see their revenues drop as customers will migrate to solutions that are more trustworthy and less antagonistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that PayPal needs to revise how its anti-fraud division communicates with people who have frozen accounts. They need to change the adversarial pose they take with their own customers to one that is collaborative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="note"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Note&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This issue made me very angry. To help me calm down in order to write this article I found &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0807012394/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0807012394&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=cn-001-20"&gt;this book&lt;/a&gt; recommended by my friend Randall Degges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are into Django, Python, or programming in general, check out the book I co-authored at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://django.2scoops.org/"&gt;https://django.2scoops.org/&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="twoscoops"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="paypal"></category><category term="rant"></category></entry><entry><title>Two Scoops of Django 1.5 Beta Released</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/two-scoops-beta-released.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-28T15:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2013-02-28:two-scoops-beta-released.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After thirty four days of hard work, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey Roy&lt;/a&gt; and I are proud to announce that we've released the &lt;strong&gt;beta&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;Two Scoops of Django: Best Practices for Django 1.5&lt;/a&gt;. It's been a monumental effort, a labor of love, and we hope you find our efforts worthy. You can buy it right now in e-book (PDF) form on the website: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;http://django.2scoops.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two Scoops of Django: Best Practices for Django 1.5 is a compilation of best practices for the Django framework. Like any framework, Django has tips, tricks, and pitfalls that aren't documented in one place. Experienced developers know this stuff, but gleaning it off the Internet takes a lot of time. We decided to take everything we know and write it down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stand of the shoulders of giants: We received advice from Django experts including a BDFL, Django core developers, and subject matter experts from around the world. Reader contributions from advanced and beginning developers have also shaped the book, and we can't thank enough those who gave us their insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://django.2scoops.org/"&gt;&lt;img alt="https://s3.amazonaws.com/twoscoops/img/tsd-cover-beta.png" class="align-center" id="two-scoops-of-django" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/twoscoops/img/tsd-cover-beta.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a name="features"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class="section" id="what-is-different-about-the-beta-release"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is different about the beta release?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added 50+ pages of content while reducing the file size from 5.1 MB to 1.5 MB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added list of tables, list of figures, and an index.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dramatically improved the chapters on security, testing, logging, admin, and many more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added so many more code samples that even with the new example numbering system we lost count.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaking of code examples, most of the code samples in the book are loaded directly out of fully tested projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incorporated the feedback of dozens of readers. Thank you so much for your contributions!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;a name="what-do-i-get"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-does-buying-the-beta-get-me"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What does buying the beta get me?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access the PDF version of the book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access to the Kindle and ePub formats when we release the final.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access to final release of the book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;a name="alpha-buyers"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="if-i-bought-the-alpha-do-i-have-to-buy-the-beta"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;If I bought the alpha do I have to buy the beta?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alpha buyers get full access the beta. In fact, you should have already received an email with a link to the latest version. If that hasn't arrived, please email us at &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com"&gt;2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name="beginners"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="is-this-book-good-for-beginners"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is this book good for beginners?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The response from beginning Django developers reading it has been &lt;strong&gt;unbelievably, overwhelmingly positive&lt;/strong&gt;. This is the book we wanted to have when we learned Django, and we're honored by the response the book has received.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the book isn't a tutorial, we ask that before beginners purchase it, they &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://learnpythonthehardway.org/"&gt;learn the fundamentals of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Learn-Python-Hard-Way-Introduction/dp/0321884914/?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=cn-001-20"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; and take the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/1.5/intro/tutorial01/"&gt;official Django tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When beginners find sections of the book above their head, they do what everyone does when reading a technical reference: skip over challenging sections until they have enough grounding to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any beginners are confused by our explanations, or have difficulties, please email us at &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com"&gt;2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com&lt;/a&gt;. We'll do our best to answer your questions. Your issues provide invaluable insight into what we need to improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name="experienced"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="is-this-book-good-for-experienced-developers"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is this book good for experienced developers?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've done our best to provide worthwhile material for developers of all levels. In fact, a lot of intermediate to advanced developers have said they've found good things to use in our book. Many have also found that by using our book as a supplementary manual, it helps them their team work better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name="updates"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="is-this-book-going-to-get-updated"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is this book going to get updated?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the &lt;strong&gt;alpha&lt;/strong&gt; we updated the book multiple times before knuckling down on the &lt;strong&gt;beta&lt;/strong&gt; rewrite. Even after the final version comes out, we'll continue to update the book. One of the advantages of self-published e-books is we have total control of content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name="print"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="when-can-i-get-a-print-version"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When can I get a print version?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a lot of consideration, we've decided to hold off on the print version of the book until what we call the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.com/two-scoops-beta-released.html#final"&gt;final&lt;/a&gt; release, which won't be released until after &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/"&gt;PyCon US&lt;/a&gt;. We're very finicky and don't want buyers of the print version to have an unfinished book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name="tutorial"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a name="pycon"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a name="wiring-up-django-packages"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="tutorial-pycon-are-you-going"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tutorial? PyCon? Are you going?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes! We're going to be at PyCon next month!  We're giving the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/11/"&gt;Wiring Up Django Packages&lt;/a&gt; tutorial, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://brack3t.com/"&gt;Kenneth Love&lt;/a&gt; (of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gettingstartedwithdjango.com/"&gt;Getting Started with Django&lt;/a&gt; fame) is part of our team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While tickets to PyCon itself are sold out, you can still &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/registration/register/"&gt;register for the tutorials&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name="final"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="when-is-the-book-s-final-release"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When is the book's final release?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final release won't occur until after PyCon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our plan for the final release of Two Scoops of Django: Best Practices for Django 1.5 is to focus on errata, alternative electronic formats, and the print version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name="bulk"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="can-we-purchase-the-book-in-bulk"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Can we purchase the book in bulk?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're working on a program to provide organizations the capability to purchase many e-copies and keep the recipients of the book updated constantly. We hope to have this ready in a few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name="paypal"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="can-i-buy-the-book-via-paypal"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Can I buy the book via PayPal?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No. I've answered in full &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.com/we-are-not-using-paypal.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're considering other non-credit card options to handle payment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name="known-issue-warnings"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="known-issue-warnings"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Known Issue Warnings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="copy-paste"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Copy/Paste&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are problems with copy/pasting of code from the PDF. The new build process is turning the code examples into some sort of image type of object, which explains the strange characters. We're working on it, but aren't sure how long the fix will take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="android"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Android&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Android, if you try to open the PDF directly from the Gumroad download, you might get a &amp;quot;Cannot open file&amp;quot; error; however, if you navigate to the download location on your phone/tablet with a file browser (e.g. Samsung's &amp;quot;My Files&amp;quot;), you should be able to open the file from there. Gumroad is currently investigating the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name="errata"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="where-should-i-send-errata-or-suggestions"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where should I send errata or suggestions?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send errata to &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com"&gt;2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com&lt;/a&gt;. We try to respond personally to every request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="twoscoops"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="audrey"></category><category term="pycon"></category></entry><entry><title>Two Scoops of Django FAQ</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/two-scoops-django-faq-20130121.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-21T16:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2013-01-21:two-scoops-django-faq-20130121.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://django.2scoops.org/"&gt;&lt;img alt="https://s3.amazonaws.com/pydanny/frontispiece.png" class="align-center" id="two-scoops-of-django" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/pydanny/frontispiece.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;Two Scoops of Django: Best Practices for Django 1.5&lt;/a&gt; book has gone pretty well. The response has been almost entirely positive and sales have been pretty brisk. We've gotten a ton of great, constructive editorial feedback, which we're sorting through as we race towards the BETA release. Here are answers to the commonly asked questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="when-can-i-buy-the-book-via-paypal"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When can I buy the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; via PayPal?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will support PayPal in either the BETA or FINAL release of the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to handle PayPal we need to find a reputable e-publisher that supports it that gives us similar rates, customer service, and product control (updates at any time, uploads of PDF, no surprise charges, etc) as &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gumroad.com"&gt;Gumroad&lt;/a&gt;. If you know of an e-publisher who is willing to provide that same level of service, please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the record, we aren't leaving &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gumroad.com"&gt;Gumroad&lt;/a&gt;. We just want to support developers and students who don't have credit cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;note:&lt;/strong&gt; While we could certainly write our own publishing platform, that would delay work on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt;. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="when-can-i-get-a-kindle-mobi-or-epub-version"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When can I get a Kindle (mobi) or ePub version?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our plan is to support those formats in either the BETA or FINAL releases. In fact, I really love my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B007HCCNJU/?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=cn-001-20"&gt;Kindle&lt;/a&gt;. I can't wait to proof my own &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; on my favorite reading device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="when-can-i-get-a-print-version"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When can I get a print version?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope to have a print version in about 30 days. We need to ensure that the cover and layout actually looks nice, and that involves ordering copies from the Lulu, CreateSpace, whatever and reviewing them and making corrections. Then ordering again to make sure the corrections look okay. That simply takes a lot of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are hoping for a mid-February release. Also, keep in mind we aren't sure yet if we'll do a print version of anything but a FINAL release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="when-are-the-beta-and-final-releases"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When are the BETA and FINAL releases?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can't make promises, but at the latest, the FINAL &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be done by the start of March so people have them in hand at PyCon US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="is-this-book-going-to-get-updated"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is this book going to get updated?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, we've already sent out three minor updates for grammar and spelling issues, and some bug fixes.  Even after the FINAL version comes out, we'll continue to update the book. One of the advantages of self-published books is we have control of content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-much-work-went-into-the-book"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How much work went into the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey&lt;/a&gt; and I put in hundreds of hours writing and testing the content. We worked 12-16 hour days for weeks. It was madness, but a glorious madness. We became like hermits and toiled on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; while ignoring distractions like sleep, food and consistent exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our amazing technical reviewers also worked very hard to provide us with critical commentary, advice and corrections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="where-should-i-send-errata"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where should I send errata?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send errata to &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com"&gt;2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com&lt;/a&gt;. The first person who reports an issue or makes a suggestion that we adopt will receive credit in the book. If not in the changelog, then in the dialogue of the book itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="are-you-going-to-pycon-us"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Are you going to PyCon US?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely! Wouldn't miss &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/"&gt;PyCon US&lt;/a&gt; for the world! &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey&lt;/a&gt; and I met and fell in love at PyCon US 2010! We'll be there for at least the second day of  tutorials, all the talks, and all the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/community/sprints/"&gt;sprints&lt;/a&gt;. I've even got a blog post coming that should serve as a guide for beginning Python and Django developers attending the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shameless Plug:&lt;/em&gt; We're both speaking and giving a tutorial. Sign up for the tutorial or attend our talks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="wiring-up-django-packages-tutorial"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/11/"&gt;Wiring Up Django Packages&lt;/a&gt; (Tutorial)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You just finished the Django tutorial. What do you do now? You wire in Django Packages! Django is part of an ecosphere of over 20,000 packages, which can be leveraged to great effect. This tutorial will teach the evaluation, use, and extension of third party Python and Django applications in your projects. This tutorial will be a lecture with a lot of detailed and annotated code examples. Instructors are &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey Roy&lt;/a&gt;, Daniel Greenfeld, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://brack3t.com/"&gt;Kenneth Love&lt;/a&gt; (of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gettingstartedwithdjango.com/"&gt;Getting Started with Django&lt;/a&gt; fame).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="advanced-django-forms-usage-talk"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/101/"&gt;Advanced Django Forms Usage&lt;/a&gt;  (Talk)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django forms are really powerful but there are edge cases, especially with class based views), that can cause a bit of anguish. This talk will go over how to handle many common solutions not currently described in the core documentation. It will also cover useful third-party libraries. Speaker is Daniel Greenfeld.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="using-python-to-generate-art-and-sound-talk"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/58/"&gt;Using Python To Generate Art And Sound&lt;/a&gt; (Talk)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trick to navigating the overwhelming Python audio/imaging landscape is understanding how the fundamentals work, using common data processing/visualization libraries, in-depth code samples, and simple math operations. I use the stdlib, NumPy, SciPy, Matplotlib, PIL, and PyCairo to create building blocks, which I then combine to demonstrate advanced sound and image generation techniques. Speaker is &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey Roy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="are-you-going-to-django-circus"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Are you going to Django Circus?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope so. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://2013.djangocon.eu/"&gt;Django Circus&lt;/a&gt;, a.k.a. DjangoCon Europe, is one of the important industry events for us and we're trying to figure out logistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our problem is that 2012 was a very hard year - the majority of our clients have not paid for the work that we did. Collecting is turning out to be extremely difficult, time consuming, and unpleasant. This is impacting everything we want to do in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-does-the-alpha-work"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How does the ALPHA work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ALPHA is a preview version that we are selling at an introductory price of $12. When you purchase the ALPHA, you get access to the BETA and FINAL versions when they are released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you're wondering, we are planning to increase the price of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; when we release the BETA and FINAL versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="twoscoops"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="audrey"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="djangocon"></category></entry><entry><title>Our Django Book Has Launched</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/our-django-book-is-launched.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-17T10:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2013-01-17:our-django-book-is-launched.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://django.2scoops.org/"&gt;&lt;img alt="https://s3.amazonaws.com/twoscoops/img/tsd-cover.png" class="align-center" id="two-scoops-of-django-best-practices-for-django-1-5" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/twoscoops/img/tsd-cover.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey Roy&lt;/a&gt; and I) wrote a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; on Django! It's called &lt;strong&gt;Two Scoops of Django: Best Practices for Django 1.5&lt;/strong&gt;, and you can buy it right now in e-book (PDF) form on the website: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;http://django.2scoops.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django, like any framework, has tips, tricks, and pitfalls that aren't documented in one place. Experienced developers know this stuff, but gleaning it off the Internet takes a lot of time. We decided to take everything we know and write it down. This &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; reflects a portion of what we documented, and if it does well we plan to follow it up with other references.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've followed this blog or watched our talks you've know we've explained tons of Django and Python related examples. We enjoy using Django and Python to build stable, fast web applications quickly and efficiently. This is the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; we would have wanted while learning the intricacies of our tools, and then kept it handy for reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; we cover everything from customizing the Django 1.5 User model, forms,  views, templates, security, bottleneck analysis and so much more. We tie in third-party packages from the Django and Python community. We discuss the positive patterns that allow for rapid development, and point out the anti-patterns that cause problems.
The result isn't a walk-through or tutorial, but a reference guide for anyone with at least a basic understanding of Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tried to make the code copy/pastable, but we are constrained by the limits of PDF. While the code examples display nicely, &lt;em&gt;when pasting from Adobe Reader the leading white spaces vanish&lt;/em&gt;. We apologize and ask if anyone knows how to address this issue to let us know at &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com"&gt;2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even with an amazing cadre of technical reviewers, there is always the possibility of errors. We are going to be actively maintaining the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt;, so if you find a mistake, let us know and we'll update it and send out an updated copy of the PDF to all buyers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you'd like to buy the book (or learn more about it), you can do so here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;http://django.2scoops.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="twoscoops"></category><category term="resolutions"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="audrey"></category><category term="class-based-views"></category><category term="heroku"></category><category term="dotcloud"></category><category term="gondor"></category></entry></feed>