<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>pydanny</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pydanny.com/feeds/djangocon.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pydanny.com/</id><updated>2013-07-18T16:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Travel Tips for Geeks: Preventing Theft</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/travel-tips-for-geeks-preventing-theft.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-07-18T16:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2013-07-18:travel-tips-for-geeks-preventing-theft.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the first in a set of blog posts based on my experiences traveling in various places around the world. This particular safety-related post is about theft, not scams, which I may cover in another article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this first article, I'm hoping this gets on various technical RSS feeds. I'm doing this because many of the readers of such feeds attend conferences and are strangers in far and distant places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="about-thieves"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About Thieves&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thieves are everywhere. I've seen extremely suspicious activity in Portland, Los Angeles, Washington DC, Barcelona, Florence, Pisa, and Krakow. Years ago in Washington DC I had stuff stolen from me twice so I've been observant and careful ever since. Anywhere there are non-residents distracted by looking at new vistas while suffering from travel fatigue is where most thieves can be found. I've learned a lot by observation and doing research but I don't claim to be an expert. All I claim to be is someone who doesn't want to be ripped off far from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-basics-any-place-with-tourists-is-risky"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Basics: Any place with tourists is risky&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it can be said that thieves can be anywhere, the truth is that they focus on where the tourists go. We carry money and expensive things, are tired, distracted, and don't know our way around. For a thief, A moment of risk can yield hundreds or thousands of dollars of profit from a traveler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-ve-never-had-any-problems-there"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&amp;quot;I've never had any problems there&amp;quot;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've heard this several times from local residents or travelers, often in places with statistical high crime rates. You'll hear it too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that means is that they've either been lucky or unobservant. It's better to be careful and avoid a miserable trip, because losing your identification, credit cards, cash, or electronics will ruin a trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="listen-to-warnings-before-you-go-places"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Listen to warnings before you go places&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Barcelona our host warned us about La Rambla, a tourist-heavy street that's notoriously thick with thieves. While we're always careful, we were especially observant there, and enjoyed the very lovely and friendly downtown Barcelona without incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversely, don't pay attention to warnings at locations. Public notices about thieves are a nasty trap. When you see them you check your most expensive things, giving away the location of money, jewelry, watches, and cell phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="watch-how-local-residents-protect-themselves"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Watch how local residents protect themselves&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In suspicious places you'll notice local men with their hands in their pockets. Why? It's because they are literally keeping their hands on the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the same places, local women will take a shirt, sweater, or even a newspaper and have it on top of their purse with their arm on top of that. Where &amp;quot;man-purses&amp;quot; are acceptable wear, they'll do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="good-thieves-look-like-tourists-or-non-criminals"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Good thieves Look like tourists or non-criminals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people or articles warn you about this or that ethnicity or how people dress. That's not just racist and shallow, it's stupid and inaccurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thieves simply don't want to be noticed, and if noticed they want escape to be as easy as possible. Which means the more active and successful ones dress and act like everyone around you. Which means, for example, in Europe the better thieves are of Caucasian descent and dress like American visitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do note that criminals from a non-majority ethnicity do exist, but they aren't likely to be thieves. This is because being an ethnic minority makes them easier to spot and track down. Also, the all-too-human justice system is harsher on them. Instead, they are often the ones preying on tourists by selling cheap, overpriced trinkets on the sidewalks to tourists who often don't realize they are breaking local laws by purchasing from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="underage-thieves-are-fearless"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Underage thieves are fearless&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Underage thieves have the benefit of that they don't have to worry about the justice system. In many places the police can't arrest children under a certain age and have to let them go. Also, if they are caught, if they are in a gang, an older family member&amp;quot; will come up, rebuke them publicly, and most people will let it go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="an-ounce-of-preperation"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;An ounce of preperation...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a good idea to spend a little time and money getting a few things before you travel. Why? Cause here are the easiest targets in rough order of ease for thieves (1 is super-easy, 7 is merely easy):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backbacks without locks worn on the back. &lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt;: Don't put passports in your backback!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fanny pack or wallet in the back pocket.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grocery or store-purchase bag&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any outside-pocket cellphone holder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suitcases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wallet in the front pocket.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="don-t-be-stupid"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Don't be stupid&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least one travel writer advocates putting your stuff in a local grocery or store bag. That way you &amp;quot;fit in&amp;quot;, thieves ignore you, and you can confidently enjoy your visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;em&gt;mind-bogglingly stupid&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confidence means you allow yourself to be distracted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unless you live somewhere, you stand out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grocery or store bags are not designed to carry things for hours on end. They break.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grocery or store bags are one of the easiest target for thieves. They either don't close adequately or are the perfect target for razor armed thieves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="your-wallet"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Your wallet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take your ID out and only keep a very small amount of money in your wallet, which should be in your front pocket. Take the credit cards out and put them in secret stashes. If you really want a credit card in your wallet, get one linked to a bank account with just enough money for the day in it. Add more money to it as you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="shorten-the-straps"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Shorten the Straps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep the straps of your stuff short and in your hands. When walking next to a street, keep bags on the far side from the road. Moped thieves will will snatch and pull you until the straps break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="use-secret-stashes-on-your-person"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Use secret stashes on your person&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most sporting good stores sell money belts and underclothes pouches. Use the money belt to store cash. Use an underclothes pouch to store your passport and at least one credit card. For underclothes pouches I recommend you open packages and feel the material against your skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="consider-buying-anti-theft-backpacks-laptop-bags"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Consider buying anti-theft backpacks / laptop bags&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We prefer &lt;strong&gt;PacSafe&lt;/strong&gt; brand gear because the clasps are hidden and require a trick to open. Their stuff also has steel wire woven into their straps and fabric, meaning they can't get cut by a razor. PacSafe stuff isn't cheap but the peace of mind has been definitely worth the price. We've relied on the PacSafe &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Pacsafe-Metrosafe-Anti-Theft-Tablet-Laptop/dp/B00AVXDELI/?tag=cn-001-20"&gt;laptop bag&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Pacsafe-Luggage-Slingsafe-Shoulder-Black/dp/B006QLMDH0/?tag=cn-001-20"&gt;shoulder bag&lt;/a&gt; for about 18 months now and they've been awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="identifying-thief-tactics"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Identifying Thief Tactics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a successful thief requires the same skills as a magician. Observation, distraction, misdirection, staged audience members, and timing are how they do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some common techniques they use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-big-local-attraction"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Big Local Attraction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you are gazing at the masterpiece of architecture, hungrily peering at the door menu, or the incredible street performance, your focus is off your stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt;: Train yourself so when you start to feel distracted to put your arm or hand on your most expensive stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-magician"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Magician&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For reference, this is literally the same sort of sleight-of-hand that magicians use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pickpockets often have a newspaper, expensive jacket, or nice sweater in one hand to block what they are doing. While they engage you in friendly conversation they use the prop to block your like of sight from their other hand, which is busy. Especially good thieves don't even bother with the props and just rely on the width of their arm to block lines of observation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt;: If someone you don't know shows something up close to you, back off. In fact, just apologize and keep your distance. It's perfectly okay to not follow &amp;quot;local custom&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-spill"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Spill&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone throws anything at you, or if something is spilled on you, the thief helps you clean up, their accomplice is going through your stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt;: Back up and start screaming &amp;quot;Help, Thief&amp;quot; because it means you've been targeted and are under active scam. Cover your stuff with your arms and hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-fall"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Fall&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one is hard to deal with, especially for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a person falls or stumbles around you, don't help them, regardless of their age or apparent infirmity. While you help them their accomplice is taking from you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt;: Unless there is obvious injury, back off and let the locals take care of it, or find the police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-gift"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Gift&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year the new trick is for someone to ask you if you want them to take pictures of you using your camera or cell phone. You hand them your camera and they start running. &lt;em&gt;You've literally 'gifted' them your camera!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt;: Look for someone to take your picture, never the other way around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="your-room"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Your Room&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While staying at a hotel/hostel/BnB you go out for the day in a place without a safe. When you come back your valuables are gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt;: No safe? Carry your valuables!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="if-you-catch-a-thief"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;If you catch a thief&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You've caught them in the act. Maybe you've grabbed them or maybe they started running. Follow these steps to avoid injury and even death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="don-t-chase-thieves"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DON'T CHASE THIEVES&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever you do, don't chase thieves. Thieves of all ages are usually in gangs or have friends nearby. Their 'backup' carry weapons ranging from sticks to knives to guns. People die from chasing thieves every year in every country. Nothing you are carrying is worth your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="call-for-help"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Call for help&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how to yell &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;Help, Thief!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot; in the local language. Often the locals may deal with it as they hate thieves since crime damages their businesses and local reputation. In fact sometimes the response is overwhelmingly violent. There are stories of would-be victims in Africa, India, and Europe intervening to save the life of a would-be thief's life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-police"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Police&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's pretty universal police who deal with street crime wear uniforms. Work with them and if they ask you if you want to press charges, do so. Otherwise in many places they have to let the person go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="danger-the-undercover-police"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DANGER: The 'undercover' police&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone not wearing a uniform and claiming to be 'undercover' is an accomplice, scam artist, or worse. If they 'come to help':&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't give up any identification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demand that real police be summoned by radio or phone to this location immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't leave the spot!&lt;/strong&gt; If 'undercover' police try to get you to come with them, refuse loudly. If they try to force you away, start yelling as if your life is in danger, &lt;em&gt;because it is&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="in-closing"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;In Closing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theft is real. Go to Youtube and spent 10 minutes searching on &amp;quot;thief&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;pickpocket&amp;quot; for proof. Most of the videos are surveillance videos, but when magicians talk about theft it's pretty fun to watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, it's easy to dramatically decrease your chances of being a victim of this kind of crime by being prepared and vigilant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="djangocon"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="travel tips for geeks"></category></entry><entry><title>Off to Europe!</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/off-to-europe.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-20T09:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2013-04-20:off-to-europe.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I feel like I'm dreaming, but &lt;strong&gt;we're on our way to Europe!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey&lt;/a&gt; and I decided to move. While looking at possible rentals or even mortgages, we were idly (dreaming really... still paying off debts incurred from last year) looking at how much a room/apartment would cost to rent in Europe. To our surprise, we found a lot of good options that cost less then it would to pay monthly rent/mortgage in Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;o_O&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we discovered an amazing travel deal. It combined a very cheap red-eye flight from Los Angeles to Fort Lauderdale, and a slow trans-atlantic ship from Port Miami to Barcelona, about as much as a cheap hotel but with free food! If we avoid alcohol and any extra fees, it's actually extremely inexpensive. Being mostly disconnected from the internet would mean we could really focus on a couple of critical projects. If only we had a business justification for going to Europe...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It just so happens that we have business in Europe.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our plan is to spend a few months in Europe before returning back to the USA. We'll work hard on the ship, work hard when we arrive, and just get stuff done. It's not a vacation, but it is Europe, and there is such a thing as weekends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll be spending a few days in early May in Barcelona, then making our way to Poland for several weeks. Yes, we're attending &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://djangocircus.com"&gt;Django Circus&lt;/a&gt;, plus I want to investigate some family roots. After Poland, we're thinking either France, Italy, Hungary, England, Belgium, Scotland, Ireland, and other options. We'll see where the winds and affordable AirBNB places take us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When do we go back? Well, we plan to stay for at least two months. Even if we go back to the USA, we would have at least been in Europe for May and June. How cool is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We could have talked ourselves out of going. We nearly did. However, even with our workload this is the chance of a lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, for the next two weeks I'll only be able to access the internet for a few minutes per day. Please expect my responses to emails and tweets to be slower than normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; In the middle of all of this, I was invited to keynote Django Circus: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.djangocircus.com/post/48439600279/meet-daniel-greenfeld"&gt;http://blog.djangocircus.com/post/48439600279/meet-daniel-greenfeld&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="europe"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="djangocon"></category></entry><entry><title>Two Scoops of Django FAQ</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/two-scoops-django-faq-20130121.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-21T16:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2013-01-21:two-scoops-django-faq-20130121.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://django.2scoops.org/"&gt;&lt;img alt="https://s3.amazonaws.com/pydanny/frontispiece.png" class="align-center" id="two-scoops-of-django" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/pydanny/frontispiece.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;Two Scoops of Django: Best Practices for Django 1.5&lt;/a&gt; book has gone pretty well. The response has been almost entirely positive and sales have been pretty brisk. We've gotten a ton of great, constructive editorial feedback, which we're sorting through as we race towards the BETA release. Here are answers to the commonly asked questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="when-can-i-buy-the-book-via-paypal"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When can I buy the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; via PayPal?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will support PayPal in either the BETA or FINAL release of the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to handle PayPal we need to find a reputable e-publisher that supports it that gives us similar rates, customer service, and product control (updates at any time, uploads of PDF, no surprise charges, etc) as &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gumroad.com"&gt;Gumroad&lt;/a&gt;. If you know of an e-publisher who is willing to provide that same level of service, please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the record, we aren't leaving &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gumroad.com"&gt;Gumroad&lt;/a&gt;. We just want to support developers and students who don't have credit cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;note:&lt;/strong&gt; While we could certainly write our own publishing platform, that would delay work on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt;. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="when-can-i-get-a-kindle-mobi-or-epub-version"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When can I get a Kindle (mobi) or ePub version?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our plan is to support those formats in either the BETA or FINAL releases. In fact, I really love my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B007HCCNJU/?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=cn-001-20"&gt;Kindle&lt;/a&gt;. I can't wait to proof my own &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; on my favorite reading device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="when-can-i-get-a-print-version"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When can I get a print version?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope to have a print version in about 30 days. We need to ensure that the cover and layout actually looks nice, and that involves ordering copies from the Lulu, CreateSpace, whatever and reviewing them and making corrections. Then ordering again to make sure the corrections look okay. That simply takes a lot of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are hoping for a mid-February release. Also, keep in mind we aren't sure yet if we'll do a print version of anything but a FINAL release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="when-are-the-beta-and-final-releases"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When are the BETA and FINAL releases?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can't make promises, but at the latest, the FINAL &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be done by the start of March so people have them in hand at PyCon US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="is-this-book-going-to-get-updated"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is this book going to get updated?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, we've already sent out three minor updates for grammar and spelling issues, and some bug fixes.  Even after the FINAL version comes out, we'll continue to update the book. One of the advantages of self-published books is we have control of content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-much-work-went-into-the-book"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How much work went into the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey&lt;/a&gt; and I put in hundreds of hours writing and testing the content. We worked 12-16 hour days for weeks. It was madness, but a glorious madness. We became like hermits and toiled on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; while ignoring distractions like sleep, food and consistent exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our amazing technical reviewers also worked very hard to provide us with critical commentary, advice and corrections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="where-should-i-send-errata"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where should I send errata?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send errata to &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com"&gt;2scoops&amp;#64;cartwheelweb.com&lt;/a&gt;. The first person who reports an issue or makes a suggestion that we adopt will receive credit in the book. If not in the changelog, then in the dialogue of the book itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="are-you-going-to-pycon-us"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Are you going to PyCon US?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely! Wouldn't miss &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/"&gt;PyCon US&lt;/a&gt; for the world! &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey&lt;/a&gt; and I met and fell in love at PyCon US 2010! We'll be there for at least the second day of  tutorials, all the talks, and all the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/community/sprints/"&gt;sprints&lt;/a&gt;. I've even got a blog post coming that should serve as a guide for beginning Python and Django developers attending the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shameless Plug:&lt;/em&gt; We're both speaking and giving a tutorial. Sign up for the tutorial or attend our talks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="wiring-up-django-packages-tutorial"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/11/"&gt;Wiring Up Django Packages&lt;/a&gt; (Tutorial)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You just finished the Django tutorial. What do you do now? You wire in Django Packages! Django is part of an ecosphere of over 20,000 packages, which can be leveraged to great effect. This tutorial will teach the evaluation, use, and extension of third party Python and Django applications in your projects. This tutorial will be a lecture with a lot of detailed and annotated code examples. Instructors are &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey Roy&lt;/a&gt;, Daniel Greenfeld, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://brack3t.com/"&gt;Kenneth Love&lt;/a&gt; (of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gettingstartedwithdjango.com/"&gt;Getting Started with Django&lt;/a&gt; fame).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="advanced-django-forms-usage-talk"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/101/"&gt;Advanced Django Forms Usage&lt;/a&gt;  (Talk)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django forms are really powerful but there are edge cases, especially with class based views), that can cause a bit of anguish. This talk will go over how to handle many common solutions not currently described in the core documentation. It will also cover useful third-party libraries. Speaker is Daniel Greenfeld.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="using-python-to-generate-art-and-sound-talk"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/58/"&gt;Using Python To Generate Art And Sound&lt;/a&gt; (Talk)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trick to navigating the overwhelming Python audio/imaging landscape is understanding how the fundamentals work, using common data processing/visualization libraries, in-depth code samples, and simple math operations. I use the stdlib, NumPy, SciPy, Matplotlib, PIL, and PyCairo to create building blocks, which I then combine to demonstrate advanced sound and image generation techniques. Speaker is &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey Roy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="are-you-going-to-django-circus"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Are you going to Django Circus?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope so. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://2013.djangocon.eu/"&gt;Django Circus&lt;/a&gt;, a.k.a. DjangoCon Europe, is one of the important industry events for us and we're trying to figure out logistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our problem is that 2012 was a very hard year - the majority of our clients have not paid for the work that we did. Collecting is turning out to be extremely difficult, time consuming, and unpleasant. This is impacting everything we want to do in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-does-the-alpha-work"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How does the ALPHA work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ALPHA is a preview version that we are selling at an introductory price of $12. When you purchase the ALPHA, you get access to the BETA and FINAL versions when they are released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you're wondering, we are planning to increase the price of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; when we release the BETA and FINAL versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="twoscoops"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="audrey"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="djangocon"></category></entry><entry><title>Deadline for DjangoCon Financial Aid requests is tomorrow!</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/deadline-for-djangocon-financial-aid-requests-is-tomorrow.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-08-02T21:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2012-08-02:deadline-for-djangocon-financial-aid-requests-is-tomorrow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For 2012, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangocon.us/"&gt;DjangoCon US&lt;/a&gt; has moved to Washington, DC, and everyone is invited! If you need financial support to get there, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.djangoproject.com/foundation/"&gt;Django Software Foundation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pyladies.com/"&gt;PyLadies&lt;/a&gt; have paired with a number of forward thinking sponsors to help get you there. All genders are eligible for assistance, so don't hesitate to submit your application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deadline for financial aid requests is tomorrow, Friday, August 3rd by 11:59pm Eastern Time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/viewform?formkey=dDc1X2hrUGJVRGdEWnRjTklxR2tSNFE6MQ#gid=0"&gt;Apply while you still have time!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="django"></category><category term="djangocon"></category><category term="pyladies"></category><category term="dsf"></category></entry><entry><title>10 reasons to go to DjangoCon Europe</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/10-reasons-to-go-to-djangocon-europe.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-14T19:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2012-05-14:10-reasons-to-go-to-djangocon-europe.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;You should go to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://djangocon.eu"&gt;DjangoCon Europe&lt;/a&gt; in lovely &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zurich"&gt;Zurich&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Switzerland"&gt;Switzerland&lt;/a&gt;. Here are 10 reasons why:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="chocolate"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Chocolate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much of what we like about chocolate comes from Switzerland. For example, Milk Chocolate was invented in Switzerland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="keynote-speaker-jacob-kaplan-moss"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;Keynote speaker: Jacob Kaplan-Moss&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always a great speaker and fun to be around, he's one of the BDFL's of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://djangoproject.com"&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="cheese"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;Cheese&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up thinking that Swiss Cheese was just about holes. It's so much more. I can't wait to try fresh European cheese made by master craftsmen from the freshest ingredients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="keynote-speaker-jessica-mckellar"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. &lt;strong&gt;Keynote speaker: Jessica McKellar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a word, Jessica is &lt;strong&gt;incredible&lt;/strong&gt;. She's a Twisted core developer, PSF board member, part of the trio responsible for the gigantic Boston Python User Group's massive size explosion, and a talented speaker. She's used her incredible talents and skills to increase diversity in the community and generally help other people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="breakfast"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5. &lt;strong&gt;Breakfast&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Muesli was invented in Switzerland. I love Muesli. I was floored by how much better it was in New Zealand. I can't wait to try it in it's homeland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="web-site"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;6. &lt;strong&gt;Web Site&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DjangoCon Europe site is crazy. I mean, look at all those animations!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="talks"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;7. &lt;strong&gt;Talks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a single track event with proven speakers like Zachary Voase and Andrew Godwin, yet balances that with bringing in new blood to spice things up. And dare I say &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://2012.djangocon.eu/schedule/round-pegs-and-square-holes/"&gt;I'm giving a technical talk&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com/"&gt;Audrey Roy&lt;/a&gt;? ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="mountains"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;8. &lt;strong&gt;Mountains&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all the incredible food, you would think you would gain umpteen kilograms. Fortunately there are mountains all around to climb and hike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sprints"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;9. &lt;strong&gt;Sprints&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to sprint on Django itself? Look no further because there will be Django core developers around! There will also be notable &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://python.org"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; developers like &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kennethreitz.com/"&gt;Kenneth Reitz&lt;/a&gt; and others around working hard on a lot of different projects. It's going to intense and fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="castles"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;10. &lt;strong&gt;Castles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living in the USA, we just don't have anything like castles. DjangoCon Europe will be near a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_castles_and_fortresses_in_Switzerland#Zurich"&gt;small horde of stone fortifications&lt;/a&gt;. Which means if the Zombie Apocalypse happens during the conference, we'll have many secure places to go. They also make lovely tourist destinations. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-are-you-waiting-for"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What are you waiting for?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DjangoCon Europe has a cap on attendance. Tickets for Python events have been selling out, not just for PyCon US. Don't miss out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="it-s-all-about-me"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It's all about me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Call me selfish but I want you there because I haven't haven't met all our European friends yet in person. Hope to see you next month in Zurich!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="europe"></category><category term="djangocon"></category></entry><entry><title>Join us at DjangoCon Europe!</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/join-us-at-djangocon-europe.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-04-10T12:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2012-04-10:join-us-at-djangocon-europe.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year in June, the European edition of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://djangocon.eu"&gt;DjangoCon&lt;/a&gt; is going to be held in lovely &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zurich"&gt;Zurich&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Switzerland"&gt;Switzerland&lt;/a&gt;. It is my great fortune and delight to announce that &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey&lt;/a&gt; and I will be attending. Hooray!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, we're extremely excited. My &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dannygreenfeld.blogspot.com/search/label/ploneconf2007"&gt;trip to Europe in 2007&lt;/a&gt; was an amazingly fun and educational experience, and I can't wait to share a similar experience with Audrey. We can't wait to see all our old European friends, make new ones, and be dazzled by what Europe has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, let's face it, the conference is going to be &lt;strong&gt;incredible&lt;/strong&gt;. They've lined up some awesome venues, the food (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raclette"&gt;cheese&lt;/a&gt;, chocolate, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Muesli"&gt;muesli&lt;/a&gt;, etc) in Switzerland is world-renowned, the website looks fantastic, and they've got Jacob Kaplan-Moss to keynote. It looks so good I'm surprised there are any &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://2012.djangocon.eu/sponsors/"&gt;sponsor slots left&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="talks"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Talks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While attending the conference, we submitted and hope to give a presentation on the positives (speed, flexibility, community, etc) and negatives (a few) of using &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mongodb.org/"&gt;MongoDB&lt;/a&gt; as a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://djangoproject.com"&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; datastore. I'm also considering giving a second talk. Some ideas for that include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zen of Django&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django isn't for beginners (A Tredennick inspired talk explaining why teaching beginning developers Django isn't a good idea)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced Django Template Usage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced Django Models Usage (An intimidating talk to put together)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django Packages Thunderdome II&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I'm at it, I'm going to poke any prospective conference goers to submit their own talks. I love attending conference talks and at PyCon US this year I barely got to see any. Show me what you got!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/pydanny/1614703646/"&gt;&lt;img alt="http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2339/1614703646_2e2610162a.jpg" class="align-center" id="my-last-day-in-italy-back-in-2007-when-i-still-had-hair" src="http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2339/1614703646_2e2610162a.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="djangocon"></category><category term="mongodb"></category></entry></feed>