<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>pydanny</title><link href="http://pydanny.com" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pydanny.com/feeds/europe.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pydanny.com</id><updated>2012-05-14T19:30:00Z</updated><entry><title>10 reasons to go to DjangoCon Europe</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/10-reasons-to-go-to-djangocon-europe.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-14T19:30:00Z</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>http://pydanny.com/10-reasons-to-go-to-djangocon-europe.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;You should go to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://djangocon.eu"&gt;DjangoCon Europe&lt;/a&gt; in lovely &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zurich"&gt;Zurich&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Switzerland"&gt;Switzerland&lt;/a&gt;. Here are 10 reasons why:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chocolate&lt;/strong&gt;: So much of what we like about chocolate comes from Switzerland. For example, Milk Chocolate was invented in Switzerland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keynote speaker: Jacob Kaplan-Moss&lt;/strong&gt;: Always a great speaker and fun to be around, he's one of the BDFL's of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://djangoproject.com"&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cheese&lt;/strong&gt;: I grew up thinking that Swiss Cheese was just about holes. It's so much more. I can't wait to try fresh European cheese made by master craftsmen from the freshest ingredients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keynote speaker: Jessica McKellar&lt;/strong&gt;: In a word, Jessica is &lt;strong&gt;incredible&lt;/strong&gt;. She's a Twisted core developer, PSF board member, part of the trio responsible for the gigantic Boston Python User Group's massive size explosion, and a talented speaker. She's used her incredible talents and skills to increase diversity in the community and generally help other people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breakfast&lt;/strong&gt;: Muesli was invented in Switzerland. I love Muesli. I was floored by how much better it was in New Zealand. I can't wait to try it in it's homeland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web Site&lt;/strong&gt;: The DjangoCon Europe site is crazy. I mean, look at all those animations!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talks&lt;/strong&gt;: This is a single track event with proven speakers like Zachary Voase and Andrew Godwin, yet balances that with bringing in new blood to spice things up. And dare I say &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://2012.djangocon.eu/schedule/round-pegs-and-square-holes/"&gt;I'm giving a technical talk&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com/"&gt;Audrey Roy&lt;/a&gt;? ;-)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mountains&lt;/strong&gt;: With all the incredible food, you would think you would gain umpteen kilograms. Fortunately there are mountains all around to climb and hike.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sprints&lt;/strong&gt;: Want to sprint on Django itself? Look no further because there will be Django core developers around! There will also be notable &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://python.org"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; developers like &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kennethreitz.com/"&gt;Kenneth Reitz&lt;/a&gt; and others around working hard on a lot of different projects. It's going to intense and fun!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Castles&lt;/strong&gt;: Living in the USA, we just don't have anything like castles. DjangoCon Europe will be near a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_castles_and_fortresses_in_Switzerland#Zurich"&gt;small horde of stone fortifications&lt;/a&gt;. Which means if the Zombie Apocalypse happens during the conference, we'll have many secure places to go. They also make lovely tourist destinations. :-)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-are-you-waiting-for"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What are you waiting for?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DjangoCon Europe has a cap on attendance. Tickets for Python events have been selling out, not just for PyCon US. Don't miss out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="it-s-all-about-me"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It's all about me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yup. Call me selfish but I want you there because I haven't haven't met all our European friends yet in person. Hope to see you next month in Zurich!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="europe"></category><category term="djangocon"></category></entry></feed>