<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>pydanny</title><link href="https://pydanny.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pydanny.com/feeds/europe.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pydanny.com/</id><updated>2013-09-09T12:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Dynów 2013 Part I</title><link href="https://pydanny.com/dynow-2013-part-i.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-09T12:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:https://pydanny.com,2013-09-09:dynow-2013-part-i.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;note&lt;/strong&gt;: This is the first part in a series about a family research trip to Dynów, Poland in May 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was our second trip to Poland. Last year (2012) I went with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey&lt;/a&gt; in 2012 for a few days to present at a software conference called &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pl.pycon.org/"&gt;PyCon Poland&lt;/a&gt;. We stayed for a few days afterwards in the eerily familiar Krakow, always conscious that my family heritage was perhaps just hours away. You see, my mother and father's family come from Jews who emigrated to the USA respectively about 110 and 90 years ago. Unfortunately, for many reasons boiling down to time, resources, and contacts I held off from exploring my family roots, promising myself I would return one day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I was back in Poland, with both the time, resources, and contacts to make it possible to explore at least a portion of my family roots. This year I would get to research and visit where my grand-father's roots in south-eastern Poland. We blocked out some time, made various reservations, talked to family members such as my mother and Aunt Bernice (who &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kehilalinks.jewishgen.org/krosno/Krosnodubtrip.htm"&gt;wrote about her trip in 2006&lt;/a&gt;), and leaned heavily on the graces of close friends Tomasz 'Tomek' Paczkowski and Alexandra 'Ola' Sendecka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We knew we were in for an uphill battle researching the family. You can't just go to a computer and search. In fact, as of the summer of 2013 there isn't really a central database of information for Jewish ancestry - what exists is still under construction and rather incomplete. That means you have to go and look at old documents yourself, which are incomplete and hard to find. You see, over the decades various documents have been destroyed by accident or war, meaning that the old property/census/tax documents are either incomplete or broken up into parts seperated by hours of travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting to Dynów was a matter of renting a car and having Tomasz drive us from Krakow. Most of it was on a pretty new highway and we zipped along at a rapid pace. Once we got to Rzeszow and the highway ended, we were on the winding country roads that make up most of Poland. While unbelievably scenic, the country roads make Poland feel much larger than it seems; explaining why we would not be able to accomodate the requests from various family members and friends in the USA to visit the villages of their ancestors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More about the trip is forthcoming later in the series. In the meantime, here are some things still being edited:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/pydanny/sets/72157635453007448/"&gt;Photos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/pydanny/dynow-trip-2013"&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="europe"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="travel tips for geeks"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="friends"></category><category term="audrey"></category></entry><entry><title>Off to Europe!</title><link href="https://pydanny.com/off-to-europe.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-20T09:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:https://pydanny.com,2013-04-20:off-to-europe.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I feel like I'm dreaming, but &lt;strong&gt;we're on our way to Europe!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey&lt;/a&gt; and I decided to move. While looking at possible rentals or even mortgages, we were idly (dreaming really... still paying off debts incurred from last year) looking at how much a room/apartment would cost to rent in Europe. To our surprise, we found a lot of good options that cost less then it would to pay monthly rent/mortgage in Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;o_O&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we discovered an amazing travel deal. It combined a very cheap red-eye flight from Los Angeles to Fort Lauderdale, and a slow trans-atlantic ship from Port Miami to Barcelona, about as much as a cheap hotel but with free food! If we avoid alcohol and any extra fees, it's actually extremely inexpensive. Being mostly disconnected from the internet would mean we could really focus on a couple of critical projects. If only we had a business justification for going to Europe...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It just so happens that we have business in Europe.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our plan is to spend a few months in Europe before returning back to the USA. We'll work hard on the ship, work hard when we arrive, and just get stuff done. It's not a vacation, but it is Europe, and there is such a thing as weekends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll be spending a few days in early May in Barcelona, then making our way to Poland for several weeks. Yes, we're attending &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://djangocircus.com"&gt;Django Circus&lt;/a&gt;, plus I want to investigate some family roots. After Poland, we're thinking either France, Italy, Hungary, England, Belgium, Scotland, Ireland, and other options. We'll see where the winds and affordable AirBNB places take us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When do we go back? Well, we plan to stay for at least two months. Even if we go back to the USA, we would have at least been in Europe for May and June. How cool is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We could have talked ourselves out of going. We nearly did. However, even with our workload this is the chance of a lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, for the next two weeks I'll only be able to access the internet for a few minutes per day. Please expect my responses to emails and tweets to be slower than normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; In the middle of all of this, I was invited to keynote Django Circus: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.djangocircus.com/post/48439600279/meet-daniel-greenfeld"&gt;http://blog.djangocircus.com/post/48439600279/meet-daniel-greenfeld&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="europe"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="djangocon"></category></entry><entry><title>10 reasons to go to DjangoCon Europe</title><link href="https://pydanny.com/10-reasons-to-go-to-djangocon-europe.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-14T19:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Roy-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:https://pydanny.com,2012-05-14:10-reasons-to-go-to-djangocon-europe.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;You should go to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://djangocon.eu"&gt;DjangoCon Europe&lt;/a&gt; in lovely &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zurich"&gt;Zurich&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Switzerland"&gt;Switzerland&lt;/a&gt;. Here are 10 reasons why:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="chocolate"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Chocolate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much of what we like about chocolate comes from Switzerland. For example, Milk Chocolate was invented in Switzerland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="keynote-speaker-jacob-kaplan-moss"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;Keynote speaker: Jacob Kaplan-Moss&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always a great speaker and fun to be around, he's one of the BDFL's of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://djangoproject.com"&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="cheese"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;Cheese&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up thinking that Swiss Cheese was just about holes. It's so much more. I can't wait to try fresh European cheese made by master craftsmen from the freshest ingredients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="keynote-speaker-jessica-mckellar"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. &lt;strong&gt;Keynote speaker: Jessica McKellar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a word, Jessica is &lt;strong&gt;incredible&lt;/strong&gt;. She's a Twisted core developer, PSF board member, part of the trio responsible for the gigantic Boston Python User Group's massive size explosion, and a talented speaker. She's used her incredible talents and skills to increase diversity in the community and generally help other people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="breakfast"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5. &lt;strong&gt;Breakfast&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Muesli was invented in Switzerland. I love Muesli. I was floored by how much better it was in New Zealand. I can't wait to try it in it's homeland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="web-site"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;6. &lt;strong&gt;Web Site&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DjangoCon Europe site is crazy. I mean, look at all those animations!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="talks"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;7. &lt;strong&gt;Talks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a single track event with proven speakers like Zachary Voase and Andrew Godwin, yet balances that with bringing in new blood to spice things up. And dare I say &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://2012.djangocon.eu/schedule/round-pegs-and-square-holes/"&gt;I'm giving a technical talk&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com/"&gt;Audrey Roy&lt;/a&gt;? ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="mountains"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;8. &lt;strong&gt;Mountains&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all the incredible food, you would think you would gain umpteen kilograms. Fortunately there are mountains all around to climb and hike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sprints"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;9. &lt;strong&gt;Sprints&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to sprint on Django itself? Look no further because there will be Django core developers around! There will also be notable &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://python.org"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; developers like &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kennethreitz.com/"&gt;Kenneth Reitz&lt;/a&gt; and others around working hard on a lot of different projects. It's going to intense and fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="castles"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;10. &lt;strong&gt;Castles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living in the USA, we just don't have anything like castles. DjangoCon Europe will be near a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_castles_and_fortresses_in_Switzerland#Zurich"&gt;small horde of stone fortifications&lt;/a&gt;. Which means if the Zombie Apocalypse happens during the conference, we'll have many secure places to go. They also make lovely tourist destinations. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-are-you-waiting-for"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What are you waiting for?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DjangoCon Europe has a cap on attendance. Tickets for Python events have been selling out, not just for PyCon US. Don't miss out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="it-s-all-about-me"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It's all about me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Call me selfish but I want you there because I haven't haven't met all our European friends yet in person. Hope to see you next month in Zurich!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="europe"></category><category term="djangocon"></category></entry></feed>