<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>pydanny</title><link href="http://pydanny.github.com" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pydanny.github.com/feeds/open-comparison.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pydanny.github.com</id><updated>2012-03-28T11:30:00Z</updated><entry><title>Calendar About Nothing</title><link href="http://pydanny.github.com/calendar-about-nothing.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-28T11:30:00Z</updated><author><name>Daniel Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.github.com,2012-03-28:/calendar-about-nothing.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On October 16th, 2011, which was one hundred and sixty-four days before today I resolved to get myself onto the Longest Streak list of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://calendaraboutnothing.com/"&gt;Calendar About Nothing&lt;/a&gt;. Today, with this blog post, I've managed to do just that - get on the Longest Streaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calendar About Nothing tracks your open project commits on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://github.com"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. It tallies your total number of days, records your longest streak, and lets you compare yourself against other committers. The idea comes from an &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lifehacker.com/281626/jerry-seinfelds-productivity-secret?tag=softwaremotivation"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; where Jerry Seinfeld says his secret to productivity is to get something done every day, because if you skip one day then skipping another day is easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-feel-a-great-sense-of-accomplishment"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I feel a great sense of accomplishment.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The majority of those days I would like to think I did real commits. I pledged to myself to do more than just white space tweaks or write a script to do the work for me. I wanted to accomplish things and make a difference. I started projects, wrote code, cleaned up old code, added tests, documented a lot, and moved my blog here. It's been an awesome time, and keeping my fingers constantly in projects has been eye opening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-feel-a-great-sense-of-relief"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I feel a great sense of relief.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've really enjoyed this but there were days it was hard to get to the internet or days I was busy on other things. I discovered early on my phone was not a good interface with Github's text editor. Some days I had no desire to code or lacked the creativity to write. Then I remembered that my ability to work openly on Github is a gift, and I should just do it. Now I can relax a bit and if I miss a day, it's not such a big deal. I've made it to the Longest Streak list!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-long-a-streak"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How long a streak?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll see what happens now. I just feel happy that I've captured the moment and made my mark on the board. I invite you to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="open-comparison"></category></entry></feed>