<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>pydanny</title><link href="http://pydanny.com" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pydanny.com/feeds/pycon.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pydanny.com</id><updated>2012-06-01T12:00:00Z</updated><entry><title>Announcing PyCon Philippines!</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/announcing-pycon-philippines.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-06-01T12:00:00Z</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>http://pydanny.com/announcing-pycon-philippines.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ph.pycon.org"&gt;PyCon Philippines&lt;/a&gt;, set to occur on &lt;strong&gt;June 30&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ph.pycon.org"&gt;http://ph.pycon.org&lt;/a&gt;, is the first Python programming conference held in the Philippines. PyCon is a volunteer run effort that brings together Python developers from a variety of backgrounds and skill levels into a friendly, cooperative environment in order to educate, inspire, and work together - building relationships that transcend the event and can turn into lifelong friendships or even very impressive business alliances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This event is possible due to the hard work and contributions of members of the Manila Python users group, the support of the Python Software Foundation, various members of the Python community, our gracious sponsors, and many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be there, along with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey Roy&lt;/a&gt; and Django core developer &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/malcolmt"&gt;Malcolm Tredinnick&lt;/a&gt;. Hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-is-python"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is Python?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://python.org"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; is an open source programming language used for science, engineering, robotics, entertainment, web development, and more. It is used by organizations such as Google, NASA, Instagram, Pinterest, Mozilla, Walt Disney Animation Studios, WETA Digital, and many more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="interested-in-attending"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Interested in attending?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then head to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ph.pycon.org/register.html"&gt;registration page&lt;/a&gt;. The early bird discount ends on June 15th, so buy your tickets now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="interested-in-sponsoring"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Interested in sponsoring?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please go to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ph.pycon.org/sponsor.html"&gt;sponsorship page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your sponsorship would go a long way towards making PyCon Philippines 2012 a memorable event. As this is an entirely volunteer-run event, 100% of funds go toward actual event costs: food, drinks, chairs, tables, signage, nametags, flyers, advertising, etc. Per custom with PyCons around the world, the organizers receive no payment for their efforts, and any funds left over will be either placed in a Philippine based non-profit corporation or donated back to the Python Software Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://ph.pycon.org"&gt;&lt;img alt="http://ph.pycon.org/images/phpug.png" class="align-center" id="pycon-philippines-logo" src="http://ph.pycon.org/images/phpug.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="philippines"></category><category term="pycon"></category></entry><entry><title>Launching our API at PyCon 2012</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/launching-our-api-at-pycon-2012.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-09T07:30:00Z</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>http://pydanny.com/launching-our-api-at-pycon-2012.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few months ago me and my fiancee, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey Roy&lt;/a&gt;, launched our start up, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://consumernotebook.com"&gt;Consumer Notebook&lt;/a&gt;. It's a Python powered product comparison site that combines the best features of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opencomparison.org"&gt;Open Comparison&lt;/a&gt;, Yelp, Consumer Reports, and Pinterest. We've worked day and night to make it better, with countless members of the Python community using the site and giving us invaluable feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of that brings us to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://us.pycon.org/2012/"&gt;PyCon&lt;/a&gt;. We're not just here as attendees and participants, but also to promote our startup.  It used to be the cool thing to launch your startup at SXSW, but times have changed. Now it's the cool thing to launch at PyCon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Twilio, Twitter, Facebook, and Google, we've got an &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://api.consumernotebook.com"&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; we want developers to use. And as an upcoming startup, we've got to really be creative in how we gain your attention, so here is what we're doing for PyCon 2012:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="demos-at-our-pycon-startup-row-booth"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Demos at our &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/community/openspaces/capoeira/"&gt;PyCon Startup Row&lt;/a&gt; booth.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks PyCon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've got a booth on Saturday. We've got banners and bright red track jackets. We're giving out handy API reference cards, as well as 10 different &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://consumernotebook.com/lists/audreyr/list-of-oreo-cookie-flavors/"&gt;flavors of Oreo cookies&lt;/a&gt; (see our site for a complete list of every Oreo cookie flavor, by the way).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So stop on by, sign up for the BETA, have a cookie, and talk to us about our API. For that matter, feel free to talk to me or Audrey about the API any time you see us. We're wearing bright red jackets with '&lt;strong&gt;Ask me about our API&lt;/strong&gt;' on our back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the API, the next item on our plan is...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="a-big-kickoff-api-contest"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. A big kickoff API contest.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've put together the Consumer Notebook &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://api.consumernotebook.com"&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;, which lets you get product list
and comparison data out of our site via a simple REST interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're kicking off our PyCon 2012 API launch with an &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://developers.consumernotebook.com/contest.html"&gt;API contest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have from now until April 22 to find new and exciting ways to use our &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://api.consumernotebook.com"&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;. If you win we'll give you a Kindle Fire or equivalent gift certificate valid in your nation of origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://developers.consumernotebook.com/contest.html"&gt;API Contest Details&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/pydanny/6821231296/sizes/m/in/photostream/"&gt;&lt;img alt="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7189/6821231296_d0670e84b7_m.jpg" class="align-center" id="grid-of-python-books" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7189/6821231296_d0670e84b7_m.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="we-re-hosting-the-saturday-night-pycon-capoeira-open-space"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. We're hosting the Saturday night &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/community/openspaces/capoeira/"&gt;PyCon Capoeira Open Space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to see some awesome Capoeira moves? Want to learn some of the basics? Want to just have fun?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've hired professional Hollywood stuntman and Capoeira instructor to the stars, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://valleycapoeira.com/?page_id=7"&gt;Contra Mestre Xingu&lt;/a&gt;, to come up from Los Angeles to lead this event. In addition to appearing in movies, videos, and commercials, he's got first hand experience with snakes. In his own words:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capoeira saved my life. What? How? Well it was a sunny afternoon, I was shooting a film in the Hollywood hills off Coldwater Canyon at a house. I was running back to set from the bathroom and out of nowhere a rattlesnake jumped up from the ground and tried to bite me. I quickly jumped out of the way and did a fast negative &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_capoeira_techniques#Rol.C3.AA"&gt;rolé&lt;/a&gt; away from the snake. Then I called the other people on set and we caught it. I really didn't think much of it afterwards until after the shoot. My friend told me the rattlesnake was a young one and I'm lucky I didn't get bitten.  When a younger rattler bites you, it usually unloads all of it's venom in you because it cannot control the amount it releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&amp;mdash;Contra Mestre Xingu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over 30 people have signed up up for this event, including Python core developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
When: Saturday, 8pm - 10pm
What to bring: Camera!
What to bring if you are participating: Workout clothes, water bottle
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/pydanny/6821195620/sizes/s/in/photostream/"&gt;&lt;img alt="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7182/6821195620_2b7870a39c_m.jpg" class="align-center" id="location-of-the-pycon-capoeira-open-space-event" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7182/6821195620_2b7870a39c_m.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location: The PyCon upstairs central open space&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you around!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="OAuth"></category><category term="api"></category><category term="Consumer-Notebook"></category><category term="pycon"></category></entry><entry><title>PyCon Australia 2011 Review</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/pycon-australia-2011-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-24T12:45:00Z</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>http://pydanny.com/pycon-australia-2011-review.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In June of 2011 I had the good fortune of having my then girlfriend, Audrey Roy, now fiancee, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.blogspot.com/2011/06/im-going-to-pycon-australia.html"&gt;invited to present a keynote speech at PyCon Australia 2011&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was terribly excited for her to get that invitation, and that excitement was compounded when they allowed me to present on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/pydanny/confessions-of-a-joe-developer`:"&gt;Confessions of Joe Developer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travel is a passion of mine, and it's only been since 2007 that I've gotten a chance to do much seeing of the world. Australia was always this distant goal of mine, but I never thought I would get the chance to go. Fortunately, my assumption was wrong and we landed on August 18th in Sydney, Australia!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audrey &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreyr.posterous.com/thank-you-pycon-au"&gt;wrote her own statement about the event&lt;/a&gt; right after we were done. She's good that way. Okay then, off to my own review. This is belated, but better late then never, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conference-rooms"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conference Rooms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sydney Masonic Center was the venue and it was a really curious building. They built it a while ago, then apparently grafted an office building onto the top of the temple. &lt;strong&gt;You have to see it to believe it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main temple room was room, interesting, and fun. The acoustics, to my limited ear, seemed quite good. The alternative rooms for some of the tracks were small presentation rooms, which did quite nicely except when the organizers chose popular talks for small rooms and things overflowed. Everyone was good natured about that and we all just worked it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result: Great&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="speakers"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Speakers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm partial but I think the opening keynote by Audrey Roy about diversity was wonderful. Mary Gardinar also talk about open source projects trying to change the world that need our support. Raymond Hettiger seriously delivered the goods with another version of his amazing talk about what makes Python great. Whatever you do, go and see it as many times as possible because he changes it each and every time.  Richard Jones' presentation on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny-event-notes.readthedocs.org/en/latest/PyconAU2011/zen_of_python.html"&gt;Zen of Python&lt;/a&gt; was very solid too, and I'll use this as an opportunity to promote my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pypi.python.org/pypi/that"&gt;Anti-Zen of Python&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it came time for me to present on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/pydanny/confessions-of-a-joe-developer`:"&gt;Confessions of Joe Developer&lt;/a&gt;, I finished way too early; plus me and Audrey felt the talk was not technical enough. Even though the reception for my talk was very positive, based on that experience and observation we ramped up the technical content for DjangoCon US and I delivered a much stronger talk. I want to thank the Australian Python community for being a wonderful audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny-event-notes.readthedocs.org/en/latest/PyconAU2011/index.html"&gt;rest of the talks I saw were all quite good&lt;/a&gt;, in fact the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny-event-notes.readthedocs.org/en/latest/PyconAU2011/decorators.html"&gt;one on decorators&lt;/a&gt; was incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result: Super&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conference-meals"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conference Meals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The night before the conference, Frends/mentors Russell Keith-Magee and Malcolm Tredennick took me to a sushi-train place and we gobbled down some very nice raw seafood. Call me silly, but sushi on moving plates just tastes better! Thanks guys!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In between talks they served nice little sandwiches. The coffee bar had lovely Flat Whites and considering the quality of dairy in Australia I was very happy with the break food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first night of the conference they served an amazing, amazing meal. The lamb was like nothing I've tasted before - my best way of describing it was &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;so this is how lamb is supposed to taste&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot;. We also got served Pavlova, which Audrey really enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last evening of the conference we went out to a famous Sydney gastropub/brewery and got kangaroo and crocodile pizza. The kangaroo was outstanding, but the alligator wasn't my thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the conference we went with Graham Dumpleton to a wonderful Dim Sum place and I stuffed myself silly while Audrey quizzed Graham on WSGI. I was sleepy for the rest of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pounds gained? Many.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result: Superb&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="parties"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Parties&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were some lovely dinners and hang-outs. It was incredible putting faces to names and personalities. Everyone looked as I imagined, which meant they looked smashing. Events tended to be lower key, which can make for some wonderfully nice, cozy conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result: Good&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="accomodations"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Accomodations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was no official conference hotel so we stayed at World Hotel - in easy walking distance of the conference center. It wasn't cheap, but I've learned from painful experience that when you travel to a conference, you want to spend your time at the conference, not going to-and-from a cheap hotel five miles away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The staff of the hotel were very nice and helpful. Unfortunately they were working around the limitations of their building. The rooms were really tiny and rather stuffy. Normally that isn't an issue since we spend a lot of our time outside the room, but in this case Audrey was polishing her talk and needed a quiet room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result: Average but not the fault of the conference&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sprints"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sprints&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked with Richard Jones about PyPI authentication issues, and he decided to go with OpenID. Personally, I would prefer OAUTH but I'll take whatever I can get. On the behalf of the community Mark Rees implemented OpenID on PyPI at the sprint so things like &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opencomparison.org"&gt;http://opencomparison.org&lt;/a&gt; can support the community better. One goal at PyCon 2012 is to get that working as another authentication system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise I closed bugs and worked lintification of the project. Audrey and a couple Australian PyLadies, Elena Williams and Jenny Nguyen, worked some core Django documentation tickets. We didn't get as much done as we hoped thanks to an outside distraction, but the organization of the sprints was top-notch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the sprint, those crazy Australians taught us how to do a &lt;strong&gt;Tim Tam Slam&lt;/strong&gt;. It's rather scary and not for the faint of heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result: Great&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="overall-result"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overall Result&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conference was run professionally. The leadership was on the ball. The few issues that cropped up were taken care of, certainly better then what I would have done. Thank you everyone who put it together or just gave us a great time: Tim Ansell, Richard Jones, Nick Coghlan, Russell Keith McGee, Graham Dumpleton, Malcolm Tredennick and many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Australia was amazing. The people were wonderful. I wish we had more time to go sightseeing and relax, but we were off all too quickly. I could write a book about the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Combined Result: Great&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="audrey"></category><category term="australia"></category><category term="review"></category></entry><entry><title>My PyCon 2012 Schedule</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/my-pycon-2012-schedule.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-22T09:00:00Z</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>http://pydanny.com/my-pycon-2012-schedule.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here I was thinking that this year's PyCon wasn't going to be so busy because I didn't submit a talk or tutorial. Ha! What the heck was I thinking?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what I've already got in the works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="wednesday-march-7th"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wednesday, March 7th&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me and Audrey are driving up from Los Angeles. I've wanted to do this drive for a while, so this is very exciting. We'll arrive in the evening and hopefully tag up with friends old and new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="thursday-march-8th"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thursday, March 8th&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm moderating the Code Reuse panel of the Python Web Summit. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.google.com/moderator/#15/e=1c9a94&amp;amp;t=1c9a94.43"&gt;Have you submitted a question yet&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening we'll be helping assemble bags for the conference. That's always a blast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="friday-march-9th"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Friday, March 9th&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon really begins! I'll be at the keynotes, and then the talks begin. These are some of the talks I'm really leaning towards watching:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/64/"&gt;Introduction to Metaclasses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/399/"&gt;The Art of Subclassing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/249/"&gt;Data, Design, Meaning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/246/"&gt;Code Generation in Python: Dismantling Jinja&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem, of course, is that all the talks look awesome. Missing some of these talks is going to hurt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening we're going to the New Relic/Loggly/Skull Candy party and hang out at the (in)famous TIP BOF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="saturday-march-10th"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Saturday, March 10th&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be at the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://consumernotebook.com"&gt;Consumer Notebook&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pycon.blogspot.com/2012/02/startup-row-winners-for-pycon-2012.html"&gt;Startup Row&lt;/a&gt; booth all day! Come and hang out with us and all the other bright, new companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening I'm hosting the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/community/openspaces/capoeira/"&gt;PyCon Capoeira Open Space&lt;/a&gt;. We've got a seriously large room assigned for the event, and over twenty five people currently signed up to participate (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bit.ly/pycon-capoeira"&gt;there's still room for signups&lt;/a&gt;). Even if you don't want to play a musical instrument or learn/play at Capoeira, come anyway to watch. Some of the players there have some seriously amazing skills - I can assure you've seen them in the movies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sunday-march-11th"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sunday, March 11th&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More talks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/482/"&gt;Transifex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/301/"&gt;Sketching a better product&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/66/"&gt;Building A Python-Based Search Engine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/168/"&gt;Diversity in practice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="monday-march-12-thursday-march-15"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Monday March 12 - Thursday, March 15&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sprints! Nothing set in stone yet, but some ideas I've had include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launch python.opencomparison.org for all of Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenComparison integration of PyPI OpenID, SourceForge OAUTH, and BitBucket OAUTH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved OpenComparison integration of the Launchpad API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement Gitorious API for OpenComparison.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement Text Based search for OpenComparison.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hack on Mongo related technologies such as django-mongonaut and some other planned projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/"&gt;&lt;img border="0" height="102" width="277" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-fa4jnLXs1so/TniyemLkoiI/AAAAAAAAAqo/LjZqklTFBXk/s400/pycon2012.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="consumernotebook"></category><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>Selected for PyCon StartUp Row</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/selected-for-pycon-startup-row.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-21T01:00:00Z</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>http://pydanny.com/selected-for-pycon-startup-row.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Me and Audrey have been working hard on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://consumernotebook.com"&gt;Consumer Notebook&lt;/a&gt;, a Python/Django based project. We submitted it to PyCon StartUp row and found out this morning we've been accepted. &lt;strong&gt;Hooray!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pycon.blogspot.com/2012/02/startup-row-winners-for-pycon-2012.html"&gt;PyCon StartUp Row winner's post&lt;/a&gt;, here is a little bit of what we're about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="highlights"&gt;
Have you tried researching products online recently? Search engines are gamed by scammy marketers. Product review sites overwhelm you with ads, have unreliable reviews, or dryly compare raw product specs. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://consumernotebook.com"&gt;Consumer Notebook&lt;/a&gt; is working to solve this problem. It is like Yelp for products, with product comparison grids inspired by the founders' open-source work on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://djangopackages.com"&gt;Django Packages&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opencomparison.org"&gt;Open Comparison&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just so you know, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://us.pycon.org"&gt;PyCon&lt;/a&gt; in North America is the biggest gathering for the international Python community. The conference this year is in Santa Clara, California, and is sold-out at 1500+ attendees, but could have easily sold out several times that number. The talks, tutorials, and events are going to be incredible, and I'm delighted to be part of the PyCon experience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to sharing the StartUp Row with friends like Transifex, Python Packages, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.weddinglovely.com/"&gt;Wedding Lovely&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please check out &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://consumernotebook.com"&gt;Consumer Notebook&lt;/a&gt; right now and also visit our PyCon booth on Saturday, March 10th and we'll show you what we're doing.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="audrey"></category><category term="consumernotebook"></category><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>Two years ago today</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/two-years-ago-today.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-17T09:20:00Z</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>http://pydanny.com/two-years-ago-today.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://us.pycon.org"&gt;PyCon&lt;/a&gt; tutorial on Django in Depth was ending. I had been sitting next to my friend &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://djangrrl.com/"&gt;Barbara&lt;/a&gt; and we got up to go when I heard a feminine voice ask: &amp;quot;Are you &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/bshaurette"&gt;bshaurette&lt;/a&gt;?&amp;quot; I turned and it was like I got punched in the gut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the first time I met &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey&lt;/a&gt;. I remember every detail of how she looked at that moment. The clothes she was wearing, the part in her hair, that her eyes met mine, and that they didn't turn away. I was immediately captivating, but fortunately remembered to act like a gentleman. I tossed in a casual invitation to her to join us for lunch, which I pulled off even though my heart was pounding. Thankfully she accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life has been pretty much awesome ever since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the day I met the love of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pycon"></category><category term="audrey"></category></entry></feed>