<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>pydanny</title><link href="http://pydanny.github.com" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pydanny.github.com/feeds/pycon.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pydanny.github.com</id><updated>2012-02-21T01:00:00Z</updated><entry><title>Selected for PyCon StartUp Row</title><link href="http://pydanny.github.com/selected-for-pycon-startup-row.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-21T01:00:00Z</updated><author><name>Daniel Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.github.com,2012-02-21:/selected-for-pycon-startup-row.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Me and Audrey have been working hard on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://consumernotebook.com"&gt;Consumer Notebook&lt;/a&gt;, a Python/Django based project. We submitted it to PyCon StartUp row and found out this morning we've been accepted. &lt;strong&gt;Hooray!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pycon.blogspot.com/2012/02/startup-row-winners-for-pycon-2012.html"&gt;PyCon StartUp Row winner's post&lt;/a&gt;, here is a little bit of what we're about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="highlights"&gt;
Have you tried researching products online recently? Search engines are gamed by scammy marketers. Product review sites overwhelm you with ads, have unreliable reviews, or dryly compare raw product specs. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://consumernotebook.com"&gt;Consumer Notebook&lt;/a&gt; is working to solve this problem. It is like Yelp for products, with product comparison grids inspired by the founders' open-source work on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://djangopackages.com"&gt;Django Packages&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opencomparison.org"&gt;Open Comparison&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just so you know, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://us.pycon.org"&gt;PyCon&lt;/a&gt; in North America is the biggest gathering for the international Python community. The conference this year is in Santa Clara, California, and is sold-out at 1500+ attendees, but could have easily sold out several times that number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to sharing the StartUp Row with friends like Transifex, Python Packages, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.weddinglovely.com/"&gt;Wedding Lovely&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please check out &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://consumernotebook.com"&gt;Consumer Notebook&lt;/a&gt; right now and also visit our PyCon booth on Saturday, March 10th and we'll show you what we're doing.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="audrey"></category><category term="consumernotebook"></category><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>Two years ago today</title><link href="http://pydanny.github.com/two-years-ago-today.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-17T09:20:00Z</updated><author><name>Daniel Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.github.com,2012-02-17:/two-years-ago-today.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://us.pycon.org"&gt;PyCon&lt;/a&gt; tutorial on Django in Depth was ending. I had been sitting next to my friend &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://djangrrl.com/"&gt;Barbara&lt;/a&gt; and we got up to go when I heard a feminine voice ask: &amp;quot;Are you &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/bshaurette"&gt;bshaurette&lt;/a&gt;?&amp;quot; I turned and it was like I got punched in the gut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the first time I met &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey&lt;/a&gt;. I remember every detail of how she looked at that moment. The clothes she was wearing, the part in her hair, that her eyes met mine, and that they didn't turn away. I was immediately captivating, but fortunately remembered to act like a gentleman. I tossed in a casual invitation to her to join us for lunch, which I pulled off even though my heart was pounding. Thankfully she accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life has been pretty much awesome ever since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the day I met the love of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pycon"></category><category term="audrey"></category></entry></feed>