<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>pydanny</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pydanny.com/feeds/pycon-2013-guide.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pydanny.com/</id><updated>2013-03-10T23:50:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Beginner's Guide to PyCon 2013 Part III</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/beginners-guide-pycon-2013-part-3.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-10T23:50:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2013-03-10:beginners-guide-pycon-2013-part-3.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is Part III in a series of blog posts about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/"&gt;PyCon US 2013&lt;/a&gt;. The goal is to provide a handy reference guide for first time attendees of the world's largest &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://python.org"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; conference.  &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.com/beginners-guide-pycon-2013-part-1.html"&gt;Part I&lt;/a&gt; was mostly about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/tutorials/"&gt;tutorials&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.com/beginners-guide-pycon-2013-part-2.html"&gt;Part II&lt;/a&gt; was mostly about the first day of talks, this third post in the series will be about the second day of talks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="early-saturday-morning"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Early Saturday Morning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/5k/"&gt;PyCon 5K Charity Fun Run&lt;/a&gt; begins at 7 AM. Registration for this event is seperate from PyCon, and all proceeds go to the John Hunter Memorial Fund and the American Cancer Society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="saturday-morning"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Saturday Morning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After breakfast ends at 8:30 am, don't miss 30 minutes of lightning talks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then get ready as noted Python experts and proven speakers Jessica McKellar and Raymond Hettiger deliver keynotes to remember. They've changed communities and lives with the speeches given around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="am-talks"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;10:50 AM talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/83/"&gt;Getting started with automated testing&lt;/a&gt; (Carl Meyer) - This talk will get you moving into good test automation practices, and is presented by one of the maintainers of Django, pip, and virtualenv.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/129/"&gt;5 powerful pyramid features&lt;/a&gt; (Carlos de la Guardia) - Pyramid is a minimalist, modular web framework that encourages excellent coding patterns. Carlos will give you a tour of some of the great features that makes this such a powerful tool for application development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/120/"&gt;So Easy You Can Even Do It in JavaScript: Event-Driven Architecture for Regular Programmers&lt;/a&gt; (Glyph) - Asynchronous frameworks are said to be the new hotness, but Python's Twisted framework has been around for over 11 years. The creator of the project isn't just a master developer, but an illuminating speaker capable of explaining the most sophisticated concepts in a beginner friendly way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id1"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;11:30 AM talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/75/"&gt;Who’s there? - Home Automation with Arduino/RaspberryPi&lt;/a&gt; (Rupa Dachere) - Automate your home with Python! Learn how to use a Arduino or RaspberryPi to notify you by SMS that packages have arrived.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/41/"&gt;Copyright and You&lt;/a&gt; (Frank Siler) - Using and writing open source software involves a basic understanding of licensing and understanding of copyright law. The presenter, a licensed attorney, will cover the fundamentals needed to work safely in the open source world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/104/"&gt;Scaling community diversity outreach&lt;/a&gt; (Asheesh Laroia, Jessica McKellar, Dana Bauer, Daniel Choi) - Leaders of community groups around the USA will explain how they get people of all backgrounds not just coding, but helping each other in order to grow the diversity of the technical community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pm-talks"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;12:10 PM talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/114/"&gt;Why you should use Python 3 for text processing&lt;/a&gt; (David Mertz) - The presenter literally wrote the book on text processing using Python (many of his techniques have since made their way into core Python). In this often technical talk he explains why Python 3 is the tool you should be using.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/42/"&gt;What teachers really need from us&lt;/a&gt; (Selena Deckelman) - Noted speaker and developer, Selena Deckelman, explains what the what the Python community can do to help K-12 teachers need to forward programming education.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="saturday-lunch-12-40-pm"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Saturday Lunch (12:40 PM)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food! Chow down! Don't forget the meal tickets you picked up during registration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pyladies-lunch-at-pycon-12-30-pm"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PyLadies Lunch at PyCon (12:30 PM)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyLadies have organized to host a lunch for &lt;strong&gt;women&lt;/strong&gt; attending the conference who love Python, or who want to learn more about Python or PyLadies. While the event is filled up, you can &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.eventbrite.com/event/5227826570"&gt;register to get on the waitlist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="saturday-afternoon"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Saturday Afternoon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id2"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1:40 PM talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/56/"&gt;Designers + Developers: Collaborating on your Python project&lt;/a&gt; (Julia Elman, Mark Lavin) - Like many developers I've had good and bad experiences with designers. We both play our critical roles in projects, and it will be good to hear their presentation on how to collaborate and work in tandem as part of a team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id3"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1:55 PM talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/122/"&gt;Teaching with the IPython Notebook&lt;/a&gt; (Matt Davis) - The IPython Notebook is an unbelievably incredible tool. Imagine a Python shell that allows you to embed images and graphs right into the REPL. Designed by and for scientists, the IPython Notebook is useful for developers of all levels. You have to see it in action to believe it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/101/"&gt;Advanced Django Forms Usage&lt;/a&gt; (Daniel Greenfeld) - This isn't a beginner talk, but it's my talk! Indeed, I'm shamelessly plugging my intermediate level talk on what you can do with Django forms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id4"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2:35 PM talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a rough spot because there are four really beginner good talks by four great speakers happening at the same time. Since all of this are going to be wonderful presentations, I'm labeling them all as 'must-see'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/141/"&gt;Who are we? A sociological analysis of the indigenous Python tribe&lt;/a&gt; (Jackie Kazil) - Journalist and computer scientist at the Library of Congress, Jackie Kazil uses her amazing skills to analyze the Python community's code bases across thousands of projects to determine where we've been as a people and we are going in the future. If you want to see how an expert analyzes trends in the Python-verse, this is a talk that can't be missed!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/67/"&gt;Building full-stack scientific applications in Python&lt;/a&gt; (Luke Lee) - Did you know that Python is used in high performance scientific applications? Tools like SciPy and NumPy are built on top of very robust, optimized C and Fortran libraries. Luke will cover their use and also how to present the data using tools like PyQt. If you are into big data, you can't miss this talk!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/146/"&gt;Customizing the Django Admin: The How and the Why&lt;/a&gt; (Lakshman Prasad) - Following my talk is a deep dive into Django's famous admin interface. I was fortunate enough to get a sneak preview of the talk and I can say with confidence this is going to be an incredible presentation. Don't miss it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/92/"&gt;Location, Location, Location&lt;/a&gt; (Julia Grace) - Django, via the GeoDjango toolkit has amazing support for building GIS based applications. Julia's an experienced developer and great speaker, making this a can't miss talk!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id5"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3:15 PM talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There isn't a beginner-focused talk in this slot, so I'm going to make this the &lt;em&gt;roller-coaster&lt;/em&gt; slot. In other words, I'm going to steer you to the most intensely advanced talk at this time. Attend, buckle in the safety harness, and drink in the extreme knowledge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/80/"&gt;Making Apache suck less for hosting Python web applications&lt;/a&gt; (Graham Dumpleton) - It is not hard to find developers who will tell you that Apache sucks for running Python web applications. Is there a valid basis to such claims or have they simply been misguided by the views of others? Well, Graham understands how Python serves up web pages and won't hold back on technical detail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/130/"&gt;Numba: A Dynamic Python compiler for Science&lt;/a&gt; (Travis Oliphant, Siu Kwan Lam, Mark Florisson) - Numba is a compiler for Python syntax that uses the LLVM library and llvmpy to convert specifically decorated Python functions to machine code at run-time. It allows Python syntax to be used to do scientific and numerical computing that is blazing fast yet tightly integrated with the CPython run-time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="talk"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4:15 talk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this time period there is a single talk specifically aimed at beginners. There are some other useful talks around this time, but they are aimed at educators and integrators over beginners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/74/"&gt;Crypto 101&lt;/a&gt; (Laurens Van Houtven) - Cryptography is a tricky subject, and the goal of this 4:15 PM talk isn't to turn attendees into cryptography experts. Instead, you'll have a basic understanding of how some common systems compare, and also a sense for detecting and exposing snake oil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pm-talk"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4:30 PM talk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/102/"&gt;Getting Python and Django Through Your Java Shop Front Door (with Jython)&lt;/a&gt; (Frank Wierzbicki) - Work in a Java shop and want to bring in Python? Learn how to do it using Jython, the Python implementation that works in the JVM!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id6"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5:10 PM talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/138/"&gt;MTO On Blast: Using Python's Natural Language Toolkit to Model Gossip Blogs&lt;/a&gt; (Robert Elwell) - Python's powerful Natural Language Toolkit will be featured as the presenter gives an overview of Natural Language Processing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/103/"&gt;What is the Python Software Foundation?&lt;/a&gt; (Brian Curtin) - This talk aims to engage us in thinking about what it takes to further Python. Whether it's an idea of code, community, or otherwise, it will jumpstart us into helping the very positive community that has brought us together for the amazing event that is PyCon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/128/"&gt;Asset Management in Python&lt;/a&gt; (Robert Kluin, Beau Lyddon) - Coffeescript, Less, SASS, and all those other exciting new front end asset tools can be a challenge to deploy when doing web development in tools like Django, Flask, and Pyramid. The presenters will introduce &lt;em&gt;webassets&lt;/em&gt;, a library designed to make deployment of assets quick and easy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="evening-activities"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Evening Activities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday night will be the evening of a huge number of fantastic fun. Two items of note (more to come):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/sponsors/charityauction/"&gt;The PyCon Charity Auction&lt;/a&gt; (6:30 PM+) - Along with Disney Animation Studios and other contributors, Audrey and I are submitting a preview copy of the upcoming print edition of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django.2scoops.org"&gt;Two Scoops of Django: Best Practices for Django 1.5&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The famously unrecorded Testing in Python Birds of a Feathers event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="part-iv"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Part IV&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for Part IV of this series where I cover the third day of talks best suited for new Python developers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon-2013-guide"></category></entry><entry><title>Beginner's Guide to PyCon 2013 Part II</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/beginners-guide-pycon-2013-part-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-23T16:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2013-01-23:beginners-guide-pycon-2013-part-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is Part II in a series of blog posts about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/"&gt;PyCon US 2013&lt;/a&gt;. The goal is to provide a handy reference guide for first time attendees of the world's largest &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://python.org"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; conference. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.com/beginners-guide-pycon-2013-part-1.html"&gt;Part I&lt;/a&gt; was mostly about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/tutorials/"&gt;tutorials&lt;/a&gt;, this post will be about registration and the first day of talks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="registration"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Registration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven't done so yet, please &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/registration/register/"&gt;register&lt;/a&gt; now. Last year PyCon sold out way in advance, and hundreds missed the event. Which is a shame, because the conference is awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that the money you spend on registration will go towards a very good thing. You see, after the costs for running PyCon are subtracted, the rest will go to the non-profit Python Software Foundation (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://python.org/psf/"&gt;PSF&lt;/a&gt;). In addition to supporting the Python language itself, the PSF provides financial aid and grants for aspiring developers around the world. Which means the money you spend registering for PyCon will literally change people's lives. This isn't an idle exaggeration, this outreach has made a difference for you, me, and arguably the world. I would love to say more, but that's an article for another day...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, on to the talks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="talk-attendance-guidelines"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Talk Attendance Guidelines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At PyCon, talks are either 30 or 45 long. They represent the best and brightest in both old hands in the community and rising stars. Some quick guidelines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask Questions!&lt;/strong&gt; If the speaker leaves time for questions at the end, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://cecinestpasun.com/entries/i-can-haz-question-or-five/"&gt;go and ask&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shut the Laptop and Turn Off the Device.&lt;/strong&gt; It's disconcerting to give a speech to hundreds of people staring at their portable electronics and not responding to your banter. Unless you are using electronics to actively take notes on the talk, consider turning them off to look at the speaker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't Heckle.&lt;/strong&gt; It's nerve wracking going up in front of hundreds of people live and tens of thousands on streaming video. Heckling is &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; funny and it's a good way to lose friends and make enemies. Unless the speaker asks for commentary during the talk, wait until the end and then ask your questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, that out of the way, let's take a look at what Friday, March 15th, has to offer in terms of beginner friendly talks...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="friday-morning"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Friday Morning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The registration desk opens at 7:00 AM. Breakfast begins at 8:00 AM. From 9:00 AM to 10:20 AM is the welcome and initial keynote speeches. PyCon keynotes aren't boring - &lt;strong&gt;they are crazy awesome!&lt;/strong&gt; Say hi if you see me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In selecting these talks, I've tried to focus on the more technical ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="am-talks"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;10:50 AM talks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/35/"&gt;How to Except When You're Excepting&lt;/a&gt; (Esther Nam) - One of the rising stars of the community, Esther works for a group that demands 100% test coverage. She's going to cover the fundamentals of writing tests and why tests are a good thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/50/"&gt;How the Internet works&lt;/a&gt; (Jessica McKellar) - Want to know how the internet actually works? Jessica McKellar (also giving two tutorials and a keynote speech) will use Python to help you understand what's really going on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/116/"&gt;Gittip: Inspiring Generosity&lt;/a&gt; (Chad Whitacre) - Gittip is an open source Python platform for sustaining open source development via small, anonymous donations. This is a technical case-study about the story of community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id1"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;11:30 AM talks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/135/"&gt;Scrapy: it GETs the web&lt;/a&gt; (Asheesh Laroia) - In 2009 I took a web scraping tutorial by the author. He impressed me with his energy and knowledge. While technically this is an &lt;strong&gt;intermediate&lt;/strong&gt; talk, I know everyone will get something out of this talk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id2"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;12:10 AM talks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/39/"&gt;API Design for Library Authors&lt;/a&gt; (Chris McDonough) - Well designed APIs are critical for how other developers interact with your code. Chris is one of the talents in the community when it comes to creating easy-to-use but extremely powerful tools. I'm delighted he's made this an introductory talk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="friday-lunch"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Friday Lunch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't forget to keep your PyCon meal tickets you got when you registered in the morning or they won't let you into the lunch room!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sit down to people you don't know and introduce yourself. Every time I do this I don't just get to meet interesting people, I get to meet &lt;strong&gt;amazing&lt;/strong&gt; people. PyCon is full of brilliant minds and you'll never get to know any of them unless you try.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="friday-afternoon"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Friday Afternoon&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got lunch? Time for more talks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pm-talks"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1:40 PM talks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/58/"&gt;Using Python To Generate Art And Sound&lt;/a&gt; (Audrey Roy) - This is an &lt;strong&gt;intermediate&lt;/strong&gt; talk, but myself and those who have seen it can assure you it's a very good talk. Audrey demonstrates how to use Python tools like NumPy, SciPy, and PIL to make lovely things. You probably already know that Audrey and I wrote a Django book together, but you probably don't know that she wrote a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Very-Magical-Caterpillar-Tale-Butterfly/dp/1453714081/?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=cn-001-20"&gt;book about  caterpillars&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/54/"&gt;You can be a speaker at PyCon!&lt;/a&gt; (Anna Ravenscroft, Lynn Root) - PyCon loves new blood. Get some pointers on how to get your talks ready for submission next year!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/117/"&gt;Python 3.3: Trust Me, It's Better than 2.7&lt;/a&gt; (Brett Cannon) - The world of Python is heading towards Python 3. Want to know why? Attend this talk!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pm-talk"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1:55 PM talk&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/40/"&gt;Twisted Logic&lt;/a&gt; (Ashwini Oruganti) - Twisted is a mature, stable asynchronous framework written in Python that's been around for over a decade. New to the framework, the presenter explains why you shouldn't be scared of Twisted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id3"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2:35 PM talks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This slot is going to be hard because all three beginner talks are things you don't want to miss!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/76/"&gt;Loop like a native: while, for, iterators, generators&lt;/a&gt; (Ned Batchelder) - One of the really awesome features of Python is that you can write custom looping classes. Factor in generators and you'll be amazed by one of Python's most powerful features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/112/"&gt;Visualizing Github, Part I: Data to Information&lt;/a&gt; (Dana Bauer, Idan Gazit) - How can you go wrong with visualizing GitHub data using Python? This first part of the talk is on gathering and processing of data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/145/"&gt;Encapsulation with descriptors&lt;/a&gt; (Luciano Ramalho) - Python has no private fields, but the property decorator lets you replace public attributes with getters and setters without breaking client code. It's amazing what Python can do when you delve into it's subtleties!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id4"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3:15 PM talk&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/136/"&gt;Music Theory and Performance Analysis with Sebastian and Czerny&lt;/a&gt; (James Tauber) - An amazing speaker talking about one of his favorite subjects, this will be a great beginner talk. James mentored me in my early days of Django and JQuery, and I only have good things to say about him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/108/"&gt;Visualizing Github, Part II: Information to Meaning&lt;/a&gt; (Idan Gazit, Dana Bauer) - How can you go wrong with visualizing GitHub data using Python? This second part of the talk is on visualizing the data into something meaningful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id5"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4:15 PM talks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/126/"&gt;Transforming Code into Beautiful, Idiomatic Python&lt;/a&gt; (Raymond Hettinger) - This is the talk that's going to bring down the house, because Raymond covers the basics in such a way that even the most advanced developers pick up new tricks. This talk will be standing room only, filled with beginners to the most senior developers on the planet. Get to this one early or you'll miss it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/118/"&gt;Deploy your Python app in 5 min with a PaaS&lt;/a&gt; (Nate Aune) - Long time presenter Nate Aune doesn't just explain and demonstrate various Platforms as a Service, he also gives tips on evaluating which one is best for your needs. For someone getting into the Python web this talk is an invaluable service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="talk"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4:30 talk&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/124/"&gt;If You Code, You Should Write&lt;/a&gt; (Brian Jones) - Python has an amazing culture of documentation. We believe it's our civic duty to document our work on private and public projects. Brian explains why this is so and how to get across the concepts of your work in the best way possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="talks"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5:10 talks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/65/"&gt;SimpleCV - Computer Vision using Python&lt;/a&gt; (Katherine Scott) - This is a crash course on computer vision using the amazing ipython notebook along with NumPy and SciPy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/96/"&gt;Planning and Tending the Garden: The Future of Early Childhood Python Education&lt;/a&gt; (Kurt Grandis) - After his PyCon talk last year about using Python to fend off squirrels, Kurt suddenly found himself in the world of kid's education. This talk goes over the current state of the art for kids learning programming in Python and other tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/113/"&gt;Write the Docs&lt;/a&gt; (James Bennett) - Have you heard of a certain well-documented web framework called 'Django'? James Bennett is one of the people responsible for it's amazingly high documentation standard. In this talk he's going to coach on how to write prose that inspires and invigorates people to use your tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="evening-activities"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Evening Activities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On friday night the social scene will kick into high gear. There will be dinners, parties, Starcraft II contests, and much more. As these become more definite I'll adding them to this post!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="part-iii"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Part III&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for Part III of this series where I cover the second day of talks best suited for new Python developers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="audrey"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon-2013-guide"></category></entry><entry><title>Beginner's Guide to PyCon 2013 Part I</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/beginners-guide-pycon-2013-part-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-22T16:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2013-01-22:beginners-guide-pycon-2013-part-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;New to Python and thinking about going to the upcoming &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/"&gt;PyCon US&lt;/a&gt; for the first time? You know, that big &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://python.org"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; conference taking place near San Francisco in March?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps you signed up already and are getting worried about being overwhelmed by hundreds of tutorials, talks, and activities?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No worries! This multi-part guide will aid you in getting the most out of attending one of the best technical conferences on the planet. I'm going to share how to get through the whole event in good shape and cover some incredible beginner friendly events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-basics"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Basics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/registration/register/"&gt;register&lt;/a&gt; already! PyCon US sold out last year around this time. Don't be left out in the cold. Buy your ticket now before it's too late!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you've got that done, keep in mind that Python has two days of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/tutorials/"&gt;tutorials&lt;/a&gt;, three days of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/talks/"&gt;talks&lt;/a&gt;, and four days of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/community/sprints/"&gt;sprints&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Nine days of Python!&lt;/strong&gt; The trick is to not get exhausted or sick. Therefore, do the following every day of the conference:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take at least one shower. Please.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eat at least two good meals. Make a point of sitting with different people at each meal and introducing yourself. Make new friends!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get at least three hours of sleep. More if possible because your brain is going to go into learning overdrive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, PyCon US also has a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/about/code-of-conduct/"&gt;code of conduct&lt;/a&gt;. I like to sum it up as, &amp;quot;Act professionally.&amp;quot; Whether or not you agree with codes of conduct for conferences, PyCon US has one and it will be enforced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, enough basics, let's get onto tutorials!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="tutorials"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tutorials&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tutorials take place on March 13th and 14th. They each cost $150 but are well worth the price. The following are the talks I believe are best suited for beginners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="wednesday-morning"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Wednesday Morning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For novice programmers start with Jessica McKellar's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/1/"&gt;A hands-on introduction to Python for beginning programmers&lt;/a&gt;. I can vouch that the instructor is amazing, and will jumpstart you on the road to being a Python developer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are you an experienced developer new to Python? I suggest &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/8/"&gt;Going from web pages to web apps with Python&lt;/a&gt; by Asheesh Loroia and Karen Rustad. In 2009 I took a class by Asheesh and was impressed by his energy, enthusiasm, and depth of knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to learn Python web that isn't Django? Try out Paul Everitt's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/12/"&gt;Pyramid for Humans&lt;/a&gt; class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="wednesday-afternoon"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Wednesday Afternoon&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You simply can't go wrong with David Beazley's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/2/"&gt;Learn Python Through Public Data Hacking&lt;/a&gt;. He's the author of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Python-Essential-Reference-4th-Edition/dp/0672329786/?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=cn-001-20"&gt;Python Essential Reference&lt;/a&gt;, an amazing instructor, and delivered a PyCon keynote last year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you're interested in the web, check out Nathan Yergler's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/9/"&gt;Effective Django&lt;/a&gt;. I can assure you that he knows his Django material and is going to deliver a great experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="thursday-morning"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Thursday Morning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you're new to Python, you need to learn the Python environment. This means version control, PyPI, test automation, and more. Matt Harrison covers this in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/3/"&gt;Scripting: from Hard-drive to Github to PyPI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting back to the web, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/10/"&gt;Fully Test-Driven Web Development with Django and Selenium&lt;/a&gt; is another run through the Django tutorial, but done from the test driven perspective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fascinating tutorial offered at this time is &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/30/"&gt;A Gentle Introduction to Computer Vision&lt;/a&gt;. It's a great way to learn how Python is used in many creative and unexpected ways.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="thursday-afternoon"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Thursday Afternoon&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jessica McKellar returns to instruct on how to give back to the community with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/4/"&gt;Contribute with me! Getting started with open source development&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to learn how to program games? Look no further than Richard Jones' &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/19/"&gt;Introduction to PyGame&lt;/a&gt;. He's taught this class for years, and I can't say enough good things about him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shameless Plug:&lt;/strong&gt; My talk is not meant for beginning Django developers, but I'm listing it anyway. It's my blog, right? In any case, along with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey Roy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gettingstartedwithdjango.com/"&gt;Kenneth Love&lt;/a&gt;, we're presenting &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/schedule/presentation/11/"&gt;Wiring Up Django Packages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="evening-activities"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Evening Activities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2013/events/reception/"&gt;Opening Reception&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="part-ii"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Part II&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.com/beginners-guide-pycon-2013-part-2.html"&gt;Beginner's Guide to PyCon 2013 Part II&lt;/a&gt; where I cover the first day of talks best suited for new Python developers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="audrey"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon-2013-guide"></category></entry></feed>