<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>pydanny</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pydanny.com/feeds/travel%20tips%20for%20geeks.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pydanny.com/</id><updated>2013-08-05T14:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Travel Tips for Geeks: Traveling Cheaply</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/travel-tips-for-geeks-living-cheaply.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-08-05T14:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2013-08-05:travel-tips-for-geeks-living-cheaply.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's a given that in order to travel you need to have money or make a lot of money, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's not really true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are ways to live well but cheaply. It takes a bit of discipline, forethought, and judgement, but the reward of living is amazing. This article explains how &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://audreymroy.com"&gt;Audrey Roy&lt;/a&gt; and I do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pick-the-right-location"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pick the Right Location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of famous destination cities are expensive no matter what you do. San Francisco, New York, London, Paris, Berlin, Rome, and Tokyo might be wonderful, but they are also places where you have to pay more. More for everything. Rent, food, and accessory costs are likely to be at least double what you expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, certain entire countries are expensive. Switzerland, Slovenia, Australia, and New Zealand are lovely, but everything just costs more there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, if the transit system is good, consider staying a little further from the expensive downtown or waterfront. This can make even expensive cities affordable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affordable places we've discovered this year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Barcelona, Spain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bologna, Italy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Florence, Italy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Krakow, Poland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Islands near Split, Croatia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Warsaw, Poland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zagreb, Croatia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of our resource is &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Worlds-Cheapest-Destinations-Countries-ebook/dp/B00AYIBO1M/ref=tmm_kin_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;sr=&amp;amp;tag=mlinar-20"&gt;The World's Cheapest Destinations&lt;/a&gt;, which, if nothing else, is an interesting read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="use-a-service-to-find-a-place-and-stay-a-while"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Use a service to find a place and stay a while&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use a service like &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.airbnb.com"&gt;airbnb&lt;/a&gt; or the local equivalent to find a place. Some people like to just stay at hostels, we prefer apartments. Stay for a month so you get a lower rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try to research the nearby grocery shopping. While little stores are wonderful, they cost more than a large supermarket. The supermarket will allow you to stay cheaply in an area. However, make sure to check out the little markets at least once a week because the food there is often much, much better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our two constant requirements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WiFi (we work remotely)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Washing machine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="if-you-work-remotely"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;If you work remotely&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're fortunate in that our work lets us work remotely. Keep in mind the two cardinal rules:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be available in real-time:&lt;/strong&gt; Use Google Hangouts, Chat, IRC or whatever at regular times to demonstrate you are working.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get your work done on time:&lt;/strong&gt;  If you are working remotely while traveling, you have to demonstrate to the client/boss that the travel isn't a distraction. If you seem flakey, they'll seriously consider other options besides you. Honestly, who can blame them?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="try-to-cook-and-eat-at-home"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Try to Cook and Eat at Home&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our rule is we eat out once a week. Otherwise, it's all home cooking. Even when we do tourist things on our day off, we bring food from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the ingredients are always different. Fruits, vegetables, and meats are grown in different soils and climates and taste different. This means don't try and replicate what you eat at home, cook simple things they make where you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="finding-good-affordable-restaurants"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Finding Good, Affordable Restaurants&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding good, affordable restaurants is easy. Here are our steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find a place that looks busy.&lt;/strong&gt; A busy place means the food is palatable and because of volume, the food is fresh. If the place is empty, walk away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check the menu for prices.&lt;/strong&gt; If they make you flinch, walk away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen to what people are saying.&lt;/strong&gt; If it's in your version of your language, walk away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you stay, keep in mind local portion sizes. For example, in slavic countries like Poland and Croatia, the portions can be quite large. What we sometimes do is share a main course and use the savings to buy drinks or dessert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like beer, try to order local varieties of beer. They often sell for less and can be really tasty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like wine, the rule goes like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the USA, order the cheapest non-house wine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Europe, order the house wine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-else"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Else?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be updating this article in the days and months and hopefully years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="travel"></category><category term="travel tips for geeks"></category></entry><entry><title>Travel Tips for Geeks: Preventing Theft</title><link href="http://pydanny.com/travel-tips-for-geeks-preventing-theft.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-07-18T16:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Daniel-Greenfeld</name></author><id>tag:pydanny.com,2013-07-18:travel-tips-for-geeks-preventing-theft.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the first in a set of blog posts based on my experiences traveling in various places around the world. This particular safety-related post is about theft, not scams, which I may cover in another article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this first article, I'm hoping this gets on various technical RSS feeds. I'm doing this because many of the readers of such feeds attend conferences and are strangers in far and distant places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="about-thieves"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About Thieves&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thieves (or pick pockets) are everywhere. I've seen extremely suspicious activity in Portland, Los Angeles, Washington DC, Barcelona, Florence, Pisa, and Krakow. Years ago in Washington DC I had stuff stolen from me twice so I've been observant and careful ever since. Anywhere there are non-residents distracted by looking at new vistas while suffering from travel fatigue is where most thieves can be found. I've learned a lot by observation and doing research but I don't claim to be an expert. All I claim to be is someone who doesn't want to be ripped off far from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-basics-any-place-with-tourists-is-risky"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Basics: Any place with tourists is risky&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it can be said that thieves can be anywhere, the truth is that they focus on where the tourists go. We carry money and expensive things, are tired, distracted, and don't know our way around. For a thief, A moment of risk can yield hundreds or thousands of dollars of profit from a traveler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-ve-never-had-any-problems-there"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&amp;quot;I've never had any problems there&amp;quot;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've heard this several times from local residents or travelers, often about places with statistically high crime rates. You'll hear it too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that means is that they've either been lucky or unobservant. It's better to avoid a miserable trip by being a least a little careful with your identity, money, and electronics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="listen-to-warnings-before-you-go-places"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Listen to warnings before you go places&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Barcelona our host warned us about La Rambla, a tourist-heavy street that's notoriously thick with thieves. While we're always careful, we were especially observant there, and enjoyed the very lovely and friendly downtown Barcelona without incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversely, don't pay attention to warnings at locations. Public notices about thieves are a nasty trap. When you see them you check your most expensive things, giving away the location of money, jewelry, watches, and cell phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="watch-how-local-residents-protect-themselves"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Watch how local residents protect themselves&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In suspicious places you'll notice local men with their hands in their pockets. Why? It's because they are literally keeping their hands on the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the same places, local women will take a shirt, sweater, or even a newspaper and have it on top of their purse with their arm on top of that. Where &amp;quot;man-purses&amp;quot; are acceptable wear, men will do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="good-thieves-look-like-tourists-or-non-criminals"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Good thieves Look like tourists or non-criminals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people or articles warn you about this or that ethnicity or how people dress. That's not just racist and shallow, it's stupid and inaccurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thieves simply don't want to be noticed, and if noticed they want escape to be as easy as possible. Which means the more active and successful ones dress and act like everyone around you. Which means, for example, in Europe the better thieves are of Caucasian descent and dress like American visitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do note that criminals from a non-majority ethnicity do exist, but they aren't likely to be thieves. This is because being an ethnic minority makes them easier to spot and track down. Also, the all-too-human justice system is harsher on them. Instead, they are often the ones preying on tourists by selling cheap, overpriced trinkets on the sidewalks to tourists who often don't realize they are breaking local laws by purchasing from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="underage-thieves-are-fearless"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Underage thieves are fearless&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Underage thieves have the benefit of that they don't have to worry about the justice system. In many places the police can't arrest children under a certain age and have to let them go. Also, if they are caught, if they are in a gang, an older family member&amp;quot; will come up, rebuke them publicly, and most people will let it go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="an-ounce-of-preperation"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;An ounce of preperation...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a good idea to spend a little time and money getting a few things before you travel. Why? Cause here are the easiest targets in rough order of ease for thieves (1 is super-easy, 7 is merely easy):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backbacks without locks worn on the back. &lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt;: Don't put passports in your backback!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fanny pack or wallet in the back pocket.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grocery or store-purchase bag&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any outside-pocket cellphone holder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suitcases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wallet in the front pocket.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="don-t-be-stupid"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Don't be stupid&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least one travel writer advocates putting your stuff in a local grocery or store bag. That way you &amp;quot;fit in&amp;quot;, thieves ignore you, and you can confidently enjoy your visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;em&gt;mind-bogglingly stupid&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confidence means you allow yourself to be distracted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unless you live somewhere, you stand out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grocery or store bags are not designed to carry things for hours on end. They break.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grocery or store bags are one of the easiest target for thieves. They either don't close adequately or are the perfect target for razor armed thieves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="your-wallet"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Your wallet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take your ID out and only keep a very small amount of money in your wallet, which should be in your front pocket. Take the credit cards out and put them in secret stashes. If you really want a credit card in your wallet, get one linked to a bank account with just enough money for the day in it. Add more money to it as you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="shorten-the-straps"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Shorten the Straps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep the straps of your stuff short and in your hands. When walking next to a street, keep bags on the far side from the road. Moped thieves will will snatch and pull you until the straps break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="use-secret-stashes-on-your-person"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Use secret stashes on your person&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most sporting good stores sell money belts and underclothes pouches. Use the money belt to store cash. Use an underclothes pouch to store your passport and at least one credit card. For underclothes pouches I recommend you open packages and feel the material against your skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="consider-buying-anti-theft-backpacks-laptop-bags"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Consider buying anti-theft backpacks / laptop bags&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We prefer &lt;strong&gt;PacSafe&lt;/strong&gt; brand gear because the clasps are hidden and require a trick to open. Their stuff also has steel wire woven into their straps and fabric, meaning they can't get cut by a razor. PacSafe stuff isn't cheap but the peace of mind has been definitely worth the price. We've relied on the PacSafe &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Pacsafe-Metrosafe-Anti-Theft-Tablet-Laptop/dp/B00AVXDELI/?tag=ihpydanny-20"&gt;laptop bag&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Pacsafe-Luggage-Slingsafe-Shoulder-Black/dp/B006QLMDH0/?tag=ihpydanny-20"&gt;shoulder bag&lt;/a&gt; for about 18 months now and they've been awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://www.amazon.com/Pacsafe-Metrosafe-Anti-Theft-Tablet-Laptop/dp/B00AVXDELI/?tag=ihpydanny-20"&gt;&lt;img alt="My laptop bag" class="align-center" src="http://ecx.images-amazon.com/images/I/41lh%2B2goeNL._SL500_SS80_.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My laptop bag&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://www.amazon.com/Pacsafe-Luggage-Slingsafe-Shoulder-Black/dp/B006QLMDH0/?tag=ihpydanny-20"&gt;&lt;img alt="Audrey's shoulder bag" class="align-center" src="http://ecx.images-amazon.com/images/I/31jF8RBoBEL._SL500_SS80_.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Audrey's shoulder bag&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="identifying-thief-tactics"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Identifying Thief Tactics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a successful thief requires the same skills as a magician. Observation, distraction, misdirection, staged audience members, and timing are how they do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some common techniques they use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-big-local-attraction"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Big Local Attraction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you are gazing at the masterpiece of architecture, hungrily peering at the door menu, or the incredible street performance, your focus is off your stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt;: Train yourself so when you start to feel distracted to put your arm or hand on your most expensive stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-magician"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Magician&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For reference, this is literally the same sort of sleight-of-hand that magicians use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pickpockets often have a newspaper, expensive jacket, or nice sweater in one hand to block what they are doing. While they engage you in friendly conversation they use the prop to block your like of sight from their other hand, which is busy. Especially good thieves don't even bother with the props and just rely on the width of their arm to block lines of observation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt;: If someone you don't know shows something up close to you, back off. In fact, just apologize and keep your distance. It's perfectly okay to not follow &amp;quot;local custom&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-spill"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Spill&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone throws anything at you, or if something is spilled on you, the thief helps you clean up, their accomplice is going through your stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt;: Back up and start screaming &amp;quot;Help, Thief&amp;quot; because it means you've been targeted and are under active scam. Cover your stuff with your arms and hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-fall"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Fall&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one is hard to deal with, especially for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a person falls or stumbles around you, don't help them, regardless of their age or apparent infirmity. While you help them their accomplice is taking from you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt;: Unless there is obvious injury, back off and let the locals take care of it, or find the police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-gift"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Gift&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year the new trick is for someone to ask you if you want them to take pictures of you using your camera or cell phone. You hand them your camera and they start running. &lt;em&gt;You've literally 'gifted' them your camera!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt;: Look for someone to take your picture, never the other way around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="your-room"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Your Room&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While staying at a hotel/hostel/BnB you go out for the day in a place without a safe. When you come back your valuables are gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt;: No safe? Carry your valuables!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="if-you-catch-a-thief"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;If you catch a thief&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You've caught them in the act. Maybe you've grabbed them or maybe they started running. Follow these steps to avoid injury and even death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="don-t-chase-thieves"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DON'T CHASE THIEVES&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever you do, don't chase thieves. Thieves of all ages are usually in gangs or have friends nearby. Their 'backup' carry weapons ranging from sticks to knives to guns. People die from chasing thieves every year in every country. Nothing you are carrying is worth your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="call-for-help"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Call for help&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how to yell &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;Help, Thief!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot; in the local language. Often the locals may deal with it as they hate thieves since crime damages their businesses and local reputation. In fact sometimes the response is overwhelmingly violent. There are stories of would-be victims in Africa, India, and Europe intervening to save the life of a would-be thief's life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-police"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Police&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's pretty universal police who deal with street crime wear uniforms. Work with them and if they ask you if you want to press charges, do so. Otherwise in many places they have to let the person go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="danger-the-undercover-police"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DANGER: The 'undercover' police&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone not wearing a uniform and claiming to be 'undercover' is an accomplice, scam artist, or worse. If they 'come to help':&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't give up any identification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demand that uniformed police be summoned by radio or phone to this location immediately. If the 'undercover' police refuse, then they are a scam or worse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't leave the spot!&lt;/strong&gt; If 'undercover' police try to get you to come with them, refuse loudly. If they try to force you away, start yelling as if your life is in danger, &lt;strong&gt;because it is&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="in-closing"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;In Closing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theft is real. Go to Youtube and spent 10 minutes searching on &amp;quot;thief&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;pickpocket&amp;quot; for proof. Most of the videos are surveillance videos, but when magicians talk about theft it's pretty fun to watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, it's easy to dramatically decrease your chances of being a victim of this kind of crime by being prepared and vigilant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="djangocon"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="travel tips for geeks"></category></entry></feed>